<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The judges resolutions upon the several statutes concerning bankrupts with the like resolutions on the statutes of 13 Eliz. and 27 Eliz. touching fraudulent conveyances / by George Billinghurst ...</title>
            <author>Billinghurst, George.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1676</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 227 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 104 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2014-11">2014-11 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A28155</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing B2906</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R4175</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">13678211</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 13678211</idno>
            <idno type="VID">101268</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A28155)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 101268)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 836:3)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The judges resolutions upon the several statutes concerning bankrupts with the like resolutions on the statutes of 13 Eliz. and 27 Eliz. touching fraudulent conveyances / by George Billinghurst ...</title>
                  <author>Billinghurst, George.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>206 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Henry Twyford ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1676.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Includes index.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Bankruptcy --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Bankruptcy --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Fraudulent conveyances --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Fraudulent conveyances --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-04</date>
            <label>Colm MacCrossan</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:1"/>
            <p>THE Judges Reſolutions Upon the Several Statutes Concerning BANKRUPTS, WITH The like Reſolutions on the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes of 13. <hi>Eliz.</hi> and 27. <hi>Eliz.</hi> touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing fraudulent CONVEYANCES. By <hi>GEORGE BILLINGH<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>RST</hi> of <hi>Grays-Inne,</hi> Eſq;</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Henry Twyford</hi> in <hi>Vine-Court Middle-Temple,</hi> 1676.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="license">
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:2"/>
            <p>I do allow the Printing of this Book, Intituled, <hi>The Judges Reſolutions upon the Statute con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Bankrupts.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <date>
                  <hi>28th.</hi> June, 1676.</date>
               <signed>FRA: NORTH.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:2"/>
            <opener>
               <salute>Gentle Reader.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>THou haſt here a methodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cal digeſtion of the ſeveral Statutes concerning Bankrupts, preſented to thy view; together with ſuch Expoſitions as have been made of the ſeveral parts of them by the Learned Judges of this Kingdom, ſince they came forth.</p>
            <p>And in regard the matter hereof may concern most men, I thought it would not be unneceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary to be publiſhed. For al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though there be a Reading in Print upon ſome of thoſe Statures
<pb facs="tcp:101268:3"/> more full of abſtruſe Notions and Learning than this is. yet I have ſome ground to believe that this will be thought for ordinary capacities, and the generality of men, much more uſeful. I have alſo added hereunto the ſeveral Statutes of <hi>13 El.</hi> and <hi>27 El.</hi> touching fraudulent conveyances, with the like Expoſition of the Learned Judges on them in ſeveral caſes annexed, which may be likewiſe of uſe unto thee.</p>
            <closer>
               <salute>Farewel.</salute>
               <signed>T. B.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:101268:3"/>
            <head>What a Bankrupt is, and his Deſcription. 34. <hi>Hen. 8. Chap.</hi> 4.</head>
            <p>THe Lord Chancellor, Trea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurer, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall take order with Bankrupts Bodies, Lands, and Goods for the payment of their Debts. Al. 13 <hi>El. 7. 1 Jac. 15. 21 Jac.</hi> 19.</p>
            <div type="part">
               <head>13 <hi>Eliz. Chap.</hi> 7. Who is a Bankrupt, how and by whom his Body, Lands, and Goods ſhall be ordered for the payment of his Creditors.</head>
               <p>FOrasmuch as notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Statute made againſt Bankrupts, in the xxxiiii year of
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:101268:4"/> the Reign of our late Sovereign Lord King <hi>Henry</hi> the eighth, thoſe kind of perſons have, and do ſtill increaſe into great and exceſſive numbers, and are like more to do, if ſome better pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſion be not made for the repreſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of them. And for a plain de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration to be made and ſet forth, who is and ought to be ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken and deemed for a Bankrupt: Therefore be it enacted and eſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhed by the Authority of this preſent Parliament, that if any Merchant or other perſon, u<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing or exerciſing the trade of Merchandize, by way of Bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaining, Exchange, Rechange, Bartry, Cheviſance, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, in groſs, or by retail, or ſeek<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his or her trade of living, by buying and ſelling, and being Subject born of this Realm, or of any the Queens Dominions, or Denizen, ſithence the firſt day of this preſent Parliament hath,
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:101268:4"/> or at any time hereafter ſhall de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>part the Realm, or begin to keep his or her Houſe or Houſes, or otherwiſe to abſent him or her<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſelf,, or take Sanctuary, or ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer him or her ſelf willingly to be arreſted for any debt or other thing, not grown or due for Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney delivered, Wares ſold, or any other juſt and lawful cauſe, or good conſideration or purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, hath or will ſuffer him or her ſelf to be outlawd, or yield him or her ſelf to priſon, or depart from his or her dwelling Houſe or Houſes, to the intent or pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe to defraud or hinder any of his or her Creditors, being alſo a Subject born, as is aforeſaid, of the juſt Debt or duty of ſuch Creditor or Creditors, ſhall be reputed, deemed, and taken for a Bankrupt.</p>
               <p>And be it enacted by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That the Lord Chancellour of England, or Lord
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:101268:5"/> Keeper of the great Seal of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland for the time being, upon every complaint made to him in writing, againſt any ſuch perſon or perſons being Bankrupt, as is before defined, ſhall have full power and Authority by Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion under the great Seal of England, to name, aſſign, and appoint ſuch wiſe and honeſt, diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creet perſons, as to him ſhall ſeem good: Who, or the moſt part of them, by vertue of this Act and of ſuch Commiſſion, ſhall have full power and authority to take by their diſcretions ſuch or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der and direction, with the body and bodies of ſuch perſon, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever he or ſhe may be had, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in his or her Houſe or Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, Sanctuary or elſewhere, as well by impriſonment of his or her body or bodies, as alſo with all his or her Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, as well Copy or Cuſtomary-hold, as Free-hold,
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:101268:5"/> which he or ſhee ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>ve in his or her own right, before he or ſhe became Bankrupt, and alſo with all ſuch Lands, Tenements and Hereditaments, as ſuch perſon ſhall have purchaſed, or obtained for money, or other recompence joyntly with his wife, children or childe, to the only uſe of ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fender, or offenders,<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or of, or for ſuch uſe, intereſt, right or title, as ſuch offender or offenders then ſhall have in the ſame, which he or ſhe may lawfully depart with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>al, or with any perſon or perſons, of truſt to any ſecret uſe of ſuch offender or offenders, and alſo with his or her money, goods, chattels, wares, merchandiſes and debts, whereſoever they may be found or known, and cauſe the ſaid Lands, Tenements, Fees, Annuities, Offices, Goods, Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, Wares, Merchandizes and Debts, to be ſearched, viewed rented, and apprayſed to the beſt
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:101268:6"/> value they may, and by Deed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dented, enrolled in one of the Queens Majeſties Courts of Record, to make ſale of the ſaid Lands, Tenements, and Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, and of all Deeds, Writings, and Evidences, touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing only the ſame, belonging to ſuch offender or offenders, deb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor or debtors, and alſo of all Fees, Annuities, Offices, Goods, and Chattels, or otherwiſe to order the ſame for true ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction and payment of the ſaid Creditors: that is to ſay, To every of the ſaid Creditors a por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, rate and rate like, according to the quantity of his or their debts: and that every direction, order, bargain, ſale, and other things done by the ſaid perſons ſo authoriſed, as is aforeſaid, in form aforeſaid, ſhall be good and effectual in the Law, to all in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, conſtructions, and purpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, againſt the ſaid offender or
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:101268:6"/> offenders, debtor or debtors, his or their wife or wives, heir and heirs, childe and children, and ſuch perſon and perſons, as by ſuch joynt purchaſe with the ſaid offender or offenders, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, have or ſhall have any eſtate or intereſt in the premiſſes, and againſt all other perſon and perſons claiming by, from, or under ſuch offender or offenders, debtor or debtors, by any Act or Acts had, made, or done after any ſuch perſon ſhall become Bankrupt, as is aforeſaid, and alſo againſt the Lords of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, whereof the ſaid Copyhold or Cuſtomary lands been holden, their heirs, ſucceſſors, and aſſigns, and every of them.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the Authority aforeſaid, That all and every perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, to whom any ſuch ſale of Copyhold, or Cuſtomary Lands, or Tenements ſhall be made,
<pb n="12" facs="tcp:101268:7"/> ſhall before ſuch time as they or any of them ſhall enter or take any profit of the ſame Lands or Tenements, agree and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pound with the Lords of the Mannors of whom the ſame ſhall be holden, for ſuch fines or in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes as heretofore have been moſt uſual, and accuſtomed to be yielded or paid therefore: and that upon every ſuch agreement or compoſition, the ſaid Lords for the time being, at the next Court to be holden at, or for the ſaid Mannors, ſhall not only grant unto the ſaid <hi>Vendee</hi> or <hi>Vendees,</hi> upon requeſt, the ſame Copy or Cuſtomary Lands or Tenements, by Copy of Court Roll, of the ſame Mannors, for ſuch eſtate or intereſt as to them ſhall be ſold, and reſerving the antient Rents, Cuſtomes, and Services: but alſo in the ſame Court admit them Tenants of the ſame Copy or Cuſtomary
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:101268:7"/> Lands, as other Copyholders of the ſame Mannors, have been wont to be admitted, and to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive their fealty accordingly.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by the Authority aforeſaid, That ſuch of the ſaid Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners as ſhall put the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion in execution, ſhall upon lawful requeſt to them made by the ſaid Bankrupt, not only make a true declaration to the ſame Bankrupts, of the imploying and beſtowing of their ſaid Lands, Tenements, Offices, fees, Goods, Chattels, and debts ſo payed and ſatisfied to their ſaid Creditors, but alſo make payment of the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verplus of the ſame (if any ſuch ſhall be) to the ſaid Bankrupts, their Executors, Adminiſtrators, or Aſſigns.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted by the Authority aforeſaid, that if after any ſuch act or offence commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, and complaint thereof made
<pb n="14" facs="tcp:101268:8"/> to the ſaid Commiſſioners ſo to be appointed, as is aforeſaid, or the more part of them, by any party grieved, as is aforeſaid, concerning the premiſſes, know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſuppoſing, or ſuſpecting any of the goods, chattels, wares, merchandizes, or debts of ſuch offender or offenders, debtor or debtors, to be in cuſtody, uſe, oc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cupying, keeping, or poſſeſſion of any perſon or perſons, or any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons to be indebted to any ſuch offender or offenders, do make relation thereof to the ſaid Commiſſioners ſo to be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, or the more part of them: that then the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or the moſt part of them, ſhall by vertue hereof and of the ſaid Commiſſion, have full power and authority to ſend for, and call before them by ſuch Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſs, ways or means, as they ſhall think convenient by their diſcretions, all and every ſuch
<pb n="15" facs="tcp:101268:8"/> perſon and perſons ſo known. ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected, or ſuppoſed to have any ſuch goods, chattels, wares, mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandizes, or debts, in his or their cuſtody, uſe, occupation, keeping, or poſſeſſion, or ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, or ſuſpected to be indebted, to ſuch offender or offenders, and upon their appearance, to exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine them, and every of them, as well by their Oaths as other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, by ſuch ways and means as the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them, by their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretions ſhall think meet and convenient, for and upon the ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cialty, certainty, true declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and knowledge of all and ſingular ſuch goods, chattels, wares, merchandizes, and debts of any ſuch offender or offenders, as be ſuppoſed or ſuſpected to be in his or their cuſtody, uſe, occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation or poſſeſſion, and all ſuch debts as by them or any of them, ſhall be ſuppoſed or ſuſpected to
<pb n="16" facs="tcp:101268:9"/> be owing to any ſuch offender or offenders.</p>
               <p>And if any ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons upon ſuch examination, do not diſcloſe and plainly declare, and ſhew the whole truth of ſuch things as he or they ſhall be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amined of concerning the pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſes to his knowledge, or do deny to ſwear: then every ſuch perſon or perſons ſo denying to ſwear, or being examined do not declare the plain and whole truth concerning the premiſſes, upon due proof thereof to be made be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them ſo to be appointed, as is aforeſaid, by witneſs, examination, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, as to the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or the more part of them ſhall ſeem ſufficient in that be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>half, ſhall loſe and forfeit double the value of all ſuch goods, chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, wares, merchandizes, &amp; debts, by them or any of them ſo con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealed,
<pb n="17" facs="tcp:101268:9"/> and not wholly and plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly declared and ſhewed: which forfeiture ſhall be levied by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them, of the Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, Hereditaments, goods, and chattels, of ſuch perſon ſo de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nying to ſwear, or not diſcloſing the whole truth, as is aforeſaid, by ſuch ways and means, and in ſuch manner and form, as is be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore limited and appointed for the principal offender or offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, debtor, or debtors. and the ſame forfeiture or forfeitures to be diſtributed, or imployed to and for the ſatisfaction and payments of the debts of the ſaid creditor or creditors, in ſuch like manner, rate, and form, as is above de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared, concerning the ordering of the lands and tenements, of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices, fees, goods, and chattels, of ſuch offender or offenders, debtor or debtors as is aforeſaid.</p>
               <p>And <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e it further enacted,
<pb n="18" facs="tcp:101268:10"/> That if at any time before or af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter that any ſuch perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons departeth the Realm, or ſhall keep his or their Houſe or Houſes, or otherwiſe abſent him or themſelves, or take ſanctuary, or ſuffer him or themſelves to be arreſted, outlawd, or yield his or their bodies to priſon, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid: any perſon or perſons do fraudulently by covin or col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luſion, claim, demand, recover, poſſeſs, or detain any debts, du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, goods, chattels, lands, or te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, by writing, truſt, or otherwiſe, which were or ſhall be due, belonging, or appertaining to any ſuch offender or offenders. other than ſuch as he or they can and do prove to be due by right and conſcience in form aforeſaid, for money payed, wares deliver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, or other juſt conſideration or cauſe reaſonable, to the juſt va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue thereof, before the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners ſo to be appointed, or
<pb n="19" facs="tcp:101268:10"/> the more part of them, as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, and the ſame to proceed <hi>(bona fide)</hi> without fraud or co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>vin: that then every ſuch perſon or perſons ſo craftily demanding, claiming, having, poſſeſſing. or detaining any ſuch debt, duty, or other thing, as is aforeſaid, ſhall forfeit and loſe double as much as he or they ſhall ſo claim, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, detain, or poſſeſs, which ſaid forfeiture ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e levied, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covered, and imployed in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner and form as is afore rehear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, and be it enact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by Authority aforeſaid, that if it ſhall fortune the creditors of any ſuch Bankrupt, as is aforeſaid, to be ſatisfied and paid of their debts and duties, of, or with the proper lands, tenements, goods, chattels, and debts of the ſaid Bankrupts, or of, or with the ſame, and ſome part of the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures of the ſaid double values
<pb n="20" facs="tcp:101268:11"/> to be forfeited, as is aforeſaid, and that there ſhall remain an over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus of the ſaid forfeitures of the ſaid double values: that then the one moiety of the ſaid overplus of the ſaid forfeitures of the dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble values ſo remaining, ſhall be by the ſaid Commiſſioners ſo ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecuting the ſaid Commiſſion, within convenient time after the levying thereof, paid unto the Queens Majeſty, her Heirs and Succeſſors, and the other moiety thereof ſhall be by the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners employed and diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buted to and amongſt the poor within the Hoſpitals in every City, Town or County, where any ſuch Bankrupt ſhall happen to be: Any thing in this Act to the contrary thereof not with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted by Authority aforeſaid, that if any ſuch perſon or perſons which is or ſhall be indebted, do of purpoſe
<pb n="21" facs="tcp:101268:11"/> withdraw him or themſelves out or from his or their uſual man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion houſe or houſes: that then upon complaint thereof made to the ſaid Commiſſioners having authority, as is aforeſaid, the ſame Commiſſioners, or the more part of them, ſhall by vertue and au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority of this preſent Act, have full power and authority to award five Proclamations to be made in the Queens name, upon five ſun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dry Market dayes, in ſuch places near the place where ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt hath moſt commonly dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led or made his abode, command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing him or them by the ſame Proclamations in the Queens name to return with all conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient ſpeed, and to yeeld his or their bodies before the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, having authority as is aforeſaid, or one of them, at ſuch time and place as by the ſaid Proclamation ſhall be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed: and if the ſaid perſon
<pb n="22" facs="tcp:101268:12"/> be not according to ſuch Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation repair and yield his or their body as is aforeſaid, that then the body of all and every ſuch offender or offenders, ſhall be adjudged, taken, and deemed to all intents and purpoſes out of the Queens protection: and that alſo every perſon and perſons that ſhall willingly and wittingly help to hide or convey, or ſhall wittingly and willingly receive, detain, or keep ſecretly any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons ſo demanded by Proclamation as is aforeſaid, ſhall ſuffer ſuch pains by impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonment of his or their bodies, or to pay ſuch fine to our Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Lady the Queens Majeſty, her Heirs and Succeſſors, as to the ſaid Lord Chancellor, or Lord Keeper of the great Seal (being informed thereof) by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners ſo to be appointed as is aforeſaid, or the more part of them ſhall ſeem meet and conve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nient
<pb n="23" facs="tcp:101268:12"/> for their ſaid offence or offences.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it further enacted, that if the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors of any ſuch offender or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders, debtor or debtors, which ſo do depart the Realm, keep his or their houſe or houſes, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe abſent or withdraw him or themſelves into places unknown, or take Sanctuary, or will ſuffer him-or themſelves to be arreſted or outlawed, or yield his or their bodies into priſon purpoſely, and for the cauſes aforeſaid, be not fully ſatisfied or otherwiſe con<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>tented for their debts and duties by the way and means before ſpecified and declared: that then the ſaid Creditor or Creditors, and every of them ſhall and may have their remedy for the recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry and levying of the reſidue of their ſaid debts or duties, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of they ſhall not be fully ſatisfied, payd, or otherwiſe contented in
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:101268:13"/> form aforeſaid, againſt the ſaid offender or offenders, in like man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner and form as they ſhould and might have had before the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of this Act. And that the ſaid creditor or creditors, and e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very of them, ſhall be only barred and excluded by vertue of this Act, of, and for every ſuch part and portion of the ſaid debts and duties as ſhall be paid, ſatisfied, diſtributed, or delivered unto him or them by order of the ſaid per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, as is aforeſaid, and of no more portion or parcel thereof: Any thing herein ſpecified that may be taken or conſtrued to the contrary notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo enacted by authority aforeſaid, that if any perſon or perſons, which is or ſhall be publiſhed and declared to be a Bankrupt by vertue of this Act, ſhall at any time after purchaſe any lands, tenements, hereditaments, free,
<pb n="25" facs="tcp:101268:13"/> or copy, offices, fees, goods or chattels: or that any lands, te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, hereditaments, free or copy, offices, fees, goods or chattels ſhall deſcend, revert, or by any means come to any ſuch perſon or perſons being Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, as is aforeſaid, before ſuch time as their debts due to their creditors ſhall be fully ſatisfied and payed, or otherwiſe agreed for: that then the ſaid lands, te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, hereditaments, as well free as copy, offices, fees, goods and chattels, ſhall by ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tue of this Act, be by the ſaid Commiſſioners to be appointed as is aforeſaid, or the more part of them, be bargained, ſold, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended, delivered and uſed for and towards the payment of the ſaid creditors, in ſuch like manner and form as other the lands, tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, hereditaments, free or copy, offices, fees, goods, and chattels of the ſaid Bankrupts,
<pb n="26" facs="tcp:101268:14"/> which they had when they were firſt declared to be Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, ſhould or might have been bargained, ſold, diſpoſed, or uſed by vertue of this Act.</p>
               <p>Provided alwayes, that this Act ſhall not extend to any lands, tenements, or hereditaments free or copy-hold, which hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore have been aſſured by any ſuch Bankrupt, or hereafter ſhall be aſſured by any Bankrupt before he become Bankrupt: ſo always that ſuch aſſurance be made <hi>bona fide,</hi> and not to the uſe of the Bankrupt himſelf only, or of his heirs: and that the parties to whoſe uſe ſuch aſſurance hath or ſhall be made, be not at or before the making of ſuch aſſurance, privy or conſenting to the frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulent purpoſe of any ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, to deceive his Creditors. <hi>1 Jac. 15. 21. Jac. 15.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="27" facs="tcp:101268:14"/>
               <head>1 <hi>Jacob. Chap.</hi> 15. An Expoſition and addition to the Statutes of Bankrupts, made 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 7.</head>
               <p>FOr that fraud and deceits as new diſeaſes, dayly increaſe amongſt ſuch as live by buying and ſelling, to the hindrance of traffick and mutual commerce, and to the general hurt of the Realm, by ſuch as wickedly and wilfully become Bankrupts: And for that the deſcription of a Bankrupt, in former Statutes is not ſo fully expreſſed, nor the power given thereby to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners for Bankrupts, ſo large as is meet, in ſuch caſes of deceit, to prevent the deceit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful actions of Bankrupts.</p>
               <p>For remedy whereof, Be it therefore enacted by our Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Lord the King, and by the
<pb n="28" facs="tcp:101268:15"/> Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and the Commons at this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Parliament aſſembled, and by the authority of the ſame, That all and every ſuch perſon and perſons, uſing or that ſhall uſe the trade of Merchandize, by way of bargaining, exchange, bartrie,, cheviſance, or otherwiſe in groſs, or by retail, or ſeeking his, her, or their trade of living by buying and ſelling, and being a Subject born of this Realm, or any the Kings Dominions, or Denizen, who at any time ſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thence the firſt day of this pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent Parliament, or at any time hereafter ſhall depart the Realm or begin to keep his or her houſe or houſes, or otherwiſe to abſent him or her ſelf, or take Sanctu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ary, or ſuffer him or her ſelf, willingly to be arreſted for any debt, or other thing not grown or due for money delivered, wares ſold, or any other juſt or lawful
<pb n="29" facs="tcp:101268:15"/> cauſe, or good conſideration, or purpoſes, or hath or will ſuffer him or her ſelf to be outlawed, or yield him or her ſelf to priſon, or willingly or fraudulently hath or ſhall procure him or her ſelf to be arreſted, or his or her goods, money or chattels, to be attached or ſequeſtred, or depart from his or her dwelling houſe, or make or cauſe to be made any fraudu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent grant or conveyance of his, her or their Lands, Tenements, goods or chattels, to the intent or whereby his, her or their Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors being Subjects born as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, ſhall or may be defeated or delayed for the recovery of their juſt and true debts, or being arreſted for debt, ſhall after his or her arreſt, lie in priſon ſix months or more, upon that ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt or upon any other arreſt or detention in priſon for debt, and lie in priſon ſix months upon ſuch other arreſt or detention, ſhall
<pb n="30" facs="tcp:101268:16"/> be accompted and adjudged a Bankrupt to all intents and pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted by the authority of this preſent Parliament, that the like Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſions, orders, benefits and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medies, which are and be provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded and limited by the ſaid form<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er Act of Parliament (made in <hi>13 nuper Eliz. Reginae)</hi> againſt any Bankrupts therein deſcribed, for or concerning his, her or their lands, tenements, hereditaments, fees, annuities, offices, goods, chattels, wares, merchandizes and debts, or any of them, ſhall be had, purſued, taken and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded againſt ſuch perſon and perſons that are herein ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed to be Bankrupts, his, her, and their lands, tenements, he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, fees, annuities, of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices, goods, chattels, wares, mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandiſes and debts, in ſuch like manner and form as the ſame
<pb n="31" facs="tcp:101268:16"/> ought or might have been if the perſons herein deſcribed to be Bankrupts had been deſcribed to be Bankrupts, according to the intent of the ſaid former Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute.</p>
               <p>And that it ſhall be lawful for any of the creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt within iiii months after any ſuch Commiſſion ſhall be ſued forth, and until diſtribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion ſhall be made by the ſaid Commiſſioners for the payment of the Bankrupts debts, as in ſuch caſe hath been uſed, to partake, and joyn with the other Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, that<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſhall ſue forth any ſuch commiſſion, for ſatisfaction and payment of his, her or their debts, to him or them owing, without a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny hindrance, let or diſturbance of any of the ſame Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or of any of the other cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors of any ſuch Bankrupts, the ſame Creditors ſo coming in to contribute to the charges of
<pb n="32" facs="tcp:101268:17"/> the ſaid Commiſſion, and that if the ſaid Creditors come not in within iiii months, then the Commiſſioners to have power to diſtribute.</p>
               <p>Be it further enacted, that if any perſon which hereafter is or ſhall be a Bankrupt, by intent of this Statute, ſhall convey or procure, or cauſe to be conveyed to any of his children, or other perſon or perſons, any mannors, lands, tenements, hereditaments, offices, fees, annuities, leaſes, goods, chattels, or transfer his debts into other mens names, ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept the ſame ſhall be purchaſed, conveyed, or transferred, for or upon marriage of any of his or her children, both the parties married, being of the years of conſent, or ſome valuable conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration, ſhall be in the power and authority of the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners in this behalf to be appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, or the more part of them, to
<pb n="33" facs="tcp:101268:17"/> bargain, ſell, grant, convey, de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe, or otherwiſe to diſpoſe thereof, in as ample manner, as if the ſaid Bankrupt had been actually ſeiſed or poſſeſſed there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, or the debts were in his own name of the like eſtate or intereſt to his or their own uſe, at ſuch time as he or ſhee became Bankrupt. And that every ſuch grant, bargain, ſale, conveyance, and diſpoſition of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or of the greater part of them, ſhall be good and avail<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able to all intents, conſtructions, and purpoſes in the Law againſt the offender or offenders, his heirs, executors, adminiſtrators, and aſſigns, and ſuch children and perſons as ſhall be ſubject to this Statute, and againſt all other perſon and perſons claiming by, from, or under ſuch offender or offenders, or ſuch ſaid other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, to whom ſuch conveyance ſhall be made by the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,
<pb n="34" facs="tcp:101268:18"/> or by his means or procure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</p>
               <p>And for that the practiſes of Bankrupts of late are ſo ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cret and ſo ſubtile, as that they can very hardly be found out, or brought to light: and for that the former ſtatute giving power to the Commiſſioners to exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine others than the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, hath not fully or ſufficient<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly authorized them to examine the ſaid Bankrupt upon oath: For remedie whereof, Be it further enacted by the authority of this preſent Parliament, That the ſaid Commiſſioners may call before them, or the greater part of them, the ſaid Bankrupt: and if upon lawful warning left or made in writing at three ſeve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral times at the dwelling place or houſe where the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, his wife or family, for the moſt part of his abode, did lodge or remain, within one year
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:101268:18"/> next before he, ſhe, or they be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came Bankrupt, the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt ſhall not appear before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, That then and from thenceforth it ſhall be lawful for the greater number of the ſaid Commiſſioners, to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>point to proclaim the ſaid party a Bankrupt, at ſuch publick place or places, where the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or the greater part of them ſhall think meet, warning him, her, or them to appear be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them upon the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, at ſome time appointed. And that if upon the five ſeveral Proclamations made in ſome publick place, the party offending appear not before the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſiioners, and yield his, her or their bodies to them, or ſome of them, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, ſhall or may award a Warrant to ſuch fit perſon or perſons, as they
<pb n="36" facs="tcp:101268:19"/> think meet, to apprehend the bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy and bodies of the ſaid offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, and offenders, and to bring him, her, or them ſo offending, before the ſaid Commiſſioners, whereſoever the ſaid party or parties offending may be found, in place priviledged or not, to be examined by the ſaid Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, or the greater part of them.</p>
               <p>And that it ſhall be lawful for the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, to exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine the ſaid offender or offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, upon ſuch Interrogatories, touching the Lands, tenements, goods, chattels, debts, bills, bonds, books of account, and ſuch other things, as may tend to diſcloſe his, her, or their eſtate, or the ſecret grants, conveyances and eloyuing of his, or their lands, tenements, goods, money and debts, as they ſhall think meet.</p>
               <pb n="37" facs="tcp:101268:19"/>
               <p>And that if therein the offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der or offenders ſhall refuſe to be examined, or to anſwer fully to every Interrogatory to him to be miniſtred by the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, or the greater part of them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> it ſhall be lawful for the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter part of them to commit the ſaid offender or offenders to ſome ſtrait or cloſe impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, there to remain untill he, ſhe, or they ſhall better conform him or her ſelf.</p>
               <p>And that if upon his, her or their examination it ſhall appear, that he, ſhe, or they have com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted any wilful or corrupt per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury, tending to the hurt or da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mage of the creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, to the value of ten pounds of lawful money of En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland, or above, the party ſo of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fending, ſhall or may thereof be indicted in any of the Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſties Courts of Record, and
<pb n="38" facs="tcp:101268:20"/> being lawfully convicted thereof, ſhall ſtand upon the Pillory in ſome publick place by the ſpace of two hours, and have one of his ears nailed to the pillory, and cut off.</p>
               <p>And whereas by the former Statute made in the ſaid thir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teenth year of the reign of the late Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners for Bankrupts have power given to them to ſend for ſuch perſon or perſons as the creditors ſhall know, ſuppoſe, or ſuſpect to have, detain, or keep any part of the mony, goods, chattels, or debts of the ſaid of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fender or offenders, or to be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>debted to the ſaid offender or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders, to be examined by the ſaid Commiſſioners, as by the ſame Statute appeareth, but have not good means or remedy by impriſonment or other penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, to procure the perſon ſo ſent for by them to appear before
<pb n="39" facs="tcp:101268:20"/> them, nor having appeared be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them, to make anſwer upon his oath to ſuch Interrogatories as ſhall be miniſtred unto him by the ſaid Commiſſioners, for and upon the ſpecialty, certainty, true declaration and knowledge of ſuch lands, tenements, here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, goods, debts or other things of any ſuch offender or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders, as be, or ſhall be, or which ſhall be ſuſpected to be in his cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, uſe or poſſeſſion, or in the cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy, uſe, or poſſeſſion of any other to his knowledge and of all debts owing to, or for the benefit of ſuch offender or offenders, by himſelf or by any other to his knowledge, ſo as many times a great part of the offender or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders lands, tenements, here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, goods, chattels, or debts, which by the true intent of the ſaid Statute ſhould be im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed to the ſatisfaction of the creditors of the offendor or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders,
<pb n="40" facs="tcp:101268:21"/> are concealed or detain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the hands of ſuch perſon and perſons as refuſe to come, or being come refuſe to be ſworn before the ſaid Commiſſioners, to be examined in that behalf, to the great encouragement of all Bankrupts and their wicked confederates and acceſſaries, and to the great hindrance of the juſt remedies of the creditors of the ſaid Bankrupts for their true and juſt debts to them ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing: For remedy whereof, be it further enacted by the authority aforeſaid, That if any perſon or perſons being known, ſuppoſed, or ſuſpected to have or detain any part of the lands, tenements, or hereditaments, goods, chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels or debts of the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, or to be indebted to, or for the benefit of the ſaid Bankrupt, ſhall after lawful warning to the ſaid perſon or perſons given to come before the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners,
<pb n="41" facs="tcp:101268:21"/> or the greater part of them, to be examined according to the intent of the ſaid Statute, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to come, or ſhall not come before the ſaid Commiſſioners at the time appointed, having no lawful impediment (ſuch as ſhall be admitted and allowed of by the ſaid Commiſſioners or the more part of them, and which ſhall be then ſignified or made known to the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, at the time of their aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembly;) Or that any ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons having knowledge or warning of any other aſſem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bly or meeting of the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners again, ſhall not come and appear before them at ſuch time as he or ſhe lawfully may come, having no ſuch lawful im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pediment as ſhall be then made known to the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, and by them admitted and allowed of as aforeſaid, Or being come before them ſhall refuſe to
<pb n="42" facs="tcp:101268:22"/> be ſworn and to make anſwer to ſuch Interrogatories as ſhall be miniſtred unto him or them, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the true intent and meaning of the ſaid Statute made in the ſaid thirteenth year of the reign of our ſaid late So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vereign Lady Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> or of this preſent Act, That then it ſhall be lawful for the ſaid Commiſſioners, or for the great<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er part of them, to commit to ſuch Ward and Priſon as to them or to the greater part of them ſhall be thought meet, all ſuch perſon and perſons as ſhall ſo refuſe to be ſworn and make anſwer to ſuch Interrogatories as ſhall be ſo miniſtred as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, and alſo to direct their War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants to ſuch perſon or perſons as to them or the greater part of them ſhall be thought meet, to apprehend and arreſt ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons as ſhall refuſe to appear before them as aforeſaid,
<pb n="43" facs="tcp:101268:22"/> and to bring him, her, or them before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them to be examined as above-ſaid, and upon his, her, or their refuſal to come or to be examined before the ſaid Commiſſioners as a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, to commit the ſaid par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſo refuſing, to ſuch priſons as the ſaid Commiſſioners or the greater part of them ſhall think meet, there to remain without bail or mainpriſe, until ſuch time as the ſaid perſon ſo refuſing to come, or to be ſworn to anſwer before the ſaid Commiſſioners, ſhall ſubmit him or her ſelf to the ſaid Commiſſioners, and be by them examined according to the true intent of the ſaid Statute, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and of this preſent Act.</p>
               <p>Provided alwayes, that ſuch Witneſſes as ſhall ſo be ſent for, ſhall have ſuch coſts and charges as the Commiſſioners
<pb n="44" facs="tcp:101268:23"/> in their diſcretion ſhall think fit: The ſame charges to be ratably born by the Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, according to the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portion of each of their ſeveral debts. And if any perſon o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> perſons, other than the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, either by ſubornation, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lawful procurement, ſiniſter per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwaſion, or means of any others, or by his own act, conſent, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>greement, ſhall wilfully and cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruptly commit any manner of wilfull pe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>jury by his depoſition to be taken before the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or the greater part of them, as aforeſaid, That then the party or parties ſo offending, and all and every perſon and perſons, that ſhall unlawful<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and corruptly procure a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ſuch unlawful, wilful, and corrupt perjury, ſhall, or may therefore be indicted in any of the Kings Majeſties Courts of Record, and after his or their
<pb n="45" facs="tcp:101268:23"/> conviction thereof, ſhall incur ſuch forfeiture, and receive and ſuffer ſuch pains and puniſhment as are limited by the Statute made concerning Perjury, in the fifth year of the Reign of our ſaid late Sovereign Lady Queen <hi>Elizabeth.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And be it further enacted, That all and every ſum and ſums of money, which ſhall be forfeited by force of this preſent Act, ſhall be ſued for, and recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red by the ſaid creditors only, or any of them that will ſue for the ſame, by Action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information, in any of the Kings Majeſties Courts of Record; and the ſum or ſums of money ſo recovered, the charges of ſuit being deducted, ſhall be diſtributed and divided towards the payment of the ſaid creditors of the Bankrupt.</p>
               <p>And for that the power &amp; autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity given to the Commiſſioners
<pb n="46" facs="tcp:101268:24"/> of Bankrupts, touching the debts due to the ſaid Bankrupts, is not ſo full and perfect, as that the full benefit thereof in due courſe, might be imployed to the uſe of the ſaid Creditors, as was intended: For remedie thereof, Be it further enacted by the Au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority aforeſaid, That the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners of Bankrupts, or the greater part of them all have power to grant and aſſign, or otherwiſe to order or diſpoſe, all or any of the debts due, to and for the benefit of the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, by what perſon or perſons ſoever, or in what manner and form ſoever, to the uſe of the cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the true intent of the ſaid former recited Statute of Bankrupts: And that the ſame Grant, Aſſignment, or diſpoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of the ſaid debts, in form a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid to be made by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:101268:24"/> part of them, ſhall ſo veſt the property, right and intereſt of the ſaid debt, and debts, in the perſon or perſons of him, her, or them, to whom it ſhall be grant<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, aſſigned, or ordered by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter part of them, as fully to all intents and purpoſes, as if the ſaid Bill, Bond, Bonds, Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes, Recognizances, Iudg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or Contract, whereupon the ſaid Debt or Debts, Deed or Deeds ſhall ariſe or grow, had been made, to or with, or for the ſaid perſon or perſons, to whom the ſame ſhall be ſo granted, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned, or diſpoſed, by the ſaid Commiſſioners, and that after ſuch Grant, Aſſignment, or Diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition made of the ſaid Debts, that neither the Bankrupt, nor any other to whom any ſuch Debt ſhall be due ſhall have power to recover the ſame, nor to make any releaſe, or diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge
<pb n="48" facs="tcp:101268:25"/> thereof, neither ſhall the ſame be attached, as the Debt of the Bankrupt, or ſuch ſaid o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther perſon or perſons, to whom the ſame ſhall be due, by any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther perſon or perſons, according to the Cuſtome of the City of London, or otherwiſe, But that the party or par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to whome the ſame Debts ſhall be aſſigned, ſhall have like remedy to recover the ſame, as fully and lawfully in the name or names of the perſon or perſons to whom the ſame ſhall be ſo granted, aſſigned or ordered by the ſaid Commiſſioners, in all reſpects and purpoſes, as the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty himſelf might have had, any Law, Statute, Vſe, Cuſtome to the contrary thereof in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>Provided always, that no deb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor of the Bankrupt be hereby endangered, for the payment of his other debts, truly and <hi>bona
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:101268:25"/> fide,</hi> to any ſuch Bankrupt, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore ſuch time as he ſhall under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtand or know that he is become a Bankrupt.</p>
               <p>Provided alſo, and be it fur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther enacted, That ſuch of the ſaid Commiſſioners as ſhall put the ſaid Commiſſion in Executi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, ſhall upon lawful requeſt to them made by the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, not only make a true decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration to the ſaid Bankrupts, of the imploying and beſtowing of his, her, or their ſaid lands, tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and hereditaments, offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, fees, goods, wares, mony<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> chattels, and debts, which ſhall be paid and ſatisfied to their ſaid Creditors, as is in like caſe li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited and appointed, by the ſaid former Statute, made in the ſaid thirteenth year of the ſaid late Queens Majeſties reign, but al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo make payment of the overplus of the ſame, if any ſuch ſhall be, to the ſaid Bankrupts, their exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutors
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:101268:26"/> adminiſtrators, and aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigns, and that the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, after the full ſatisfaction of the ſaid creditors, ſhall have full power and authority to reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver and receive the reſidue and remainder of the debts to them owing, Any thing in this Act con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained to the contrary in any wiſe notwithſtanding.</p>
               <p>Be it further enacted, That if any Action of Treſpaſs, or other ſuit, ſhall happen hereafter to be brought againſt any Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner authorized by the Statute, made in <hi>decimo tertio</hi> of our late Sovereign Lady Queen <hi>Eliza<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beth,</hi> for Bankrupts, or any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther perſon or perſons having au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority by vertue or under the Commiſſion, authoriſing the ſaid Commiſſioner for the doing or executing of any matter, by force of the ſaid Statute, or this preſent Statute, That the defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant or defendants, in any ſuch
<pb n="51" facs="tcp:101268:26"/> action or ſuit, may plead Not guilty, or otherwiſe juſtifie that the Act or thing whereof the plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff or plaintiffs complained, was done by Authority of the ſaid Act made in the thirteenth of <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> or in this preſent act reſpectively, without expreſſing or rehearſal of any other matter or circumſtance contained in ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther of the ſaid Acts, and with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out inforcing him or them to ſhew forth their Commiſſion authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zing the ſaid Act, or thing, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto the Plaintiff ſhall be admit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to reply, that the Defendant did the Fact, ſuppoſed in the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claration, of his own wrong, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out any ſuch cauſe alledged by the ſaid Defendant; whereupon the iſſue in ſuch action, ſhall be joyned to be tried by verdict of twelve men, and upon trial of that iſſue, the whole matter to be given on both parties in evidence, according to the very truth of the
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:101268:27"/> ſame. And if verdict upon ſuch iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſue ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ll paſs for the defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant, the defendant to have his coſts.</p>
               <p>Provided always, and be it further enacted, That after any Commiſſion of Bankrupts here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſued forth, and dealt in by the Commiſſioners, if the offendor happen to die, be<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ore the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners ſhall diſtribute the Goods, Lands, and Debts of the offendors, or any of them, by force of the foreſaid Statute, of the thirteenth year of the Reign of our late Sovereign Lady Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> and this Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, or either of them, That then nevertheleſs, the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners ſhall and may in that caſe proceed in execution, in, and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the ſaid Commiſſion, for, and concerning the offenders Goods, Lands, Tenem<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>nts, Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and Debts, in ſuch ſort as they might have done, if the
<pb n="53" facs="tcp:101268:27"/> party Offenders were living. <hi>Stat. 21 Jac. 19.</hi>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <head>21 <hi>Jac. Chap.</hi> 19. A further deſcription of a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt. The Sta<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>utes of 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> 7. and 1, Jac. 15 enlarged.</head>
               <p>FOr as much as daily experi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence ſheweth, that the num<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber and multitude of Bankrupts do increaſe more and more, and alſo the frauds and deceits inven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted and practiſed for the avoiding and deluding the penalties of the good Laws in that behalf al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ready made, and the remedy by them provided: And for that di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers defects are daily found in the former Statutes made a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Bankrupts, doth in the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcription of a Bankrupt, as alſo in the power given to the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners for the diſcovery and diſtributing the Bankrupts e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate,
<pb n="54" facs="tcp:101268:28"/> to the great incourage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of evil minded perſons, the hindrance of traffique and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>merce, the great decay, over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>throw and undoing of many Clo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thiers, by whom many thouſands of the natural born Subjects of this Realm, be from time to time in all parts of this Kingdom ſet on work: all which do tend to the general hurt of this Realm: For remedy whereof, be it enact<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Kings moſt excellent Majeſty, the Lords Spiritual and Temporal, and Commons in this preſent Parliament aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſembled, and by the Authority of the ſame, That all and ſingular the aforeſaid Statutes and Laws heretofore made againſt Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, and for relief of Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, ſhall be in all things large<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and beneficially conſtrued and expounded for the ayd, help, and relief of the Creditors of ſuch perſon or perſons as already
<pb n="55" facs="tcp:101268:28"/> be, or hereafter ſhall become Bankrupt.</p>
               <p>And that all and every perſon and perſons uſing or that ſhall uſe the trade of Merchandize, by way of bargaining, exchange, barte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring, cheviſance, or otherwiſe in groſs, or by retail, or ſeeking his, or her living, by buying and ſell<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, or that ſhall uſe the trade or profeſſion of a Scrivener, recei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving other mens moneys or e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtates into his truſt or cuſtody, who at any time after the end of preſent Seſſion of Parliament, ſhall either by himſelf, or others by his procurement, obtain any protection or protections, other than ſuch perſon or perſons as ſhall be lawfully protected by the priviledge of Parliament, or ſhall prefer or exhibit unto his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty, his Heirs or Succeſſors, or unto any of the Kings Courts, any Petition or Petitions, Bill or Bills againſt his or her Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:101268:29"/> or Creditors, or any of them, thereby deſiring, or indeavouring to compel or enforce them, or any of them, to accept leſs than their juſt and principal debts, or to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cure time, or longer days of pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, than was given at the time of their originall contracts, or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing indebted to any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons in the ſum of one hundred pounds or more, ſhall not pay, or otherwiſe compound for the ſame, within ſix months next after the ſame ſhall grow due, and the D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>btor be arreſted for the ſame, or within ſix months after an ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginall Writ ſued out to recover the ſaid debt, and notice thereof given unto him, or left in writing, at his, or their dwelling houſe, or laſt place of abode<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or being ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſted for debt, ſhall after his or her arreſt, lie in priſon two months or more, upon that, or any other arreſt or detention in priſon for debt, or being arreſted
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:101268:29"/> the ſum of one hundred pounds or more, of juſt debt or debts, ſhall at any time after ſuch ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt, eſcape out of priſon, or pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cure his enlargement, by putting in common or hired Bayl, ſhall be accounted and adjudged a Bankrupt to all intents and pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes: And in the ſaid caſes of arreſt, or lying in priſon for ſuch debt or debts, or getting forth by common or hired Bayl, from the time of his or her ſaid firſt ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted by the authority of this preſent Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, that the like Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, Orders, Benefits, and Remedies, which are and be pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided and limited by the ſaid for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer Acts of Parliaments, made in the thirteenth year of the late Queen <hi>Elizabeth,</hi> and in the firſt year of the Reign of our Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Lord the Kings Majeſty, againſt any Bankrupts in them,
<pb n="58" facs="tcp:101268:30"/> or either of them deſcribed, or for, or concerning his, her, or their Lands, Tenements, Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Fees, Annuities, Offi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, Goods, Chattels, Wares, Merchandize and Debts, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them, ſhall and may be had, purſued, taken, and expounded againſt ſuch perſon and perſons as are herein, and hereby, decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, deſcribed, or expreſſed to be Bankrupts and againſt his, her, and their Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments,, Fees, Annui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Officers, Goods, Chattels, Wares, Merchandizes and Debts, in ſuch manner and form, as the ſame ought, and might have been, if the perſons herein declared, deſcribed, or expreſſed to be Bankrupts, had been by the ſaid Statutes, or either of them, deſcribed to be Bankrupts, to all intents and purpoſes whatſoe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver.</p>
               <p>And be it enacted by the autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity,
<pb n="59" facs="tcp:101268:30"/> aforeſaid, That the ſame or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders, benefits and remedies, which are, and be provided and limited by this preſent Act, againſt any Bankrupts, in, or by this Act declared, deſcribed, or expreſſed to be Bankrupts, or for, or concerning his, her, or their Lands, Tenements, Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Fees, Annuities, Offices, Goods, Chattels, Wares, Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandizes and Debts, or any of them,, or the diſcovery of them, or any of them, ſhall from hence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forth be had, purſued, taken and expounded againſt ſuch perſon and perſons, as are declared or expreſſed to be Bankrupts, by the ſaid former Acts of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, or either of them, and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt his, her, and their Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Fees, Annuities, Offices, Goods, Chattels, Wares, Merchandi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zes and Debts, in ſuch manner and form, as the ſame ought and
<pb n="60" facs="tcp:101268:31"/> might have been, if the perſons in the ſaid former Statutes, or either of them deſcribed to be Bankrupts, had been mentioned and deſcribed to be Bankrupts, in, and by this preſent Act.</p>
               <p>And whereas by the former Laws, the Commiſſioners appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, have power to examine the Bankrupt himſelf, and ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons, as are ſuſpected to have, or detain of the eſtate, goods or chattels of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, but ſome doubt hath been made whether the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners have power to examine the wives of the Bankrupts touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſame, by reaſon whereof the Bankrupts wives do daily conceal, and convey away, and cauſe to be conveyed away much part of their husbands moneys, wares, goods, merchandize and other eſtate, to perſon or perſons unknown to any, but ſuch wives, by reaſon whereof much of the
<pb n="61" facs="tcp:101268:31"/> Bankrupts eſtate is concealed, and detained from the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors,</p>
               <p>For clearing therefore the ſaid doubt, and avoiding the inconve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niences aforeſaid, Be it declared and enacted by the authority a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, That after ſuch time, as any perſon ſhall by the ſaid Commiſſioners, executing the ſaid Commiſſion, or the greater part of them, be lawfully ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged or declared to be a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, the ſaid Commiſſioners executing ſuch commiſſion, ſhall have power and authority to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amine upon oath, the wife and wives of all and every ſuch Bankrupt, for the finding out, and diſcovery of the eſtate, and eſtates, goods, &amp; chattels of ſuch Bankrupt<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or Bankrupts, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealed, kept or diſpoſed of, by ſuch wife or wives, in their own perſon or perſons, or by their own act or means, or by any
<pb n="62" facs="tcp:101268:32"/> other perſon or perſons. And that ſhee and they, the ſaid wife and wives, ſhall incur ſuch dan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger and penalty for not coming before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or for refuſing to be ſworn and examined, or for not diſcloſing the truth upon her or their exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mination, or examinations, as in, and by the ſaid former Laws, or either of them is already made, and provided againſt any other perſon, or perſons in like caſes.</p>
               <p>And be it further euacted by the authority aforeſaid, That if any Bankrupt ſhall upon his, or her examination, or examinati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to be taken before the ſaid Commiſſioners, executing the ſaid Commiſſion, be found frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulently, or deceitfully to have conveyed away his, or her Goods, Chattels, Lands, Tenements, Offices, Fees, Rents or Annui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, or other Eſtate, or any part
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:101268:32"/> thereof, to the value of twenty pounds or above, to the end and purpoſe to hinder the execution of this Statute, or of any other the aforeſaid Statutes, or there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>by to defraud, delay, or hinder his or her Creditors of the ſame, and ſhall not upon his or her ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amination diſcover unto the ſaid Commiſſioners, and (if it lie in his or her power) deliver unto the ſaid Commiſſioners, all that eſtate, Goods, and Chattels, ſo fraudulently, and deceitfully conveyed away, as aforeſaid, or by him or her, his or her means, kept or detained from the ſaid Commiſſioners, or that cannot make it appear unto the ſaid Commiſſioners that he or ſhe hath ſuſtained ſome caſual loſs, whereby he or ſhe is diſabled to pay, what he or ſhe then owed, ſhall or may be indicted for ſuch fraud or abuſe, at the Aſſiſes or general Seſſions, to be holden
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:101268:33"/> before the Iudges of Aſſiſe, or Iuſtices of the Peace of the County or place, where he or ſhe ſhall become Bankrupt<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> And if upon ſuch Indictment or Indict<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, the Bankrupt be there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of convicted, he or ſhee ſo con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>victed, ſhall be ſet upon the Pil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lory in ſome publick place, for the ſpace of two hours, and have one of his or her ears nailed to the Pillory, and cut off.</p>
               <p>And for that ſome doubt is conceived, whether the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners in caſe of reſiſtance, have power by the former Laws, to break open, or cauſe to be bro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken open, the Houſe or Houſes of ſuch Bankrupts, which if they have not, the remedies by the former Laws given, will be to little effect: Be it therefore en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted, That in the execution of the ſaid Commiſſion, it ſhall be lawful, to, and for the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or the greater part of
<pb n="65" facs="tcp:101268:33"/> them, or any other perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, Officer or Officers, by them, or the greater part of them, to be deputed and appointed by their Warrant or Warrants, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der their hands and ſeals, to break open the Houſe or Houſes, Chambers, Shops, Warehou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, Doors, Trunks or Cheſts of the ſaid Bankrupt, where the ſaid Bankrupt, or any of his or her Goods or Eſtate, ſhall be, or reputed to be, and to ſeize upon, and order the body, Goods, Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, ready Money, and other e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate of ſuch Bankrupt, as by the ſaid former Laws are limit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and appointed, whether it be by impriſonment of his or her body, or otherwiſe, as to the ſaid Commiſſioners or the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter part of them, ſhall be thought meet.</p>
               <p>And for the better diviſion and diſtribution of the Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Hereditaments, Goods,
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:101268:34"/> Chattels, and other Eſtate of ſuch Bankrupts, to, and amongſt his or her Creditors, Be it enacted that the Commiſſioners, or the greateſt part of them, ſhall, and may examine upon oath, or by any other ways or means, as to them ſhall ſeem meet, any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons for the finding out, and diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very of the truth, and certainty of the ſeveral debts due, and owing, to all ſuch Creditor and Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, as ſhall ſeek relief by ſuch courſe or Commiſſion to be ſued forth, as aforeſaid: And that all and every Creditor &amp; Creditors, having ſecurity for his, or their ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral Debts, by Iudgment, Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, Recognizance, Specialty with penalty or without penalty, or other ſecurity, or having no ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curity, or having made Attach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in London, or any other place, by vertue of any cuſtome there uſed, of the Goods and Chattels of any ſuch Bankrupt,
<pb n="67" facs="tcp:101268:34"/> whereof there is no execution or Extent ſerved and executed, upon any the Lands, Tenements, He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, Goods, Chattels, and other eſtate of ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, before ſuch time, as he or ſhe ſhall, or do become Bankrupt, ſhall not be relieved upon any ſuch Iudgment, Statute, Recog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizance, Specialty, Attachments, or other ſecurity, for any or more than a ratable part of their juſt and due debts, with the other Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out reſpect to any ſuch penalty, or greater ſum contained in any ſuch Iudgment, Statute, Recogni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zance, Specialty with Penalty, Attachment or other Security.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted, that if it ſhall happen, any the Lands, Tenements, Goods, Chattels, Debts, or other e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate of any Bankrupt, to be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended, after ſuch time as he, or ſhe is become a Bankrupt, by any
<pb n="68" facs="tcp:101268:35"/> perſon or perſons, under colour or pretence, of his or their being an Accomptant, or any way indebted unto our Sovereign Lord the Kings Majeſty, his Heirs or Suc<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſors, that then it ſhall be lawful, to, and for the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, to examine upon oath, whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther the ſaid Debt were due to ſuch Debtor or Accomptant, upon any bargain or contract original<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly made, betwixt ſuch Accomp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tant, and the ſaid Bankrupt, the ſaid Debtor or Accomptant, and his, or their ſervants: And if ſuch bargain or contract was original<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly made, to, and with any other perſon or perſons, than the ſaid Debtor or Accomptant, or for the uſe and truſt of any other perſon or perſons, than it ſhall and may be lawful, to and for the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them to order and diſpoſe of all ſuch Lands, tenements, He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, Goods, Chattels,
<pb n="69" facs="tcp:101268:35"/> and Debts ſo extended, as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, to and for the uſe of the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, which ſhall ſeek relief by the ſaid Commiſſion; And that the order and diſpoſition of the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, ſhall be good and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vailable a gainſt the ſaid extent, and againſt all perſons claiming, from, by, or under the ſaid extent: And that ſuch perſon or perſons, to whom the ſaid Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Goods and Chattels ſo extended, ſhall be bargained, ſold, granted, or aſſigned by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners aforeſaid, or the greater part of them, ſhall have good re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy, to have, demand, and reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver the ſame, againſt ſuch perſon and perſons, who ſhall detain the ſame: And for that it often falls out, that many perſons before they become Bankrupts, do con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vey their Goods to other men, upon good conſideration, yet ſtill do keep the ſame, and are reputed
<pb n="70" facs="tcp:101268:36"/> the owners thereof, and diſpoſe the ſame as their own.</p>
               <p>Be it enacted, that if at any time hereafter, any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſhall become Bankrupt, and at ſuch time as they ſhall ſo be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>me Bankrupt, ſhall by the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent and permiſſion of the true owner, and proprietary, have in their poſſeſſion, order, and diſpoſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, any Goods, or Chattels, whereof they ſhall be reputed ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, and take upon them the ſale, alteration, or diſpoſition, as ow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, that in every ſuch caſe, the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter part of them, ſhall have power to ſell and diſpoſe the ſame, to, and for the benefit of the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, which ſhall ſeek relief by the ſaid Commiſſion, as fully as any other part of the eſtate of the Bankrupt: and for the better payment of debts, and diſcourag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing men to become Bankrupts:</p>
               <p>Be it further enacted, that the
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:101268:36"/> ſaid Commiſſioners, or the grea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter number of them, ſhall have power by vertue of this Act, by deed indented, and enrolled with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in ſix months after the making thereof, in ſome of his Majeſties Court of Record at Weſtminſter, to grant, bargain, ſell and convey any Mannors, Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, or Hereditaments, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of any Bankrupt is, or ſhall be in any ways ſeized of any eſtate, in tail, in poſſeſſion, reverſion or re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mainder, and whereof no rever<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion, or remainder is, or ſhall be in the Kings Majeſty, his Heirs, or Succeſſors, of the gift or proviſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of his Majeſty, his Progeni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, his Heirs, or Succeſſors, to any perſon or perſons, for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lief and benefit of the Creditors of all ſuch Bankrupts, and that all &amp; every ſuch grants, bargains, ſales, and conveyances ſhall be good and available in the Law, to ſuch perſon or perſons, and their
<pb n="72" facs="tcp:101268:37"/> heirs, againſt the ſaid Bankrupts, and againſt all and every the Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſues of the body of ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, and againſt all and every perſon and perſons, claiming any eſtate, right, title, or intereſt, by, from, or under the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, after ſuch time as ſuch per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſhall become Bankrupt, and againſt all and every other perſon and perſons whatſoever, whom the ſaid Bankrupt by common recovery, or other ways or means might cut off, or debar from any remainder, reverſion, rent, pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit, title or poſſibility, into, or out of any the ſaid Mannors, Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments.</p>
               <p>And be it further enacted, That if any perſon that now is, or here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhall become a Bankrupt, have heretofore granted, convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, or aſſured, or ſhall at any time hereafter, grant, convey, or aſſure any Lands, Tenements, Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, Goods, Chattels, or other eſtate, unto any perſon or
<pb n="73" facs="tcp:101268:37"/> perſons, upon condition, or power of redemption, at a day to come, by payment of mony, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe, That it ſhall and may be lawful, to, and for the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or the greater part of them, before the time of the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formance of ſuch condition, to aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſign and appoint, under their hands and ſeals, ſuch perſon or perſons, as they ſhall think fit, to make tender or payment of mony, or other performance, according to the nature of ſuch condition, as fully as the Bankrupt might have done; and that the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, ſhall after ſuch ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, payment, or performance, have power to ſell, and diſpoſe of ſuch Lands, Tenements, Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, Goods and Chattels, and other eſtates ſo granted, con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyed, or aſſured upon condition, to, and for the benefit of the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, as fully as they may ſell or diſpoſe of any the eſtate of the Bankrupt</p>
               <pb n="74" facs="tcp:101268:38"/>
               <p>Provided further, that no Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer, for good and valuable con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration, ſhall be impeached by vertue of this Act, or any other Act heretofore made againſt Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, unleſs the Commiſſion to prove him, or her a Bankrupt, be ſued forth againſt ſuch Bankrupt within five years after he, or ſhe ſhall become a Bankrupt.</p>
               <p>Provided further, and be it enacted by the Authority afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, that this Act, and all other Acts of Parliament, heretofore made againſt Bankrupts, ſhall extend to Strangers born, as well Aliens, as Denizens, as ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectually, as to the natural born Subjects, both to make them ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject to the Laws as Bankrupts, as alſo to make them capable of the benefit or contribution, as Creditors by thoſe Laws. <hi>Stat. 34 H. 8. 4. 13 El. 7. 1 Jac. 15.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Stat. 14 <hi>Car. 2.</hi> Chap. 24.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>Whereas divers Noblemen
<pb n="75" facs="tcp:101268:38"/> and Gentlemen, not bred up in Trade, have notwithſtanding put great Stocks into the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> and <hi>Guiny</hi> Company, it is de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clared that no perſons Adven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turers for putting in Mony or Merchandiſe into the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>panies, or for adventuring or ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>naging the Fiſhing, called the Royal Fiſhing Trade, ſhall be tak<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>n or reputed a Merchant or Trader within any Statutes for bankrupts or be liable to the ſame.</p>
               <p>Provided that perſons trading and trafficking in any other way or manner than the ſaid Companies or Fiſhing ſhall be liable to the Commiſſion of Bankrupts.</p>
               <p>A Verdict and Iudgment a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt Sir <hi>Jo<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Wollaſton</hi> as a Bankrupt, for trading in the <hi>Eaſt-India</hi> Company reverſed and made void. Provided, not to a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>void any ſale or diſpoſition of his lands or goods made by vertue of the Commiſſion of Bankrupts.</p>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <pb n="76" facs="tcp:101268:39"/>
                  <head>To the Right Honourable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p>IN moſt humble manner com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaining, ſheweth unto your Lordſhip your daily Orators, <hi>T. B.</hi> of <hi>A</hi>- in the County of <hi>D.</hi> Gent. and <hi>W. P</hi> of <hi>C.</hi> in the County of <hi>E.</hi> Eſq; as well for them<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelves, as for all others the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors of <hi>R. D.</hi> of the Pariſh of <hi>M.</hi> in the City of <hi>London</hi> Merchant, That whereas the ſaid <hi>R. D.</hi> uſing and exerciſing the Trade of Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandize, by way of Bargaining, Exchange, Bartering and Chevi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſance, ſeeking his Trade of living by buying and ſelling, upon good and juſt cauſes, for Wares and Merchandizes to him ſold and de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>livered, and alſo for ready mony to him lent, being indebted to your Orators, and others his Creditors in divers and ſeveral ſums of money, amounting in the whole to the ſum
<pb n="77" facs="tcp:101268:39"/> of <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and upwards; of late, that is to ſay, about the Month of <hi>No<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vember</hi> laſt did become Bankrupt, within the ſeveral Statutes lately made againſt Bankrupts, to the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent to defraud and hinder your ſaid Orator, and all other his Creditors of their juſt Debts and Duties to them due, and owing (<hi>viz.</hi>) within the Statute made in the Parliament begun and holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the ſecond day of <hi>April</hi> in the <hi>thirteenth</hi> year of the Reign of our late Sove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reign Lady Queen <hi>Elizabeth</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Bankrupts: and within the Statute made in the Parliament be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gun and holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, the nineteenth day of <hi>March</hi> in the firſt year of the Reign of our late Sovereign Lord King <hi>James</hi> of <hi>England, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and of <hi>Scotland</hi> the ſeven and thirtieth, Intituled <hi>An Act for the better relief of the Creditors againſt ſuch as ſhall become Bankrupts;</hi> as alſo within the Statute made in the Parliament
<pb n="78" facs="tcp:101268:40"/> begun and holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the nineteenth day of <hi>February</hi> in the one and twentieth year of the Reign of our ſaid late Sovereign Lord King <hi>James</hi> of <hi>England, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and of <hi>Scotland</hi> the ſeven and fiftieth, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the further deſcription of a Bankrupt, and relief of the Creditors againſt ſuch as ſhall become Bankrupts,</hi> or within ſome or one of them: In ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der conſideration whereof, may it pleaſe your Lordſhip to grant unto your Orators his Majeſties moſt gra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cious Commiſſion to be directed to ſuch and ſo many wiſe, honeſt, and diſcreet perſons as your Lordſhip ſhall ſeem meet, authorizing them thereby, not only concerning the ſaid Bankrupt, his Body, Lands, Tenements, Free-hold and Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mary Goods, Debts, and other things whatſoever, but alſo con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning all other perſons which by concealment claim, or otherwiſe do or ſhall offend touching the premi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes,
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:101268:40"/> or any part thereof, contrary to the true intent and meaning of the ſame Statutes. To do and execute all and every thing and things what<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever, as well for, and towards ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction and payment of the ſaid Creditors, as towards and for all other intents and purpoſes, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the Ordinance and Provi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion of the ſame Statutes:</p>
                  <closer>And your Orators ſhall pray, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <pb facs="tcp:101268:41"/>
                  <list>
                     <head>In Bankrupt, Note</head>
                     <item>What he is disco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vered
<list>
                           <item>1.
<list>
                                 <item>By general deſcription, Sect. 1, 2.</item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                           <item>2.
<list>
                                 <item>By his Trade. 4, 5, 6, uſque ad Sect. 11.</item>
                                 <item>By his demeanour. 12, 13, 14, uſque ad Sect. 25.</item>
                                 <item>By the final cauſe of all. Sect. 26.</item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                     <item>The pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt, and puni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>hment of him
<list>
                           <item>1. In general he ſhall be accompted a Bankrupt, and made thereby incapable to diſpoſe of his own. Sect. 28.</item>
                           <item>2. In par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar by per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons
<list>
                                 <item>1. Immediately appointed by the Act and therein note
<list>
                                       <item>1. What they are. Sect. 29.</item>
                                       <item>2. Their au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority ſet forth
<list>
                                             <item>1. Generally. Sect. 29.</item>
                                             <item>2. Parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cularly
<list>
                                                   <item>1. Touching his perſon. Sect. 30.</item>
                                                   <item>2. As to his Eſtate and there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in note
<list>
                                                         <item>1. The way of diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vering it. 32, 33, 34.</item>
                                                         <item>2. The diſpoſal of it. Sect. 35.</item>
                                                      </list>
                                                   </item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                                 <pb facs="tcp:101268:41"/>
                                 <item>2. Mediately authoriſed by Lord Chancellor
<list>
                                       <item>1 Their Commiſſion. Sect. 36.</item>
                                       <item>2. Their au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty
<list>
                                             <item>1. As to the Bankrupts perſon. Sect. 39, 40, 41.
<list>
                                                   <item>2. As to his Eſtate</item>
                                                   <item>2. What it is
<list>
                                                         <item>real. 43, 45, uſque ad 57.</item>
                                                         <item>perſonal. 61, 62, uſque ad 71.</item>
                                                      </list>
                                                   </item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                             <item>2. The means of diſco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very
<list>
                                                   <item>as to the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons
<list>
                                                         <item>the Bankrupt himſelf, Sect. 73, 74, 75, 76.</item>
                                                         <item>the Bankrupts Wife. Sect. 77.</item>
                                                         <item>other persons
<list>
                                                               <item>what perſons. Sect. 78.</item>
                                                               <item>proceeding with them
<list>
                                                                     <item>to ſend for them. Sect. 78.</item>
                                                                     <item>to examine them. Sect. 78.</item>
                                                                     <item>to puniſh them. 79, 80, uſque ad 86.</item>
                                                                  </list>
                                                               </item>
                                                               <item>allowance to them of charges. Sect. 87.</item>
                                                            </list>
                                                         </item>
                                                      </list>
                                                   </item>
                                                   <item>as to the goods, by breaking open locks, &amp;c. for them Sect. 72.</item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                             <item>3. The diſpoſal of it.
<list>
                                                   <item>1. By appraiſement, Sect. 88, &amp;c.</item>
                                                   <item>2. By ſale, Sect. 89, &amp;c.</item>
                                                   <item>3. By Di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tribution
<list>
                                                         <item>to whom, 89, 90.</item>
                                                         <item>of what, 90, 91, 92, 93, 94, 95, 96, 97, 98.</item>
                                                         <item>the time when, not until 4 months, &amp;c. Sect. 105, 108.</item>
                                                         <item>the manner; Rate and Rate like, Sect. 109.</item>
                                                         <item>the ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect of it
<list>
                                                               <item>to barr, Sect. 112.</item>
                                                               <item>to veſt the property, Sect. 113.</item>
                                                               <item>to give means of Recovery, Sect. 112.</item>
                                                               <item>to reſtore to the Bankrupt his capaci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, Sect. 123.</item>
                                                            </list>
                                                         </item>
                                                      </list>
                                                   </item>
                                                </list>
                                             </item>
                                          </list>
                                       </item>
                                       <item>3. Their accompt.</item>
                                       <item>4. Their re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>medy, if ſued</item>
                                    </list>
                                 </item>
                              </list>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <pb n="82" facs="tcp:101268:42"/>
                  <opener>
                     <signed>
                        <hi>CHARLES</hi> the Second by the Grace of God, King of <hi>England, Scotland, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland.</hi> Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der of the Faith, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                     </signed>
                     <salute>To our truſty &amp; well beloved <hi>A. B.</hi> of <hi>E.</hi> in the County of <hi>D.</hi> Gent. <hi>S. M.</hi> of <hi>H.</hi> in the County of <hi>W.</hi> Eſq. Greeting<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>Whereas we are informed that <hi>R. D.</hi> of <hi>L.</hi> in the City of <hi>London</hi> Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chant, uſing and exerciſing the Trade of Merchandiſe by way of Bargaining, Ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change, Bartering and Cheviſance, ſeek<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his Trade of living by buying and ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling, did become Bankrupt<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> within the ſeveral Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes made againſt Bankrupts, to the intent to defraud and hinder <hi>T. B.</hi> of <hi>A.</hi> in the County of <hi>D.</hi> Gent. and <hi>W. P.</hi> of <hi>C.</hi> in the County of <hi>E.</hi> Eſq; and others his Creditors of their juſt Debts and Duties to them due, and owing, We minding the due exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution as well of the Statute touching Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ders for Bankrupts in the Parliament be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gun and holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> the ſecond day of <hi>April</hi> in the thirteenth year of the Reign of our dear Siſter <hi>Elizabeth</hi> late
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:101268:42"/> Queen of <hi>England</hi> made and provided: As of the Statute made in the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment begun and holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the nineteenth day of <hi>March,</hi> in the firſt year of the Reign of our late dear Grandfather King <hi>James</hi> of <hi>England, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and of <hi>Scotland</hi> the ſeven and thirtieth, Intituled, <hi>An Act for the better relief of Creditors a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt ſuch as ſhall become Bankrupt.</hi> And alſo of the Statute made in the Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament begun &amp; holden at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> aforeſaid, the 19th day of <hi>February</hi> in the twenty firſt year of the Reign of our ſaid late dear Grandfather K. <hi>James</hi> of <hi>England, France,</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> and of <hi>Scotland</hi> the ſeven and fiftieth, Intitu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, <hi>An Act for the further deſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of a Bankrupt, and relief of Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors againſt ſuch as ſhall become Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,</hi> upon truſt of the wiſdoms, fidelities, diligence, and provident circumſpection which we have conceived in you do by theſe preſents name, aſſign, appoint, conſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, and ordain you our ſpecial Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, giving full power and authority, un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:101268:43"/> you, four or three of you, whereof you the ſaid <hi>A. B.</hi> to be one accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to the ſame Statutes, and every, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of them not only concerning the ſaid Bankrupt his body, Lands, Tenements, Free-hold, &amp; Cuſtomary Goods, Debts, &amp; other things whatſoever, but alſo concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing all other perſons which by conceal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, claim, or otherwiſe do, or ſhall offend touching the premiſes, or any part thereof contrary to the true intent and meaning of the ſame Statutes, or any of them, to do and execute all and every thing &amp; things whatſoever, as well for and towards ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>faction and payment of the ſaid Creditors, as towards, and for all other intents and purpoſes according to the Ordinances and proviſion of the ſaid Statutes, Willing and commanding you, four, or three of you whereof you the ſaid <hi>A. B.</hi> to be one, to pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceed to the execution and accompliſhment of this our Commiſſion according to the true intent and meaning of the ſame Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes, with all diligence and effect, as our ſpecial truſt is in you.</p>
                  <closer>
                     <dateline>Witneſs Our ſelf at <hi>Weſtminſter</hi> 
                        <date>the, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                        </date>
                     </dateline>
                  </closer>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="part">
               <pb n="85" facs="tcp:101268:43"/>
               <head>What a Bankrupt is, and his Deſcription.</head>
               <p n="1">1. FIrſt in General, the word<note place="margin">His Name.</note> 
                  <hi>Bankrupt,</hi> is derived of the French word <hi>Banqueroutte,</hi> which ſignifieth a breaking, or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coming a Bankrupt: and <hi>Banquerouttier,</hi> ſignifieth a Bankrupt; and <hi>faire Banque<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>route,</hi> is as much as <hi>ſolum vertere,</hi> with the Romans: the compoſition of the French word is from <hi>Banque,</hi> which is as much as <hi>Menſa</hi> in Latine, and <hi>route,</hi> which is the ſame with <hi>Veſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gium,</hi> taken for a ſign or mark left in the place from whence a Table had been re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moved; in the ſame ſence as we in En<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliſh ſay a <hi>Cartroutte, viz.</hi> the remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing impreſſion of a Cart-wheel. The O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riginal ſeemeth to be taken from the Roman <hi>Menſarii,</hi> who had their <hi>Taber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nas</hi> and <hi>Menſas: (Tabernae</hi> being taken for Shops, ſo called <hi>a tabulis, quibus cla<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>debantur</hi>) and theſe were ſeated in pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lick
<pb n="86" facs="tcp:101268:44"/> places, from which when they were diſpoſed to ſlip away and delude their Creditors, they left only of theſe Shops ſome <hi>Veſtigia,</hi> or ſigns behind them: <hi>Vide Cowel, &amp; Minſhaw verbo Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="2">(2.) In the Statute of 34 <hi>H. 8. cap.</hi>
                  <note place="margin">His de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcripti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</note> 4. a Bankrupt is thus deſcribed: <hi>viz. Whereas divers and ſundry perſons, craf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tily obtaining into their hands great ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of other mens goods, do ſuddenly flie into parts unknown, or keep their Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, not minding to pay, or reſtore unto a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny of their Creditors their Debts and Du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, but at their own wills and pleaſures, conſume the ſubſtance (obtained by cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dit) of other men, for their own pleaſures and delicate living, againſt all equity and good Conſcience.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="3">(3.) Now more particularly, A Bankrupt is ſet forth and deſcribed in the ſeveral Statutes made againſt Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, Firſt, by his Quality and Occu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pation: Secondly, by his Demeanour and Carriage.</p>
               <p n="4">(4.) For the firſt, as to his Quality<note place="margin">His Quality.</note> and Occupation, he is thus deſcribed by 13 <hi>El. chap.</hi> 7. and 1 <hi>Jac. chap. 15. If any Merchant, or other perſon, uſing or exerciſing the trade of Merchandizing,
<pb n="87" facs="tcp:101268:44"/> by way of Bargaining, Exchange, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>change, Bartry, Cheviſance, or otherwiſe in groſs, or by retail, or ſeeking his or their Trade of living by buying and ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling,</hi>
                  <note place="margin">Subjects.</note> 
                  <hi>and being a Subject born of this Realm, or of any the Queens Dominions, or Denizen, &amp;c.</hi> Which Statute, as ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears, extends only to Subjects born, or Denizens: but the Statute of 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. extends likewiſe to ſtrangers; at the later end of which Statute there is this Proviſo, <hi>viz. Provided further and be it enacted,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>that this Act, and all other Acts of Parliament, heretofore made againſt Bankrupts, ſhall extend to Strangers born:</hi> as well aliens, as De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizens,<note place="margin">Stran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gers.</note> as effectually as to the natural born Subjects, both to make them ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ject to the Laws as Bankrupts; as alſo to make them capable of the benefit or contribution, as Creditors by thoſe Laws.</p>
               <p n="5">(5.) A Shoo-maker may be a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,<note place="margin">Shooma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker.</note> becauſe he lives by buying of Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and ſelling of it again in Shoos. <hi>Crook part 3. fol. 31. Cramp</hi> and <hi>Barn.</hi> An Inn-keeper is not within the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes of Bankrupts, for although he buy proviſion to be ſpent in his houſe, and utters it, yet he doth not properly ſell it,
<pb n="88" facs="tcp:101268:45"/> but utters it at ſuch Rates, as he thinks to be reaſonable gains, and the Gueſts do not take it, or contract for it, at a cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain price; and if he take exceſſive pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ces, he is indictable; and Inn-keepers have many times Hay, Corn, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of their own growth, and their gains ariſe by the attendance of their ſervants, and furni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture of their Houſe and Rooms for the accommodation of his Gueſts. <hi>Crook 3 part. fol. 549. Criſp verſ. Prat.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="6">(6.) The like I ſuppoſe may be ſaid of a Taylor, for his Trade is not by buy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and ſelling, but by making of the Garment, and in what he buyeth, he doth it, but as a ſervant to his Cuſtomers, and ought not to take any more than he lays out.</p>
               <p n="7">(7.) Sir <hi>John Wolſtenholm,</hi> one of the Eaſt-India Company, a perſon of 3000 <hi>l.</hi> lands a year; yet in regard he had a ſtock in that company, and received the proceed thereof, he was held to be within the Statutes of Bankrupts, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though he did not get the greateſt part of his living by buying and ſelling; not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding the words of the Statute: [<hi>Seeking his or their Trade by buying and ſelling:</hi>] for the Statute ſhall be ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pounded beneficially for the Creditors:
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:101268:45"/> and it is not the Quality of a mans Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon, or the greatneſs of his Eſtate, that exempts him out of the Statute. <hi>Hughs Abridgment, fol. 315. Caſe</hi> 7.</p>
               <p n="8">(8.) A Feme covert, ſole Merchant in <hi>London</hi> (being ſuch an one as driveth one Trade, and her Husband another) by the cuſtom of that City may bring an action without her Husband, and be ſued without her Husband, 1 <hi>E. 4. pag.</hi> 13. And if her Husband be named with her in an action brought againſt her, it is but for conformity: <hi>contra,</hi> if ſhe exerciſe the ſame Trade with her Husband, al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though ſhe buy and ſell, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for it ſhall be intended as ſervant to her Husband: <hi>Crooke 3 pag. fol.</hi> 69. alſo a feme covert ſole Merchant, may give away and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe of her goods without her Husband, 21 <hi>H. 7. 18. pag.</hi> 29. A Feme covert ſole Merchant may be a Bankrupt, for if the Cuſtom of <hi>London</hi> doth create in her a diſtinct property from her Husband in the goods ſhe deals in: by the ſame rea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſhe alone may become a Bankrupt, within the Statute, and her husband not included, and her husband be alſo a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, and ſhe not thereby included. Yet Quere, for the wife is <hi>ſub poteſtate viri,</hi> by the Law of God, and Nature, from which
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:101268:46"/> no cuſtom can exempt her; and her huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band when he pleaſe may determine her ſole Merchantſhip; and there it may ſeem reaſonable, that his being a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt ſhould involve her eſtate, and that her being a Bankrupt ſhould involve his Eſtate, becauſe it is by his permiſſion and privity ſhe drives a diſtinct Trade. <hi>Vide Stones Lecture</hi> 162. who is of opinion that if ſhe abſent her ſelf, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and her husband be <hi>non-ſolvent,</hi> both will be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come Bankrupts, for it was his folly <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſuffer her to be ſole Merchant.</p>
               <p n="9">(9.) A Merchant gives over h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> trading; and ſeven years after becom<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>non-ſolvent,</hi> for money he took up whi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> he was a Merchant, he ſhall be a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt: <hi>Stones Lecture, fol. 7. contra,</hi> f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> Debts contracted ſince he gave ove<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Trading; ſo for Debts due before h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> gave over trading, and continued upo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> new ſecurity taken ſince he gave over h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> trading. <hi>ibid.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="10">(10.) A Graſier that hireth ground<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and buyeth Cattel and feedeth them, and then ſells them again, may be a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, and is within the Statutes of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, ſaith <hi>Stone: contra,</hi> if he graſe his own Free-hold: <hi>Stones Lecture</hi> 165. Yet Quere, of the laſt point, for if h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="91" facs="tcp:101268:46"/> graſe them in his own Free-hold, yet notwithſtanding he ſeeketh his Trade of living by buying and ſelling, though not wholly by buying and ſelling. <hi>Vide Sect<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> 7.</p>
               <p n="11">(11.) A Clothier that ſets poor peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple on work, but himſelf doth only buy the wool, and ſell the Cloth, may be a Bankrupt; <hi>contra,</hi> if he work himſelf, and keepeth Looms and ſervants: ſaith Mr. <hi>Stone</hi> in his <hi>Lecture, fol.</hi> 165. but Quere of the laſt point; why he may not (although he work himſelf) be within the Statutes of Bankrupts, as well as a Shoo-maker who buyeth Leather and makes it up into Shoos, and ſells them: for a Clothier buyeth Wool, and makes it up into Cloth, and ſells it. <hi>Vid. Sect.</hi> 5. A Scrivener may be a Bankrupt, by 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19.</p>
               <p n="12">(12.) Thirdly, a Bankrupt is ſet<note place="margin">Hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>m<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour.</note> forth and deſcribed by his Demeanour, or Carriage; which is, 1. his withdraw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing himſelf: as it is in 34 <hi>H. 8. cap. 4. Whereas divers and ſundry perſons craf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tily obtaining into their hands great ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtance of other mens, do ſuddenly fly into parts unknown, or keep their houſes:</hi> and by 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. he is ſaid to be ſuch an one as ſhall depart the Realm, or begin
<pb n="92" facs="tcp:101268:47"/> to keep his or their Houſe, or Houſes, or otherwiſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="13">(13.) A Merchant or Trader, ab<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſents himſelf for fear of being arreſted, by a Writ <hi>de excommunicato capiendo,</hi> ſo if a Decree in Chancery be made againſt him to make a Conveyance, and he with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>draws himſelf for fear of being attach<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for not performing of the Decree: I<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſeems in neither of theſe caſes doth his withdrawing make him a Bankrupt; <hi>con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tra,</hi> if the ſubſtance of the Decree had been for payment of Money, becauſe in ſuch caſe his withdrawing had been for Pay, to defraud, or delay the payment of his Debt: <hi>Stones Lecture, fol.</hi> 10. If he depart the Realm, and long time af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter his departure becomes <hi>non-ſolvent,</hi> his abſenting himſelf in ſuch caſe brings him within the Statutes of Bankrupts, <hi>ibid.</hi> 133.</p>
               <p n="14">(14.) Secondly, Keeping of their Houſes; withdrawing themſelves, and keeping their houſes, as it is in 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. and 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15. If a Trader upon notice of Proceſs iſſued forth a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt him, keeps his houſe to ſecure himſelf from the arreſt; and after goeth forth again; and then upon like notice keeps his houſe, and then again goeth
<pb n="93" facs="tcp:101268:47"/> forth: this bringeth him not within the Statutes of Bankrupts; becauſe he uſes to go at large, and his Policy will not al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ways prevent the ſerving of Proceſs on him, for he may be met withal unwit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tingly one time or other. <hi>Crook, part 3. fol. 13. pag.</hi> 6. If one that hath no houſe, ſojourns ſometimes at one place, and ſometimes at another; yet if he appears not abroad as formerly, nor can be found as formerly, this is an abſenting himſelf (as is conceived) within the Statute of 13 <hi>El. chap.</hi> 7. where the words are, <hi>or <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>therwiſe abſents himſelf:</hi> the ſame words are in 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
               <p n="15">(15.) Thirdly, taking of Sanctuary, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s it is in 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. and 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>5. There be no Sanctuaries now in <hi>Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land;</hi> therefore all priviledged places where the Kings Officers cannot come, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>re within theſe Statutes, as <hi>Stone</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceives in his <hi>Lecture fol.</hi> 171.</p>
               <p n="16">(16.) Fourthly, Such as ſhall ſuffer themſelves willingly to be arreſted: the words of the Statute of 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>re, <hi>Or ſuffer him or her ſelf willingly to be arreſted for any Debt, or other thing not grown, or due for moneys delivered, wares ſold, or any other juſt or lawful cauſe:</hi> and by 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15. It is, <hi>Or
<pb n="94" facs="tcp:101268:48"/> ſhall willingly ſuffer him, or her ſelf <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> be arreſted for any Debt,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>ut ſupra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> and then adds, <hi>or ſhall willingly, or frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulently procure himſelf or her ſelf to be arreſted, or his or her goods, money, and chattels to be attaqued or ſequeſtred<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> &amp;c.</p>
               <p n="17">(17.) A Merchant, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> hath an im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>propriat Rectory, the Quire is not re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paired, the Tithes are ſequeſtred, it is <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſequeſtration within the ſaid Statute, fo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> this is not his immediate procuring, a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though his default in not repairing th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Church, might be a mean to procure i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>Stones Lecture</hi> 172.</p>
               <p n="18">(18.) Fifthly, by ſuffering himſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> or her ſelf to be outlawed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 13 <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> cap. 7. 1 Jac. cap.</hi> 15. Quere, if the p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty reverſe the outlawry before the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion of Bankrupt ſued forth; whe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther his being out-lawed, be within th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Statute; and I conceive (with ſubmiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion) it is not within the Statute; for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> ſuppoſe the reaſon of this Clauſe may be, becauſe the party by the out-lawry intitleth the King to his goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> that his end in ſo doing may be conjectu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to deceive his Creditors, which can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not be intended when he after reverſeth it: By <hi>Stone</hi> one out-lawed in <hi>Ireland</hi>
                  <pb n="95" facs="tcp:101268:48"/> it is not thereby a Bankrupt here, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe the Record is not pleadable here, <hi>fol.</hi> 172.</p>
               <p n="19">(19.) Sixthly; Yielding himſelf or her ſelf to priſon. 13 <hi>El. cap. 7. 1 Jac. cap.</hi> 15. This I conceive is to be intend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed a voluntary yielding, and not when a man is impriſoned for non-payment of a Fine, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or any refractory carriage; for although the Act which cauſeth the impriſonment be voluntary, yet the im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſonment it ſelf is involuntary; but Quere, whether it be not a detention for Debt, within the following clauſe, men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned hereafter in the next Section: for. I ſuppoſe the Fine, after it is once impo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, becomes a Debt; but yet it may not be within the meaning of the Acts, which were made for the relief of Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, only who had intruſted the party offending, and not for a Fine judicially impoſed for ſome contempt.</p>
               <p n="20">(20.) Seventhly, Or being arreſted for Debt, ſhall after his or her arreſt lie in priſon ſix months or more upon that arreſt; or upon any other arreſt, or deten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in priſon for Debt; and lie in priſon ſix months upon ſuch arreſt or detenti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, <hi>&amp;c. 1 Jac. cap.</hi> 15. and in 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. It is thus; <hi>Or being arreſted
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:101268:49"/> for Debt, ſhall after his or her arreſt l<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> in priſon two months or more, upon tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> or any other arreſt, or detention in priſon for Debt. 21 Jac. cap.</hi> 19. Suppoſe h<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> be arreſted upon a Bond before the day of payment; for by the cuſtom of <hi>Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don</hi> a Creditor may arreſt a Debtor there before the day of payment to find ſure<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, <hi>Cook, lib.</hi> 8. 126. a. <hi>City of London<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> caſe:</hi> and lie in priſon two months <hi>&amp;c.</hi> I conceive this caſe to be within the Statutes, for the Debt ariſeth upon the obligation, and is a Debt preſently upo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> ſealing and delivery of the Deed; and I conceive the action for which he is ar<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>reſted muſt be an action of Debt: al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though the end of that arreſt is not to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>force the payment of the Debt, but t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> find ſureties in caſe the Creditor fea<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> the Debtor to be too weak for his ingage<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment; and in caſe the Debtor upon ſuch arreſt finds not ſureties, his body is to continue in priſon, as a pledge for th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Debt; like Law I conceive in caſe of a ſingle Bill, or a Debt ariſing upon a contract; for it is a Debt preſently and before the day of payment. <hi>Vide Crook part 2. fol. 300. Tynam verſ. Bridges.</hi>
               </p>
               <p n="21">(21.) Eightly, Or being indebted to any perſon or perſons in the ſum of
<pb n="97" facs="tcp:101268:49"/> 100. <hi>lib.</hi> or more, ſhall not pay, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe compound for the ſame within ſix months next after the ſame ſhall grow due, and the Debtor be arreſted for the ſame, or within ſix months after an ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal Writ ſued out to record the ſaid Debt, and notice thereof given unto him, or left in writing at his or their dwelling houſe, or laſt plac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>f abode: 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19.</p>
               <p n="22">(22.) Ninthly, Or being arreſted for the ſum of 100 <hi>lib.</hi> or more of juſt debt or debts, ſhall at any time after ſuch arreſt eſcape out of priſon, or procure his enlargement by common or hired bail. And in the ſaid caſes of arreſt, <note n="†" place="margin">Men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned in 21 <hi>Jac. cap. 19.</hi>
                  </note> or ly<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing in priſon for ſuch Debt or Debts, or getting forth by common or hired bail, he ſhall be judged a Bankrupt from the time of his firſt arreſt. 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19.</p>
               <p n="23">(23.) Tenthly, or ſhall either by himſelf, or others by his procurement, obtain any protection or protections; o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther than ſuch perſon or perſons ſhall be lawfully protected by the priviledg of Parliament, 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19.</p>
               <p n="24">(24.) Eleventhly, or ſhall prefer or exhibit unto his Majeſty, his heirs or Succeſſors, or unto any of the Kings
<pb n="98" facs="tcp:101268:50"/> Courts any Petition or Petitions, Bill o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Bills againſt his or her Creditor or Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, or any of them, thereby deſiring or<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> endeavouring to compel or inforce them, or any of them, to accept of le<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>than their principal and juſt Debts, or t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> procure time, or longer days of payment than was given at the time of their ori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ginal contracts, 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19.</p>
               <p n="25">(25.) Twelfthly, or ſhall make <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> cauſe to be made any fraudulent gra<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> or conveyance of his, her, or their Lands<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Tenements, Goods or Chattels, to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> intent, or whereby his, her, or their Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors being ſubjects born, <note n="*" place="margin">Vid: ſect. 4 Where it ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pears; that ſtrangers are alſo inclu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded.</note> ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap> may be defeated or delayed for the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery of their juſt and true debts; <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> it is in 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
               <p n="26">(26.) In all which caſes before reci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted, the Perſon offending is declared to be a Bankrupt, within the ſaid Statutes: And the end or final cauſe of all ſuch his demeanor, is expreſs'd by 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. to be to defraud the Creditors of their juſt Debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and by 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15. it is thus, To the intent that his, her, or their Creditors, being ſubjects born, ſhall or may be defeated or delayed from the recovery of their juſt and true Debts: <hi>ibid.</hi> And by 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. All the
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:101268:50"/> ſaid Statutes ſhall extend as well to Ali<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ens and Denizens, as to Subjects born.</p>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <head>The puniſhment, and proceedings againſt Bankrupts, by 34 <hi>H. 8. Cap. 4.</hi>
                  </head>
                  <p n="27">(27.) <hi>Nota,</hi> By 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. it is enacted, that all Statutes and Laws formerly made againſt Bankrupts, and for relief of Creditors, ſhall be in all things largely and beneficially conſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for relief of the Creditors.</p>
                  <p n="28">(28.) Firſt, in General, He ſhall be<note place="margin">In Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral.</note> accompted a Bankrupt to all intents and purpoſes; 13 <hi>Eliz. cap. 7. 21 Jac. cap. 19. 1 Jac. cap.</hi> 15. and being a Bankrupt, he is preſently diſabled, as to the diſpoſal of any part of his Eſtate, although it be to ſome of his Creditors; for he is ut<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terly diſcredited by his becoming a Bankrupt, &amp; the Law will not truſt him with the diſtribution of his Goods, <hi>vide Coke, lib. 2. 26. a.</hi> Caſe of Bankrupts.</p>
                  <p n="29">(29.) Secondly, more Particularly,<note place="margin">In parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular.</note> the Bankrupts are to be proceeded a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt by Perſons immediately authori<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed by Act of Parliament, or mediately:<note place="margin">Touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts Perſon.</note> the perſons immediately authorized are ſet forth by 34 <hi>H. 8. cap.</hi> 4. to be the Lord Chancellor or Lord Keeper for
<pb n="100" facs="tcp:101268:51"/> the time being, Lord Preſident, Lord Privy-Seal, o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> other of the Kings moſt Honourable Privy-Counſel, and the Chief Juſtice of either Bench for the time being, or three of them at the leaſt; whereof the Lord Chancellor or Keeper of the Great Seal, Lord Treaſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rer, Lord Preſident, or the Lord Privy-Seal to be one; who upon every com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaint made to them in writing by any parties grieved, ſhall have power and authority by vertue of the ſaid Act, to take by their wiſdom and diſcretion, ſuch orders and directions, as well with the bodies of the ſaid offendors, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſoever they may be had, as well in their houſes as elſe where, by impriſonment of their Bodies, or otherwiſe; as alſo with their Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which they have in Fee-ſimple, Fee-tail, for term of life, term of years, or in the right of their wives; as much as the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt, Right and Title of the ſame of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fenders ſhall extend to, or be, and may then lawfully be departed with by the ſaid offendors; and alſo with their mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys, goods, chattels, wares, merchan<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>diſes and debts, whereſoever they may be found or known, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 34 <hi>H. 8. cap.</hi> 4.</p>
                  <pb n="101" facs="tcp:101268:51"/>
                  <p n="30">(30.) So that the power given by the ſaid Statute, relates either to the perſon or eſtate of the Bankrupt: Firſt, as to his perſon, <hi>viz.</hi> If the offender doth withdraw out of the Kings Dominions, to defraud his Creditors; upon complaint thereof made in writing to the ſaid Lords, having authority as aforeſaid, they ſhall by vertue of the ſaid Act, have power to award Proclamations to be made in ſuch places as to them ſhall be thought meet and convenient; com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manding by the ſame ſuch offendor, in the Kings name, to return with all con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venient ſpeed, into this Realm, and to yield his body before the ſaid Lords, or one of them: And if the ſaid perſon, within three months after he ſhall have notice of ſuch Proclamation; or, ſo ſoon after as he conveniently may, do not repair and yield his body as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; That then the body of all and every ſuch offender and offenders, ſhall be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged, taken, and deemed, to all in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents and purpoſes, out of the Kings pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tection; and his Goods, Chattels, Lands, Tenements, and Debts, ſhall be by the order and diſcretion of the ſaid Lords, employed and diſtributed amongſt the offenders Creditors equally, <hi>&amp;c. 34 H. 8. cap</hi> 4.</p>
                  <pb n="102" facs="tcp:101268:52"/>
                  <p n="31">(31.) Secondly, Touching the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendors<note place="margin">Touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts eſtate.</note> eſtate obſerve (more particular<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly) firſt the power given to the Lords by 34. <hi>H.</hi> 8. for the diſcovering and ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining of it: Secondly, for their diſpo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſal and ordering of it.</p>
                  <p n="32">(32.) Firſt, for the diſcovery and<note place="margin">The diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>covery of it.</note> obtaining of it. The effect of that Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute is, That if, after any ſuch Act or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fence committed, and complaint thereof made to the Lords as aforeſaid, by any party grieved concerning the premiſes, who knowing, or ſuſpecting any of the goods, chattels, wares, merchandizes, or debts of ſuch offendors, to be in the cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody, uſe, or poſſeſſion, of any perſon or perſons; or any perſon or perſons to be indebted to any ſuch offendor or of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendors, do make relation thereof to the ſaid Lords, then they are impowred by the ſaid Statute, to ſend for, and convent before them, ſuch perſon or perſons ſo known or ſuppoſed to have any ſuch goods, wares, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in their cuſtody, or to be indebted to the offendor or offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors; and upon their appearance, to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amine them, and every of them, as well by their Oaths, as otherwiſe, for and up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the ſpecialty, certainty, true decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, and knowledg, of all and ſingu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lar
<pb n="103" facs="tcp:101268:52"/> ſuch goods, wares, debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as be ſuſpected to be in his, or their cuſtody, uſe, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And if the perſon ſo examined, do not plainly diſcloſe the whole truth, of ſuch things whereof he ſhall be exa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined touching the premiſes; then every ſuch perſon or perſons ſo examined, and not declaring the plain and whole truth, upon ſuch proof thereof made, before the ſaid Lords, as they ſhall judge ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficient in that behalf, ſhall loſe and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit double the value of all ſuch goods, wares, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo concealed, to be levied by the ſaid Lords, by ſuch ways and means as they ſhall think fit, the ſame to be diſtributed to the Creditors, in ſuch manner as the Bankrupts Eſtate. 34 <hi>H. 8. cap.</hi> 4.</p>
                  <p n="33">(33.) And that if any perſon or perſons do fraudulently by covin or col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>luſion demand any debt, or other thing by writing or otherwiſe, of ſuch offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dor or offendors, other than ſuch as he, or they can and do prove to be juſtly due before the ſaid Lords, that then e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>very ſuch perſon or perſons, ſo craſtily demanding any ſuch debt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall forfeit the double of what he ſhall ſo claim, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be levied and imployed as aforeſaid.</p>
                  <pb n="104" facs="tcp:101268:53"/>
                  <p n="34">(34.) So, if the Bankrupt (after he ſhall do thoſe acts, whereby he is decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red Bankrupt) ſhall ſuffer fraudulent re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>coveries againſt him of any debts, goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> upon complaint thereof to them made, the Lords are impowred to convent before them the Recoverers; and after ſuch fraud diſcovered the ſaid goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo recovered ſhall be char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geable to the Bankrupts debts, and be diſpoſed of to the Creditors (not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding ſuch Recovery.) 34 <hi>Hen. 8. cap.</hi> 4.</p>
                  <p n="35">(35.) Secondly, Obſerve the pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er<note place="margin">Diſpoſal of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts eſtate.</note> given by that Statute to the Lords, for diſpoſing and ordering of the Bankrupts Eſtate. Firſt, they have power to cauſe the Bankrupts Lands, Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Fees, Offices, Annuities, Goods, and Chattels, Debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be viewed, rented, and appraiſed. Secondly, To make a ſale of the ſaid Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or otherwiſe to order the ſame, for the true ſatisfaction, and payment of the ſaid Creditors, rate and rate like, according to the quantity of their debts. Thirdly, And that every direction, order, bargain, ſale, and other things done by the ſaid Lords as aforeſaid in w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>iting, ſigned with their hands, ſhall be good and ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectual
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:101268:53"/> in the Law, to all intents, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the offenders, their heirs and exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutors for ever, as if done and executed by the offendors themſelves. 34 <hi>Hen. 8. chap.</hi> 4.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>Which Statute of 34 H. 8. although it be now out of uſe; yet in regard I do not find itactually repealed, I ſuppoſe it will not bethought altogether ſuperfluous to be taken notice of.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <head>The proceedings againſt and puniſhment of the Bankrupt, by perſons mediate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly authoriſed by Parliament.</head>
                  <p n="36">(36.) The next things conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, are the proceedings againſt, and pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment of the Bankrupt, by Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners<note place="margin">Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners. Their Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion.</note> or perſons mediately autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rized by Parliament, wherein take notice, Firſt, of their Commiſſion: and therein obſerve, firſt from whom obtained, the Lord Chancellor of <hi>England,</hi> or Lord Keeper of the Great Seal, for the time being, upon every complaint made unto him in writing, againſt any ſuch perſon or perſons being Bankrupt, ſhall have full power and authority by Commiſſion un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der the Great Seal, to name and appoint
<pb n="106" facs="tcp:101268:54"/> ſuch honeſt and diſcreet perſons, as to him ſhall ſeem meet, <hi>&amp;c. 13 Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. Secondly, by whom to be obtained, by the Creditors. Thirdly, when to be ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained, it muſt be within five years after that the party ſhall become a Bankrupt, or elſe it is not to prejudice purchaſers. 21 <hi>Jac. chap,</hi> 19. the words of the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute are, <hi>Provided that no purchaſer for good and valuable conſideration, ſhall be impeached by vertue of this Act, or any other Act againſt Bankrupts, unleſs the Commiſſion, to prove him or her a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, he ſued forth againſt ſuch Bankrupts, within five years after he or ſhe ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come a Bankrupt.</hi> ibid. Family, The duration of the Commiſſion, it is not de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>termined by the Bankrupts death; for b<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15. it is thus enacted, <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided always, and be it enacted, that <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> after any Commiſſion of Bankrupts here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſued forth, and dealt in by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, the offendor happen to die, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Commiſſioners ſhall diſtribute the Goods, Lands, and Debts of the offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors, or any of them,</hi> by force of the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> and this Statute, or either of them, <hi>That then ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vertheleſs the ſaid Commiſſioners ſhall and may in that caſe proceed to execution
<pb n="107" facs="tcp:101268:54"/> in, and upon the ſaid Commiſſion, for, and concerning the offendors goods, lands, te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, hereditaments and debts, in ſuch ſort, as they might have done if the party offendor were living.</hi> 1 Jac. 15.</p>
                  <p n="37">(37.) If ſuch, or ſuch number of the Commiſſioners die, ſo that the reſt cannot proceed<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and thereupon a new Commiſſion be granted to other Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, they may call the ſurviving Commiſſioner or Commiſſioners before them, to give accompt for ſuch part of the Bankrupts eſtate, whereof the old Commiſſioners made no diſtribution, as perſons who have the Eſtate of the Bankrupts in their hands: <hi>Stones Lecture, fol.</hi> 19. and 187.</p>
                  <p n="38">(38.) Secondly, Note the authority given the Commiſſioners, ſo commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nated as aforeſaid, by ſeveral Acts of Parliament: Firſt, as touching the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt himſelf. Secondly, as touching his Eſtate.</p>
                  <p n="39">(39.) Firſt, as to the Bankrupt him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf,<note place="margin">To cauſe the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear.</note> by the Statute of 13 <hi>El. chap.</hi> 7. it is thus ſet forth: <hi>And be it enacted, that if any ſuch perſon or perſons, which is, or ſhall be indebted, do of purpoſe withdraw him or themſelves out of, or from his or their uſual manſion houſe or houſes, that
<pb n="108" facs="tcp:101268:55"/> then upon complaint thereof made to the ſaid Commiſſioners, the ſame Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or the more part of them, ſhall by vertu<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> and authority of this preſ<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>nt A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> have full power and authority to awa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> five Proclamations, to be made in the</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mations.</note> 
                     <hi>Queens Name, upon five ſundry Market<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>days, in ſuch places, near the place when ſuch Bankrupt hath moſt commonly d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>el<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led, or made his abode; commanding hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> or them by the ſaid Proclamations in the Queens name; to return with all conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent ſpeed; and to yield his, or their Body before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or one of them, at ſuch time and place, as by the ſaid Proclamation ſhall be appointed: and if the ſaid Perſon or perſons do not ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to ſuch Proclamation, repair and yield his or their body as aforeſaid, tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> then the body of all and every ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor or offendors ſhall be judged, taken, and deemed to all intents and purpoſes out of the Queens Protection; And that every perſon and perſons, that ſhall willingly or wittingly, receive, d<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, or keep ſecretly any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons ſo demanded by Proclamation, as is aforeſaid, ſhall ſuffer ſuch pain of impri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonment of his, or their bodies, or pay ſuch Fine to our Soveraign Lady the Queens
<pb n="109" facs="tcp:101268:55"/> Majeſty, her heirs, and Succeſſors, as the ſaid Lord Chancellor, or Lord Keeper of the Great Seal, being informed thereof by the Commiſſioners ſo to be appointed, as is afore ſaid, or the more part of them ſhall ſeem meet and convenient, for their ſaid offence or offences.</hi> 13 Eliz. chap. 7.</p>
                  <p n="40">(40.) And by the Statute of 1 <hi>Jac.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Warn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> left in wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting.</note> 
                     <hi>chap.</hi> 15. The ſaid Commiſſioners may call before them, or the greater part of them, the ſaid Bankrupt; and it upon law<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful warning left in writing, at three ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veral times, at the dwelling place or houſe where the ſaid Bankrupt his wife, or family for the moſt part of his abode did lodge, or remain, within one year next before, he, ſhe, or they became Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt; the ſaid Bankrupt ſhall not appear before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, that then and from <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>henceforth it ſhall be lawful for the greater number of the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, to appoint to proclaim the ſaid party a Bankrupt, at ſuch publick place.<note place="margin">Procla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mation.</note> or places where the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or the greater part of them, ſhall <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>hink meet, warning him, her, or them, to appear before them, upon the ſaid Commiſſion at ſome time appointed<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     <pb n="110" facs="tcp:101268:56"/> And that if upon five ſeveral Proclama<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions made in ſome publick place, the party offending, appear not before the ſaid Commiſſioners, and yield his, her<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> or their bodies to them, or ſome of the<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> the ſaid Commiſſioners or greater par<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> of them, ſhall or may award a warrant <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> ſuch fit perſon or perſons as they ſh<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> think meet to apprehend the body a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> bodies of the ſaid offendor and offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors; and to bring him, her, or them<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> offending before the ſaid Commiſſioner<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> whereſoever the ſaid party or parties <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>fending may be ſound in places priv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ledged, or not, to be examined by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <note place="margin">Break<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing open houſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to take the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts.</note> of them, 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="41">(41.) And by 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19. T<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap> of them, in execution of the ſaid Co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>miſſion, or any other perſon or perſo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> by them to be deputed by their warr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> or warrants under their hands or ſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> have power to break open the houſe <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> houſes, Chambers, Shops, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> Bankrupt, where the ſaid Bankrupt, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> his goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be; and to ſeize upo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> and order the perſon, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of ſuch Bar<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rupt, as by former Laws are appointe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>&amp;c. 21 Jac. 19. And by 13 Eliz. ch<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi>
                     <pb n="111" facs="tcp:101268:56"/> 7. The ſaid Commiſſioners have power given them, to take order by their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion with the body of the Bankrupt, whereſoever he or ſhe may be had, ei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther in his or her houſes, Sanctuary, or elſewhere, <hi>&amp;c. Ibid.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="42">(42.) Secondly, Obſerve the power of the Commiſſioners, as to the eſtate of the Bankrupt; and therein take no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice, Firſt, of what eſtate. Secondly, the means for the diſcovery, and obtain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of it. Thirdly, their diſpoſal of it.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <head>Of what Eſtate of the Bankrupts the Commiſſioners may diſpoſe.</head>
                  <p n="43">(43.) Firſt, Of the Bankrupts real<note place="margin">Real Eſtate.</note> Eſtate: Lands, tenements, and heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taments, as well Copy-hold, or Cuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mary-hold, as free-hold, which he or ſhe ſhall have in his or her own right, before he or ſhe became Bankrupt, <hi>&amp;c. 13 El. chap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="44">(44.) It is made by Mr. <hi>Stone</hi> a Quere in his Lecture: That if there be two joyntly, and the one become Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, and dies, whether his part ſhall be ſold, becauſe the ſurvivor is not in by him. But it ſeems to me, that the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts part ſhall be ſold, and that there
<pb n="112" facs="tcp:101268:57"/> ſhall be no ſurvivor in this caſe. Firſt, becauſe the Bankrupts moiety is bound by the Statutes, by his becoming a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt. Secondly, the Bankrupt had pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er to ſell the ſame in his life time, and might depart with it, and ſo within the words of 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. the words are [<hi>ſuch uſe, intereſt, right or title, as ſuch offendor or offendors that ſhall have in the ſame, which he or ſhe may lawfully depart withal.] vide</hi> after <hi>Sect.</hi> 46. Third<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, by 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15. The Commiſſioners after the Bankrupts death, may proceed in execution, in and upon the Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, for and concerning the offendors Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in ſuch ſort as if the offendor had been living; which they cannot do in the caſe before, if the ſurvivorſhip take place.</p>
                  <p n="45">(45.) It was agreed by the Juſtices<note place="margin">Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold.</note> that Copy-holds are within the intent and purliew of all the Statutes concern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Bankrupts, and may be ſold by the Commiſſioners; ſome doubt whereof was made, becauſe they are named in one clauſe of 13 <hi>El.</hi> and not in 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15. or 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19. for the ſame being in the firſt Statute, and the other Statutes being made in further con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>firmation and approbation thereof, they
<pb n="113" facs="tcp:101268:57"/> ought to be expounded liberally and ſhall be conſtrued accordingly, to make as ſtrong proviſion, as they may againſt the Bankrupt, <hi>Crook, 3. part 550. Criſp againſt Prat.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="46">(46.) And all ſuch Lands, tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments,<note place="margin">2. Lands purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed joyntly with the wife.</note> hereditaments, as ſuch perſon, [<hi>viz.</hi> the Bankrupt] ſhall have purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, or obtained for money or other re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compence joyntly with his wife, chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren, or child, to the only uſe of ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor or offendors, or ſuch uſe, intereſt, right, or title, as ſuch offendor, or offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors then ſhall have in the ſame, which he or ſhe may lawfully depart withal, 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="47">(47.) A man purchaſeth Lands to him, and his wife, and his ſon, and two years after he becomes a Trader; and four years after he becomes a Bankrupt, theſe Lands ſhall not be ſold by the Commiſſioners of Bankrupt, and are out of the meaning of the Statute, for elſe none might know with whom to deal by way of marriage or otherwiſe, when a perſon who is not a Tradeſman, ſettles Lands upon his wife and children, <hi>bona<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fide,</hi> and after becoming a Tradeſman, and then a Bankrupt, the ſaid Acts of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament ſhall overthrow a Conveyance
<pb n="114" facs="tcp:101268:58"/> ſo duly ſetled. <hi>Crook, 3 part. fol. 550. Criſp verſus Prat.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="48">(48.) Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which<note place="margin">3. Lands in truſt.</note> any perſon or perſons hath in truſt to any ſecret uſe of any ſuch offendor or offen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dors, <hi>&amp;c. 13 Eliz. chap.</hi> 7. Lord and Tenant are; the Tenant makes a Feoff<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment to deceive the Lord of the Ward<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, and then becomes a Bankrupt, theſe Lands ſhall be ſold by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, for although the conveyance was only fraudulent as againſt the Lord, yet there was a truſt between the Feof<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>for and Feoffee, <hi>Stones Lecture, fol.</hi> 185.</p>
                  <p n="49">(49.) Manors, Lands, Tenements,<note place="margin" type="runSum">4.</note> 
                     <hi>&amp;c.</hi> conveyed or procured, or cauſed to be conveyed by the Bankrupt to any of his children, or other perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, except the ſame ſhall be purchaſed or conveyed for, or upon marriage of any of his or her children, both the parties married being of the years of conſent, or ſome valuable conſideration. 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="50">(50.) A Tradeſman in conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of marriage, makes a conveyance of Lands, to the uſe of himſelf and his wife, and held to be within the Statute of 1 <hi>Jac. vide Stiles reports, fol. 288. Tucker verſ. Coſh.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <pb n="115" facs="tcp:101268:58"/>
                  <p n="51">(51.) Alſo the ſaid Commiſſioners<note place="margin">5. Lands convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed upon conditi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</note> have power to ſell Lands and Tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments conveyed, upon condition; by 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. where it is thus, <hi>If any perſon that now is, or hereafter ſhall be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>come a Bankrupt, have heretofore granted, conveyed, or aſſured, or ſhall at any time hereafter grant, convey, or aſſure any Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, goods, Chattels, or other Eſtate, unto any perſon or perſons, upon condition or power of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demption at a day to come, by payment of money or otherwiſe, that it ſhall and may be lawful to and for the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or the greater part of them, before the time of the performance of ſuch con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition, to aſſign and appoint under their hands and ſeals, ſuch perſon or perſons as they ſhall think fit to make tender or pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of money, or other performance, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the nature of ſuch condition, as fully as the Bankrupt might have done; And that the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, ſhall after ſuch ten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der, payment, or performance, have full power to ſell, and diſpoſe of ſuch Lands,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>ſo conveyed upon condition, for the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of the Creditors, as fully as they may ſell or diſpoſe of any the eſtate of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt.</hi> 21 Jac. Chap. 19.</p>
                  <pb n="116" facs="tcp:101268:59"/>
                  <p n="52">(52.) <hi>Quere,</hi> whether the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners may not by the equity of this Stat. appoint one to enter, for a condi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion broken; As if a trader makes a Feoffment, upon condition to be per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>formed on the part of the Feoffee; the Feoffee breaks the Condition, and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore entry, the Feoffor becomes a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt: It ſhould ſeem, the Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners may take advantage hereof; for the Statutes ſhall be liberally expounded for relief of the Creditors: if not, yet it ſeems to be comprehended within the words of 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. whereby power is given to the Commiſſioners, to take order and direction with the Bankrupts Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for ſuch uſe, intereſt, right or title, as ſuch offendor or offendors ſhall have in the ſame, which word (Ti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tle) includes, as I conceive, an entry for a condition broken: yet <hi>Stone</hi> makes a <hi>quaere</hi> of it in his Lecture, <hi>fo.</hi> 12.</p>
                  <p n="53">(53.) Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tailed:<note place="margin">Lands intailed.</note> The Commiſſioners, or the greater number of them, ſhall have power by deed indented and inrolled within ſix months, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to grant, bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, ſell and convey any Manors, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, whereof the Bankrupt is, or ſhall be in any wiſe
<pb n="117" facs="tcp:101268:59"/> ſeized in Tail, in poſſeſſion, reverſion or remainder (and whereof no reverſion or remainder is or ſhall be in the Kings Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty, his Heirs or Succeſſors, of the gift or proviſion of his Majeſty, his Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>genitors, Heirs or Succeſſors:) to any perſon or perſons, for the relief and be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of the Creditors, of all ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts: And that all and every ſuch grants, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be good and available in Law againſt the Bankrupt, his Iſſue, and all claiming by, from, or under him, ſince the time that he became Bankrupt: and alſo againſt all other perſons, whom the Bankrupt by common Recovery, or other ways or means might cut off or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bar from any Remainder, Reverſion, Rent, Profit, Title, or poſſiblity into, or out of any of the ſaid Manors, Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <p n="54">(54.) Alſo Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Lands deſcend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</note> purchaſed by, or deſcended or come to the Bankrupt before his debts payed or agreed for, as appears by 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. where it is thus; That if any perſon or perſons, which is, or ſhall be publiſhed and declared to be a Bankrupt, by vertue of this Act, ſhall at any time hereafter, purchaſe any Lands, Tenements, Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments,
<pb n="118" facs="tcp:101268:60"/> Free or Copy; or Offices, Fees, Goods or Chattels; or that any Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Free or Copy, Offices, Fees, Goods or Chattels, ſhall deſcend, revert, or by any means come to any ſuch perſon or perſons being Bankrupts, as is aforeſaid: before ſuch time as their debts due to their Creditors ſhall fully be ſatisfied, and payed, or otherwiſe agreed for: That then the ſaid Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be ſold by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them, for and towards the payment of the Creditors, in ſuch manner, as other Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupts, which they had when they were firſt declared to be Bankrupts, ſhould or might have been, <hi>&amp;c. 13 El. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="55">(55.) If after the commiſſion award<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and diſtribution made of all the Bankrupts Eſtate, towards the ſatisfaction of the Creditors; every Creditor ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving an equal part: Lands, Goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> deſcend or come to the Bankrupt; Mr. <hi>Stone</hi> makes a <hi>quere (fo.</hi> 17.) whether in ſuch caſe, they ſhall be ſubject alſo to a new ſale or diſtribution: And it ſeems that they ſhall, for the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners power is not fully executed until the Creditors be ſatisfied.</p>
                  <pb n="119" facs="tcp:101268:60"/>
                  <p n="56">(56.) The Commiſſioners have alſo<note place="margin">Lands exte<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>d<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</note> power to ſell Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupts extended, by ſuch as pretend to be accomptants to the King; by 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. It is thus; <hi>If i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> ſhall happen any Lands, Tenements,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Goods, Chattels, Debts, or other Eſtate of any Bankrupt to be extended, after ſuch time as he or ſhe is become a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, by any perſon or perſons, under colour or pretence of his or their being ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comptant, or any ways indebted unto our Soveraign Lord the King's Majeſty, his Heirs or Succeſſors: That then, it ſhall and may be lawful, to and for the ſaid Commiſſioners, to examine upon Oath, whether the ſaid debt were due to ſuch debtor or accomptant, upon any bargain or contract originally made between ſuch accomptant, and the ſaid Bankrupt,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>and his or their Servants: And if the ſaid Bargain or Contract was originally made, to and with any other perſon or perſons, than the ſaid Debtor or Accomp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tant, or for the uſe or truſt of anyother perſon or perſons: Then it ſhall and may be lawful, to and for the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or the greater part of them, to order and diſpoſe of all ſuch Lands,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>to and for the uſe of the Creditors, which ſhall
<pb n="120" facs="tcp:101268:61"/> ſeek relief by the ſaid Commiſſion: And that the order and diſpoſition of the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, ſhall be good and available againſt the ſaid extent; And that ſuch perſon and per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, to whom the ſaid Lands,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>ſhall be bargained, ſold,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>by the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners as aforeſaid, or the greater part of them, ſhall have good remedy to have, demand, and recover the ſame, againſt ſuch perſon or perſons that ſhall detain the ſame,</hi> &amp;c. 21 Jac. cap 19.</p>
                  <p n="57">(57.) The Commiſſioners cannot<note place="margin">Lands convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>bonafide.</hi>
                     </note> ſell any Lands; Tenements, Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, conveyed by any ſuch Bankrupt (<hi>bonafide</hi>) before he became Bankrupt: At the later end of 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. there is ſuch a Proviſo, <hi>viz.</hi> Provided always, that this Act ſhall not extend to any Lands, Tenements or Hereditaments, free or copy-hold, which heretofore hath been aſſured by any ſuch Bankrupt; or hereafter ſhall be aſſured by any Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, before he became Bankrupt; ſo that always ſuch aſſurance be made, <hi>bonafide,</hi> and not to the uſe of the Bankrupt him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf only, or his Heirs: And that the parties to whoſe uſe ſuch aſſurance hath or ſhall be made, be not at or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the making of ſuch aſſurance, privy,
<pb n="121" facs="tcp:101268:61"/> or conſenting to the fraudulent purpoſe of any ſuch Bankrupt, to deceive his Creditors, 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="58">(58.) It was reſolved (<hi>Cook lib. 2. 26. a.</hi> caſe of Bankrupts) by the Court, That the Proviſo concerning gifts and grants (<hi>bona fide</hi>) doth not make any gift or grant good, which the Bankrupt made, after that he became Bankrupt, but to exclude him out of the penalty of the Act: I ſuppoſe this reſolution ſhould be applied to that part of 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. which impoſeth the penalty or forfeiture of double the value, for detaining or poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſing fraudulently by covin or colluſion any debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupts, other than ſuch as are due, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and the ſame to proceed <hi>bona fide,</hi> without fraud or covin, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> although in <hi>Poulton,</hi> the ſaid Book and reſolution be quoted in the Margine oppoſite to the Proviſo; before ſet down in Sect. 57.</p>
                  <p n="59">(59.) Alſo the Chattels and Goods<note place="margin">Perſonal Eſtate.</note> of the Bankrupts are ſaleable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by the Commiſſioners, 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7.<note place="margin">I. Chattels Real.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p>Chattels real, as Leaſes for years. A Leaſe for years is made, Provided that the Leſſee ſhall not alien; the Leſſee be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes a Bankrupt; It is a <hi>Quaere</hi> in Mr. <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture. <hi>fo.</hi> 15. whether the ſale
<pb n="122" facs="tcp:101268:62"/> of the Commiſſioners to be a forfeiture? To which it may be anſwered in the ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gative, that it is not, becauſe this intereſt is tranſmitted by Act of Parliament, to which every man is intended party, and not by ſale of the Leſſee.</p>
                  <p n="60">(60.) Offices are likewiſe mentioned<note place="margin">Offices.</note> in 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. and made ſaleable by the Commiſſioners; which by <hi>Stone</hi> in his lecture <hi>fo.</hi> 13. is intended to be Offices of Inheritance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as the War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den of the Fleet, and ſuch like, and not Offices of Truſt, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And by 3 <hi>H. 7. cap.</hi> 12. any Offices which concern the adminiſtration of Juſtice or Clerkſhip in any Court of Record, or which con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cern the Kings Treaſure, Revenue, Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtoms, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> cannot be bargained or ſold for Money, but ſuch bargain and ſale is void; and both buyer and ſeller made in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>capable, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Therefore doubtleſs, ſuch offices cannot be aſſigned by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, in ſatisfaction of a Debt of the Bankrupts, nor are comprehended within the ſaid Statute, there being other Offices that may be ſold, and ſo the words of the Statute ſatisfied; and Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fices of Truſt are individually annexed to the perſon; <hi>vid. Coke lib. 9. 48. a.</hi> The Earl of <hi>Sbrewsburies</hi> caſe.</p>
                  <pb n="123" facs="tcp:101268:62"/>
                  <p n="61">(61.) Secondly, The Bankrupts per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſonal<note place="margin">2. Chattels perſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal.</note> Eſtate, Goods or Chattels of the Bankrupt, whereſoever to be found; by 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. are made ſaleable by the Commiſſioners: They may ſell a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts goods in <hi>Ireland, Stone</hi> in his Lecture <hi>fo. 90. A.</hi> hath an advowſon, the Church becomes void, and then <hi>A.</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes a Bankrupt: It is made a <hi>Quere</hi> by Mr. <hi>Stone</hi> in his Lecture, whether the Commiſſioners may ſell it; and I ſup<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe it may be anſwered negatively, that they cannot ſell it; for it is a thing in Action, and ſo not ſaleable by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Law; and no particular power is given by any of the Acts for ſale of it, as there is for ſale of Debts due to the Bankrupt, as hereafter appeareth: And without doubt, if the Commiſſioners pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent any one for money, it is Simo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny.</p>
                  <p n="62">(62.) Leaſes, Goods, Chattels, or Debts of the Bankrupt, by him convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed or procured to be conveyed or tranſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred to any of his Children, or other perſon or perſons, except the ſame ſhall be purchaſed, conveyed, or transferred, for or upon marriage of any of his or her children, both the parties married being
<pb n="124" facs="tcp:101268:63"/> of years of conſent, or ſome valuable Conſideration, 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="63">(63.) Any Goods or Chattels that ſhall by any means come unto the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, before ſuch time as his Debts ſhall be ſatisfied or agreed for; as well as other Chattels which the Bankrupt had, when firſt declared to be a Bankrupt, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="64">(64.) Goods and Chattels extended of the Bankrupts, by pretended accomp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tants or debtors to the King; <hi>vide devant,</hi> Sect. 56.</p>
                  <p n="65">(65.) Goods and Chattels of the<note place="margin">Goods extend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</note> Bankrupt extended, or taken in execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion. Goods of the Bankrupts were ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended by vertue of a Statute; and the extent was before he became Bankrupt, but the <hi>Liberate</hi> after; and held that they could not be ſold by the Commiſſioners of Bankrupts; becauſe being extended they are in <hi>Cuſtodia Legis,</hi> ſo that the cognizors have no power to give, ſell, or otherwiſe diſpoſe of them: And although the Cognizee hath no abſolute property in them by the extent, and before the <hi>Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berate,</hi> becauſe at the return of the <hi>Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berate,</hi>
                     <pb n="125" facs="tcp:101268:63"/> he may refuſe them, if he will: yet that is for the advantage of the Cog<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nizee, and the Cognizor hath no proper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty in them, but only in caſe where the Cognizee refuſeth them; for the goods are bound by the <hi>Teſte</hi> of the Writ of extent or execution ſued: and when the <hi>liberate</hi> is ſued, it hath relation to the extent; and they are but as one ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent: <hi>Crook, part 3. 149, 150. Audley verſus Halſey.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="66">(66.) Goods and Chattels, whereof<note place="margin">Goods poſſeſt by the Bank<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rupt.</note> the Bankrupt hath the poſſeſſion and diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſal as his own: The words of the Statute are, <hi>Whereas many perſons before they become Bankrupt do convey their goods unto other men, upon good conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and yet keep the ſame, and are repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted owners thereof, and do diſpoſe of the ſame, as their own, Be it enacted, that if any perſon or perſons ſhall become a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, and at ſuch time as they ſhall ſo become a Bankrupt, ſhall by the conſent and permiſſion of the true owners or Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prietors, have in their poſſeſſion, order, and diſpoſition, any of the goods or chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, whereof they ſhall be reputed owners, and take upon them the ſale, alteration, and diſpoſition of them as owners, the
<pb n="126" facs="tcp:101268:64"/> Commiſſioners, or greater number may ſell, and diſpoſe of the ſame, for the benefit of the Creditors.</hi> 21 Jac. 19.</p>
                  <p n="67">(67.) Goods or Chattels paſſed a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>way upon condition, or power of re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>demption by the Bankrupt, 21 <hi>Jac. 19. vide,</hi> before <hi>Sect.</hi> 51.</p>
                  <p n="68">(68.) Debts due to the Bankrupt<note place="margin">Debts.</note> are ſaleable, by 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7. expreſly; and although they are transferred into other mens names, by 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="69">(69.) In an action upon the Caſe brought for words ſpoken by the Defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant againſt the Plaintiff, the Plaintiff recovered of the Defendant for Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mages and Coſts, twelve pounds: And after the execution ſued, and money le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vied by the Sheriff (before the return of the Writ) the Plaintiff becomes a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, and the ſaid twelve pounds is aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned by the Commiſſioners to the cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, and the money being brought in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to Court, the Plaintiff [now a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt] moves for it; and the Creditors to whom the ſame was aſſigned, likewiſe moved for it; and by <hi>Jones</hi> and <hi>Hide</hi> Juſtices, the aſſignment was good, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe it was the Bankrupts Debt, and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitable
<pb n="127" facs="tcp:101268:64"/> by out-lawry: but <hi>Whitlock</hi> and <hi>Crook</hi> Juſtices <hi>contra;</hi> becauſe the Sheriff levying of the money before the party became a Bankrupt, it was in <hi>Cuſtodi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> legis,</hi> and the Creditors cannot give a diſcharge, nor are they parties in Court, and if the Judgment ſhould be reverſed, not compellable to make reſtitution: and afterwards it was judged accordingly; and that the money be delivered to the plain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiff, he acknowledging ſatisfaction: alſo it was ſaid, that the money was not the Plaintiffs until payed out of Court. <hi>Crook, part. 3. 166, 167. Benſon verſ. Flower and Backwel.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="69">(69.) <hi>A.</hi> hath one in execution for Debt, and then he becomes a Bankrupt, the Commiſſioners aſſign the Debt, if the party eſcape, whether may this Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignee have an action of eſcape: this is a Quere in Mr. <hi>Stones Lecture,</hi> fol. 9. And I conceive may be anſwered in the affirmative; for by <hi>Weſtminſter 2. chap.</hi> 
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>1. Debt is given in ſuch caſe againſt the Jaylor by the equity of that Statute, [for the words extend only to Accomp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ants.] And by 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15. It is thus: <hi>That the Commiſſioners of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt,
<pb n="128" facs="tcp:101268:65"/> or the greater part of them ſhall have power to grant and aſſign, or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wiſe to order and diſpoſe all or any of the Debt due; or to be due, to and for the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of the ſaid Bankrupt, by what perſon or perſons ſoever, or in what manner or form ſoever, to the uſe of the Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, according to the true intent of the former Statute of Bankrupts: And that the ſame grant, aſſignment, or diſpoſition of the ſaid Debts, in form a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foreſaid, to be made by the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, or any part of them, ſhall ſo veſt the property, right, and intereſt of the ſaid Debt and Debts, in the perſon or perſons of him, her, or them, to whom it ſhall be granted,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>by the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, as fully to all intents and pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſes, as if the ſaid Bill, Bond,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>Judgment, or Contract, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the ſaid Debt, or Debts ſhall ariſe or grow, had been with the perſon or perſons to whom the ſame ſhall be granted,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>And that after ſuch grant, aſſignment, or diſpoſition: neither the Bankrupts, nor any other ſhall have power to receive, recover, or releaſe it, &amp;c.</hi> 1 Jac. 15. So that by the aſſignment, the Debt is veſt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to all intents and purpoſes in the Grantee, as if he had been the origina<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <pb n="129" facs="tcp:101268:65"/> Debtor, might have had his action againſt the Sheriff, therefore the Gran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tee: and the Statute ſhall be liberally expounded for the relief of Creditors, eſpecially, ſeeing in this caſe the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignee or Grantee, is without any reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy for the Debt, if he cannot relieve himſelf againſt the Sheriff.</p>
                  <p n="70">(70.) And Mr. <hi>Stone</hi> in his <hi>Le<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cture</hi> makes another Quere, whether he that comes in as Creditor, and hath a debt made over unto him by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> may not be barred not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding by the Statute of limita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions. And it may be anſwered that he ſhall be barred, for neither of the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes gives the Aſſignee any larger pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> than the original debtor had: alſo the Statute of limitation, was made for quieting of mens eſtates, and avoid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Suits, which Statute, ſhall not be taken away without ſpecial words.</p>
                  <p n="71">(71.) Such things as the Bankrupt<note place="margin">Thin diſpoſed of by the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt.</note> himſelf diſpoſed to the ſatisfaction of ſome of the Creditors, after that he be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came a Bankrupt, for the Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 7. is, <hi>That the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners muſt diſtribute to the Creditors ſhare and ſhare alike,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>and that eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſuch bargain, ſale,</hi> &amp;c. <hi>ſhall be good
<pb n="130" facs="tcp:101268:66"/> and effectual againſt the offendors and all perſons,</hi> &amp;c. And if the debtor after that he becomes a Bankrupt, may prefer one Creditor before another, it would be unreaſonable, and a great defect in Law, that after he hath utterly diſcredited himſelf by becoming a Bankrupt, the Law ſhould intruſt him with the di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtribution of his Goods. <hi>Cook, lib. 2. 25. b. 26. a. Caſe of Bankrupts.</hi>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <head>Now obſerve the means of diſcovery, and obtaining of the Bankrupts Eſtate.</head>
                  <p n="72">(72.) It is enacted by 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19. that the Commiſſioners, in execution<note place="margin">Break open Houſes.</note> of their Commiſſion, or the greater part of them, or any other perſon or perſons, officer, or officers by them or the greater part of them to be deputed, or appoint<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed by their warrant or warrants under their hands and ſeals, may break open the houſe or houſes, chambers, ſhops, ware-houſes, doors, trunks, or cheſts of the Bankrupt, where the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, or any of his goods, or eſtate ſhall be, or reputed to be, and ſeize upon and order the Body, goods, chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, ready money, and other eſtate of ſuch Bankrupt, as by former Laws are limited and appointed, <hi>&amp;c. 21 Jac. cap.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <pb n="131" facs="tcp:101268:66"/>
                  <p n="73">(73.) Next by examination and pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment<note place="margin">Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers.</note> of perſons: 1. The Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt himſelf, they may compel him to come before them: <hi>vide</hi> before <hi>Sect.</hi> 39.) They have power to examine him upon oath, upon ſuch interrogatories touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing his Lands, Tenements, goods, chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, debts, bills, bonds, books of ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compt, and ſuch other things as may tend to diſcloſe his or their eſtate, or the ſecret grants, conveyances, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>loyning of his, her, or their Lands, Tenements, goods, money and debts, as they ſhall think fit, 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="74">(74.) Then obſerve the Bankrupts puniſhment in caſe of his refractorineſs or deceit: firſt, for his not appearance before the Commiſſioners, <hi>vide</hi> before <hi>Sect.</hi> 39.) Secondly, in caſe he refuſe to be examined, or anſwer not fully to every interrogatory to him to be admi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſtred by the ſaid Commiſſioners or the greater part of them, it ſhall be lawful for the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, to commit the ſaid offendor or offendors to ſome ſtreight or cloſe impriſonment, there to remain, until he, ſhe or they ſhall better conform him, or her ſelf: 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <pb n="132" facs="tcp:101268:67"/>
                  <p n="75">(75.) Thirdly, For his perjury: <hi>If</hi>
                     <note place="margin">Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts perjury.</note> 
                     <hi>upon his, her, or their examination, it ſhall appear that he or ſhe, or they have committed any wilful or corrupt perjury<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> tending to the hurt or damage of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, to the value of</hi> 10 lib. <hi>of lawful money of</hi> Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gland, <hi>or above; the party ſo offending ſhall or may be thereof indicted, in any of the Kings Majeſties Courts of Record, and being lawfully convicted thereof, ſhall ſtand upon the Pillory in ſome publick place, by the ſpace of two hours, and have one of his Ears, nailed to the Pillory and cut off:</hi> 1 Jac. cap. 15.</p>
                  <p n="76">(76.) Fourthly, For the Bankrupts<note place="margin">His fraud.</note> fraud: <hi>And if any Bankrupt ſhall upon his or her examination to be taken before the ſaid Commiſſioners</hi> (executing the ſaid Commiſsion) <hi>be found fraudulently or deceitfully to have conveyed away his or her goods, chattels, lands, tenements, offices, &amp;c. or other eſtate, or any part thereof to the value of</hi> 20 lib. <hi>or above; to the end and purpoſe to hinder the exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cution of this Statute, or of any other the aforeſaid Statutes, or thereby to defraud, or delay, or hinder his or her Creditors of the ſame; and ſhall not upon his or her examination, diſcover unto the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners,
<pb n="133" facs="tcp:101268:67"/> and (if it lie in his or her power) deliver unto the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, all that eſtate, goods, and chattels, ſo fraudulently and deceitfully conveyed away as aforeſaid, or by him, or her, his or her means kept or detained from the ſaid Commiſſioners: or that cannot make it appear unto the ſaid Commiſſioners, that he or ſhe hath ſuſtained ſome caſual loſs, whereby he or ſhe is diſabled to pay what he, or ſhe then owed; the offendor ſhall or may be indicted for ſuch fraud, or abuſe at the Aſſizes, or general Seſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſions, to be holden, before the Judges of Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſize, or Juſtices of Peace, of the County or place, where he, or ſhe ſhall become Bankrupt: and if upon ſuch Indictment, or Indictments, the Bankrupts be thereof convicted, he, or ſhe ſo convicted, ſhall be ſet in the Pillory in ſome publick place, for the ſpace of two hours, and have one of his, or her ears nayled to the Pillory, and cut off.</hi> 21 Jac. cap. 19.</p>
                  <p n="77">(77.) Secondly, By examination of<note place="margin">Wife of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt.</note> the Bankrupts wife: After ſuch time as any perſon ſhall by the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, executing the ſaid Commiſſion, or the greater part of them, be lawfully ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>judged, or declared to be a Bankrupt, the ſaid Commiſſioners, executing ſuch
<pb n="134" facs="tcp:101268:68"/> Commiſſion, ſhall have power and au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority upon oath to examine the wife and wives of all and every ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, for the finding out and diſcovery of the eſtate and eſtates, goods, and chattels of ſuch Bankrupt or Bankrupts, concealed, kept, or diſpoſed of by ſuch wife or wives, in their own perſons, or by their own act or means, or by any other perſon or perſons: And that ſhe, and they, the ſaid wife and wives ſhall incur ſuch danger and penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, for not coming before the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or for refuſing to be ſworn, or examined; or for not diſcloſing of the truth, upon her, or their examination or examinations, as in and by the former Laws, or either of them, is already made and provided againſt any other perſon or perſons in like caſes: 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <p n="78">(78.) Thirdly, By examination of<note place="margin">Other perſons.</note> other perſons. Any perſon known or ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected to have any of the Bankrupts eſtate, debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Wherein note<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Firſt, the power of the Commiſſioners to bring them before them; the Commiſſioners upon complaint made to them by any party grieved, knowing, ſuppoſing, or ſuſpecting any of the goods, chattels,
<pb n="135" facs="tcp:101268:68"/> wares, Merchandizes, or debts of ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor or offendors, to be in cuſtody, uſe, occupying, keeping, or poſſeſſion of any perſon or perſons; or any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to be indebted to any ſuch offendor or offendors, and do make relation there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to the ſaid Commiſſioners ſo to be ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed, or the more part of them, That then the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them ſhall have full power and authority to ſend for, and call before them, by ſuch proceſs, ways, and means, as they ſhall think convenient, all and every ſuch perſon or perſons, ſo known, or ſuſpected to have any ſuch goods, chattels, wares, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> in his or their cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtody, uſe, occupation, keeping, or poſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeſſion, or ſuppoſed, or ſuſpected to be indebted to ſuch offendor or offendors: And ſecondly, to examine them: upon their appearance, the Commiſſioners may examine them, and every of them, as well by their oaths, as otherwiſe by ſuch means as the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them ſhall think fit, for and upon the ſpecialty, certainty, and true declaration and knowledge of all and ſingular ſuch goods, chattels, wares, merchandizes and debts, of any ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor or offendors, as be ſuppoſed, or
<pb n="136" facs="tcp:101268:69"/> ſuſpected to be owing to any ſuch of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendor or offendors, 13 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="79">(79.) And in the next and third<note place="margin">Refuſing to come before the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers.</note> place, take notice of the puniſhment of ſuch other perſons; firſt, for their refu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſing to come before the Commiſſioners, or to be ſworn and make anſwer. And by the Statute of 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15. It is ſet forth, that no good means was ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed by 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> either by impriſon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, or other penalty, to procure per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to be ſuſpected to have any part of the money, goods, chattels, or debts of the ſaid offendors, or to be indebted to them, to come before the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, or to be examined by them, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and then enacts, That if any perſon, or perſons being known, ſuppoſed, or ſuſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pected, to have or detain any part of the lands, tenements, or hereditaments, goods, chattels, or debts of the ſaid Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, or to be indebted to, or for the be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nefit of the ſaid Bankrupt, ſhall after lawful warning to the ſaid perſon or perſons given, to come before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, to be examined, refuſe to come, or ſhall not come before the ſaid Commiſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners at the time appointed, having no
<pb n="137" facs="tcp:101268:69"/> lawful impediment (ſuch as ſhall be al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed by the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them;) or that any ſuch perſon or perſons, having knowledge or warning of any other aſſembly, or meet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the ſaid Commiſſioners ſhall not come and appear before them, at ſuch time, as he or ſhe may lawfully come, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving no ſuch lawful impediment, as ſhall be then made known to the ſaid Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, and by them admitted, and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lowed<note place="margin">Refuſing to be ſworn, and an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſwer.</note> as aforeſaid. Or being come be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore them, ſhall refuſe to be ſworn, and to make anſwer to ſuch interrogatories as ſhall be miniſtred to him or them, according to the true intent and mean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of the ſaid Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> or of this Act: That then it ſhall be lawful for the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, to commit to ſuch ward or priſons, as to them, or the greater part of them, ſhall be thought meet, all ſuch<note place="margin">Their puniſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</note> perſon and perſons, as ſo refuſe to be ſworn, and make anſwer to ſuch Inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rogatories, as ſhall be ſo adminiſtred as aforeſaid: 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="80">(80.) And alſo to direct their war<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rants to ſuch perſon or perſons, as to them, or the greater part of them ſhall
<pb n="138" facs="tcp:101268:70"/> be thought meet, to apprehend and ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt ſuch perſon and perſons as ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to appear before them as aforeſaid, and to bring him, her, or them, before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, to be examined as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid; and upon their refuſal, to commit them to ſuch Priſons as the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners ſhall think meet, there to remain without Bail or Mainpriſe, until their ſubmiſſion to the Commiſſioners to be examined, <hi>&amp;c. 2 Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="81">(81.) But by 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. in caſe any ſuch perſon or perſons, upon exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation, do not diſcover the truth touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſaid things whereof they are ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amined by the Commiſſioners as afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid, or do deny to ſwear, he is to forfeit double the value of the thing concealed, (<hi>vid. apres,</hi> forfeiture,) which doubt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs is not taken away by 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15. but the impriſonment is thereby added as a further penalty; and to force the parties ſuſpected to have any of the Bankrupts Eſtate, to come before the Commiſſioners and make a diſcovery: Alſo it may be obſerved, that the Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> mentioneth only the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cealing of the perſonal Eſtate, but 1 <hi>Jac.
<pb n="139" facs="tcp:101268:70"/> cap.</hi> 15. Extends to Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as before, that are ſo with-held or conceal'd.</p>
                  <p n="82">(82.) Thirdly, For their Perjury.<note place="margin">Their Perjury: 1 <hi>Jac.</hi> cap. 15.</note> If any perſon or perſons, other than the Bankrupt, either by ſubornation, unlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful procurement, ſiniſter perſwaſion or means of any others, or by his own act, conſent or agreement; ſhall wilfully and corruptly commit any manner of wilful Perjury, by his depoſition to be taken before the ſaid Commiſſioners, or the greater part of them, as aforeſaid; That then the party or parties ſo offending; and all and every perſon and perſons, that ſhall unlawfully and corruptly pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cure any ſuch unlawful, wilful, and cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt Perjury, ſhall or may therefore be indicted in any of the Kings Majeſties Courts of Record; and after his or their conviction thereof, ſhall inour ſuch for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feiture, and receive and ſuffer ſuch pains and puniſhment as are limited by the Statute made concerning Perjury, (<hi>viz. 5 El. cap.</hi> 9.) Now the puniſhment ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed for Perjury by that Statute is, That the perſon committing Perjury ſhall forfeit 20 <hi>l.</hi> and endure half a years impriſonment without Bail or Mainpriſe,
<pb n="140" facs="tcp:101268:71"/> and his Oath never after to be received, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> And if he hath no Goods or Lands of that value; then he is to be ſet in the Pillory, in ſome Market-Town, and to have both his ears nailed, and to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled to be a Witneſs in any Court of Record, <hi>vid. 5 Eliz. cap.</hi> 9. and by the ſame Stat. of 5 <hi>Eliz.</hi> the Procurers of Perjury are to forfeit 40 <hi>l.</hi> and if they have no Eſtate of that value, then to ſuf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fer half a years impriſonment, without Bail or Mainpriſe, and to ſtand in the Pillory by the ſpace of an hour, and in ſome Market-Town next adjoyning to the place where the offence was done, and never after to be admitted to be a Witneſs in any Court of Record.</p>
                  <p n="83">(83.) Fourthly, Concealing of the<note place="margin">Conceal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts Eſtate.</note> Bankrupts Eſtate: Any perſon being known or ſuſpected to have any Goods, Chattels, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupts, or to be indebted to him, if he doth not upon examination diſcloſe, and plainly declare his knowledge concerning the Premiſes, or doth deny to ſwear; Then every ſuch perſon (upon due proof thereof be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the Commiſſioners, by Witneſs, Examination, or otherwiſe, as they ſhall think fit) ſhall loſe and forfeit double
<pb n="141" facs="tcp:101268:71"/> the value of ſuch Goods, Chattels, Debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by them or any of them ſo concealed, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="84">(84.) Fraud: If any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons<note place="margin">Fraud<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                     </note> do fraudulently, by covin or collu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion claim, demand, recover, poſſeſs or detain any Debts, Duties, Goods, Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, Lands or Tenements, by writing, truſt, or otherwiſe, which were or ſhall be due, belonging or appertaining to any ſuch offendor or offendors, other than ſuch as he or they can and do prove to be due by right and conſcience for mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney paid, wares delivered, or other juſt conſideration, or cauſe reaſonable to the juſt value thereof, before the ſaid Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſsioners ſo to be appointed, or the more part of them, as is aforeſaid; and the ſame to proceed (<hi>bona fide</hi>) with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out fraud or covin; That then every ſuch perſon or perſons ſo craftily demanding, having or detaining any ſuch debt, duty, or other thing, as is aforeſaid, ſhall for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feit and loſe double as much as he or they ſhall ſo claim, demand, detain or poſſeſs, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="85">(85.) The ſaid Forfeitures of double<note place="margin">Forfei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures how im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ployed.</note> the value in both the caſes before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned, are to be levied and imployed
<pb n="142" facs="tcp:101268:72"/> by the Commiſſioners, as followeth, <hi>viz.</hi> The ſaid Commiſſioners, or the more part of them is to levy the ſame of the Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and Chattels of the perſons of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fending, by ſuch ways and means, and in ſuch manner and form as is before li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mited and appointed for the principal offendor or offendors, debtor or debtors<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and the ſame forfeiture or forfeitures to be diſtributed and imployed to and for the ſatisfaction and payment of the debts of the ſaid Creditor or Creditors, in ſuch manner, rate and form, as is by<note place="margin">Vid. Poſt</note> the Statute declared concerning the or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dering of the Lands and Tenements, Offices, Fees, Goods and Chattels of ſuch offendor or offendors, debtor or debtors, 13 <hi>Eliz cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="86">(86.) Over-plus: And if it ſhall for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune<note place="margin">Over<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plus.</note> the Creditors of any ſuch Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt to be ſatisfied and payed off their debts and duties, of or with the proper Lands, Tenements, Goods, Chattels, and Debts of the ſaid Bankrupts, or of o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> with the ſame and ſome part of the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feitures of the ſaid double values, to be forfeited as aforeſaid; and that there ſhall remain an over-plus of the ſaid
<pb n="143" facs="tcp:101268:72"/> forfeitures of the double values; That then one moyetie thereof ſhall be by the ſaid Commiſſioners, within conveni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ent time after the levying thereof, paid unto the Queens Majeſty, her Heirs and Succeſſors; and the other moyetie ſhall be by the ſaid Commiſſioners imployed and diſtributed to and amongſt the Poor, within the Hoſpitals, in every Ci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, Town or Country, where any ſuch Bankrupt ſhall happen to be, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. But the forfeitures by 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15. [being for Perjury and ſuborn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing of Perjury] is by the ſaid Act to be ſued for, and recovered by the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors only, or any of them that will ſue for the ſame, by action of Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information in any of the Kings Courts of Record; and the ſum and ſums of money ſo recover<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d, (the charges of ſuit being deducted) ſhall be diſtributed, and divided towards the payment of the ſaid Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="87">(87.) The allowance to Witneſſes:<note place="margin">Allow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance to Witneſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes.</note> Provided always, That ſuch Witneſſes as ſhall be ſent for by the Commiſſion<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers, ſhall have ſuch Coſts and Charges as the Commiſſioners in their diſcretion
<pb n="144" facs="tcp:101268:73"/> ſhall think fit: The ſame charges to be rateably born by the Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, according to the propor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of each of their ſeveral Debts, 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <head>The next thing to be conſidered, is the manner of the ordering and diſpoſal of the Bankrupts Eſtate by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners.</head>
                  <p n="88">(88.) Firſt, in General, The Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſsioners<note place="margin">In Gene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ral.</note> may according to their diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion, order the eſtate of the Bankrupt for the Creditors ſatisfaction, 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi>
                     <note place="margin">In Parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cular.</note> 
                     <hi>cap.</hi> 7. Secondly, more Particularly, Firſt, by views and appraiſement; The Commiſſioners may cauſe the Bankrupts Lands, Tenements, Fees, Annuities, Offices, Goods, Chattels, Wares, Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chandiſes and Debts, to be ſearched,<note place="margin">View, appraiſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</note> viewed, rented, and appraiſed, to the beſt value they may, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="89">(89.) Secondly, by Sale: 1. To whom<note place="margin">Sale.</note> may they ſell? The Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. is, that the Commiſſioners may ſell, without mentioning to whom; and by 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 19. which giveth power to the Commiſſioners to ſell entailed lands,
<pb n="145" facs="tcp:101268:73"/> it is to any perſon or perſons; which ſurely is intended to perſons capable, and not to aliens, although they be Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors.</p>
                  <p n="90">(90.) Thirdly, Of what? Of all<note place="margin">of what.</note> Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, and Deeds, Evidences and Writings touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the ſame; and of all Fees, Offices, Goods and Chattels of <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>he offendor, as is before ſet down.</p>
                  <p n="91">(91.) Fourthly, in what Manner?<note place="margin">How.</note> as to the Lands, Tenements, Goods and Chattels in general of the Bankrupts; the ſale is to be by Deed Indented and enrolled in any of his Majeſties Courts of Record, or otherwiſe to be ordered by the Commiſſioners, for ſatisfaction of the Creditors, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. And therefore, although the ſale be not by Deed inrolled, acco<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ding to the words of the Act, yet it is good enough, <hi>Cooke, lib.</hi> 2. 25. 26. caſe of Bankrupts: A Rent Seck, whereof there is no ſeiſin, ſhall be ſold, and the ſale is good with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out Attornement; <hi>Stones</hi> Lectur<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>, 174. <hi>quere.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="92">(92.) As to lands intail'd of the Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>krupt,<note place="margin">Intail'd Land<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</note>
                     <pb n="146" facs="tcp:101268:74"/> the Commiſſioners, or the greater number of them, are impowred by 21 <hi>Ja<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>. cap.</hi> 19. by Deed Indented and In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>olled within ſix months after the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king thereof, in ſome of his Majeſties Courts of Record at <hi>Weſtminſter,</hi> to grant, bar gain, ſell and convey any Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors, Lands, Tenements, or Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, whereof any Bankrupt is or ſhall be any ways ſeized of any eſtate in Tail, in Poſſeſſion, Reverſion, or Remainder, and whereof no Reverſion or Remain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der is or ſhall be in the Kings Majeſtie, his Heirs or Succeſſors, of the gift or proviſion of his Majeſty, his progenitors, his Heirs or Succeſſors, to any perſon or perſons, for the relief and benefit of the Creditors, 21 <hi>Jac. cap. 19. vide</hi> before Sect. 53.</p>
                  <p n="93">(93.) As to Copy-hold; or cuſtomary<note place="margin">Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold.</note> Lands, they are to be ſold by Deed In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dented and Inrolled in any of his Maje<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſties Courts of Record, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as other the Lands and Eſtate of the Bankrupt are appointed to be by 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7. But by the ſame Statute it is provided, That all and every perſon or perſons, to whom any ſuch ſale of Copy-hold, or cuſtomary Lands or Tenements ſhall be made;
<pb n="147" facs="tcp:101268:74"/> ſhall, before ſuch time, as they or any of them, ſhall enter or take any profits of the ſame Lands or Tenements; agree, &amp;c compound with the Lords of the Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nors of whom the ſame ſhall be holden, for ſuch Fines or Incomes as heretofore have been moſt uſually and accuſtomed to be yielded or paid therefore<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> And up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on every ſuch agreement or compoſition the ſaid Lords for the time being, at the next Court to be holden at or for the ſaid mannors; ſhall not only grant unto the ſaid Vendee or Vendees upon requeſt the ſame Copy or Cuſtomary Lands or Tenements, by Copy of Court-Roll of the ſaid Manors, for ſuch eſtate or In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſt as to them ſhall be ſold, and reſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the antient Rents, Cuſtomes and Services; but alſo, in the ſame Court<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> admit them Tenants of the ſame Copy or Cuſtomary Lands, as other Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders of the ſame Mannors have been wont to be admitted, and to receive their fealty accordingly, 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="94">(94.) A Copy-holder ſurrenders, &amp; before admittance <hi>ceſtuy que uſe;</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>comes a Bankrupt; The Commiſſioners ſell the Copy-hold, whether ſhall the Lord have 2 Fines, <hi>viz.</hi> one upon the
<pb n="148" facs="tcp:101268:75"/> admittance of which ſhould have been made to <hi>ceſtuy que uſe,</hi> if he had not become a Bankrupt; and another upon the admittance of the perſon that comes in by ſale of the Commiſſioners of Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>krupts: and this is a <hi>quere</hi> in Mr. <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture, fol. 137. and it is there com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pared to a ſurrender made by the Heir before admittance, which is held to be good, but not to prejudice the Lord of his Fine due upon the Deſcent, <hi>Cooke, lib.</hi> 4. 226.</p>
                  <p n="95">(95.) If the Vendee of a Copy-hold tender to the Lord a competent Fine, and the Lord refuſe it; The Vendee may enter, <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture, 176. The Commiſſioners may ſell Copy-hold in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tail'd, which by cuſtome may be intail'd and cut off, otherwiſe, if there be no ſuch cuſtome, <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture, 176. I conceive, if there be no ſuch cuſtome, then it is in nature of a Fee-ſimple con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditional at the Common Law, and then if the condition be performed, <hi>viz.</hi> if the Copy-holder hath iſſue, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſsioners may fell it, as I ſuppoſe.</p>
                  <p n="96">(96.) As to a Condition, Lands, Goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupt, made over
<pb n="149" facs="tcp:101268:75"/> by him upon condition or power of Redemption, the Commiſsioners before the time of the performance of the con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition, may appoint under their hands and ſeals, ſuch as they ſhall think fit to perform the condition; and after ſuch performance, ſhall diſpoſe of ſuch lands or goods for the Creditors advantage, as fully as of any other of the Bankrupts Eſtate, 21 <hi>Jac<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Cap. 19. vid. devant,</hi> Sect. (51.)</p>
                  <p n="97">(97.) As to lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> extended by a pretended Debtor or accomptant to the King, after that the party ſhall become a Bankrupt, 21 <hi>Jac. cap. 19. vid.</hi> Sect. 56. where it is ſet forth at large.</p>
                  <p n="98">(98.) As to debts owing to the Ban<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>krupt, <hi>vid.</hi> before Sect. 68. Suppoſe a Bankrupt be indebted to one 20 <hi>l.</hi> and to another 10 <hi>l.</hi> and hath a debt of 20 <hi>l.</hi> due to him by Bond; whether may the Commiſsioners aſsign the Bond to the two Creditors joyntly; and it was held by the Court, that it was to be divided and aſsigned according to the words of the Act, <hi>viz.</hi> to every Creditor a por<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, part and part-like: Then another queſtion was offered, whether the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignees
<pb n="150" facs="tcp:101268:76"/> might joyn in ſuit; and by <hi>War<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berton,</hi> one of the Juſtices, part being aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned to one, and part to another, the Act of Parliament doth ſo operate upon it, that they ſhall ſue ſeverally: for he ſaid, by the cuſtome of <hi>London,</hi> part of a debt might be attached, <hi>Godbolts</hi> Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports, 195. <hi>p.</hi> 282.</p>
                  <p n="99">(99.) Thirdly; Note, the diſtributi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on<note place="margin">Diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bution of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate.</note> made by the Commiſſioners, of the Bankrupts Eſtate, wherein obſerve; firſt, to what Creditors in general: It is en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>acted by 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. That the ſaid Act, and all other Acts of Parliament formerly made againſt Bankrupts, ſhould extend to ſtrangers born, as well Aliens as Denizens, as effectually as to the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tural born Subiects, both to make them ſubject to the Law, as Bankrupts, as al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo to make them capable of the benefit of contribution, as Creditors by thoſe Laws: So, that ſatisfaction is to be made to all, as well Aliens as Denizens, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="100">(100.) Alſo, It is enacted by 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. That for the better diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bution of the Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Goods, Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupt, to and amongſt his Creditors; The Commiſſioners or the greateſt part of them, ſhall and
<pb n="151" facs="tcp:101268:76"/> may examine upon Oath, or by any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther waies or means, as to them ſhall ſeem meet, any perſon or perſons for the finding out, and diſcovery of the truth and certainty of the ſeveral debts due and owing to all ſuch Creditor or Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, as ſhall ſeek relief by ſuch courſe of Commiſſion to be ſued forth, <hi>&amp;c. 21. Jac.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <p n="101">(101.) <hi>A.</hi> and <hi>B.</hi> are ſureties for <hi>I S.</hi> for the payment of Money, and had Counter-Bonds from <hi>I S.</hi> to ſave them harmleſs, the money was not payed at the day, the ſureties pay it: <hi>I S.</hi> after becomes a Bankrupt; Reſolved, that <hi>A.</hi> and <hi>B.</hi> were Creditors, within the Statutes of Bankrupts: <hi>Crooke, part 2. 127. Oſborne</hi> and <hi>Churchman's</hi> caſe; Mr. <hi>Stone</hi> in his Lecture, fol. 18. makes a <hi>Querie;</hi> whether, one becoming a Creditor to the Bankrupt after that he had notice that he was a Bankrupt, might be a Creditor, relievable within the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes: To which it may be anſwered in the negative; for if the Law diſables him to diſpoſe of his Eſtate, (after he becomes a Bankrupt) directly Then he cannot diſpoſe of it by a mean, <hi>viz.</hi> by becoming a Debtor, and ſo to make
<pb n="152" facs="tcp:101268:77"/> his Lands and Goods liable to his Debt, if in the caſe before, ſuch a Creditor were relieveable: and <hi>Stone</hi> ſeems to be of the ſame opinion, when he ſaith; A Bankrupt is committed to Priſon, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe he will not anſwer Interrogatories, the Gao ler gives him credit for victuals, he ſhall not be relieved, although he come in before diſtribution, fol. 183:</p>
                  <p n="102">(102.) A Merchant is impriſoned, and after becomes a Debtor to <hi>A.</hi> and then the ſix months paſſe, <hi>A.</hi> is a Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditor relievable; for he is not a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt by relation, <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture, 182. The Statute of 21 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 19. makes one a Bankrupt by relation from the time of his Arreſt, only in two caſes, <hi>viz</hi> either when he makes an Eſcape, or comes out upon common Bail, which enumeration I ſuppoſe, excludes (rela<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion) in other caſes, in a penal act of Parliament.</p>
                  <p n="103">(103.) A Bankrupt is convicted for inmates, and the Statute gives an action of Debt in ſuch caſe to the Lord of the Leet, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> he is no Creditor, within the Statute of Bankrupts; <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture, fol. 21. for I conceive this is not pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perly
<pb n="153" facs="tcp:101268:77"/> a Debt, but only a means given to recover a Forfeiture, and by <hi>Stone,</hi> a Mortgages of Lands may chuſe whether he will come in as a Creditor, fol. 181. There is before a ſpecial proviſion for ſatisfying of a condition by payment of the money, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by which it is intended, that the Mortgagee was never to be ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compted as a Creditor.</p>
                  <p n="104">(104.) It was decreed in <hi>Star-Chamber,</hi> that a Merchant for a wrong done by him to <hi>I. S.</hi> ſhould pay him <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>ol.</hi> and the Merchant becomes a Bankrupt, <hi>IS.</hi> is no Creditor, <hi>Stones</hi> Lecture, 184. for this is no Debt due for moneys bor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rowed, or upon any original contract; but only a payment laid on by the Court, and an action of Debt (as it is conceived) lies not for it; but only the party is to be puniſhed by the Court, if he perform not the decree.</p>
                  <p n="105">(105.) Secondly, more particularly, any Creditor coming in within four months after the commiſsion ſued forth by 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15. The words are; And that it ſhall and may be lawful for any of the Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupt, within four months after any ſuch Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſsion
<pb n="154" facs="tcp:101268:78"/> ſhall be ſued forth, and until di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtribution ſhall be made by the ſaid Commiſſioners for the payment of the Bankrupts debts, as in ſuch caſe hath been uſed to partake and joyn with the other Creditors that ſhall ſue forth any ſuch Commiſſion for ſatisfaction or pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment of his, her, or their debts to him or them owing, without any let, hindrance or diſturbance of any of the ſame Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, or of any of the other Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors of the ſaid Bankrupts: the ſame Creditors ſo coming in, to contribute to the charge of the ſaid Commiſſion: and that if the Creditors come not in with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in four months, then the Commiſſioners to have power to diſtribute: 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="106">(106.) In a Caſe of one <hi>Ruggles</hi> of <hi>Suffolk,</hi> upon view of the Statutes of 13 <hi>El. c.</hi> 7. &amp; 1 <hi>Jac. c.</hi> 15. of Bankrupts, it was reſolved by the Court, that if cer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain Creditors ſue a Commiſſion, and o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers within four months after, or more, being Creditors, come before diſtribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and will joyn in the charge of the Commiſſion, and all that belongs to it, and tender their parts thereof: that they ſhall not be refuſed, but ſhall have their equal parts, as Creditors; but if
<pb n="155" facs="tcp:101268:78"/> any diſtribution be made of any part of the eſtate, no Creditors are to be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted after, that came not in before: <hi>Hobart, 287. Ruggles Caſe.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="107">(107.) A Commiſſion was ſued out by ſome of the Creditors of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, and they purſued it; and the Lands were ſold, &amp; after other Creditors pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to be joyned with them: Reſolved in this caſe, Firſt, That the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners may ſell and prepare for diſtribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, preſently upon the execution of the Commiſſion, but untill the four months paſt, they may not proceed to diſtribution<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> Secondly, That in this caſe the offer of the Creditors, to be joyned was not an effectual offer, without offer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to be contributory to the charge, but to offer any particular ſum is not neceſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſary; and theſe words (<hi>for the charge of the Commiſſion</hi>) are to be extended to all charges, ariſing in ſuing forth of the Commiſſion, and in execution, and defence thereof. Thirdly, Reſolved, That at any time before diſtribution, the Creditors may come &amp; pray to be joyn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, but after the four months paſt, and diſtribution made, they come too late for ſo the diſtribution may be made void'
<pb n="156" facs="tcp:101268:79"/> 
                     <hi>Hutton 37, 38. Ruggles caſe, Hughes Abridgments, 316. Caſe</hi> 2.</p>
                  <p n="108">(108.) Next, obſerve the time of<note place="margin">Time of diſtribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</note> ſatisfaction, or diſtribution, it ſeems it muſt not be, untill four months after the Commiſſion ſued forth; for ſo much time is given to other Creditors to come in and joyn in the Commiſſion, and if the Creditors come not in within that time, the Commiſſioners may diſtribute, 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="109">(109.) The manner of the diſtribu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion: No reſpect is to be had to the na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture<note place="margin">Manner of diſtri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bution.</note> of the ſecurity, for by 13 <hi>El.</hi> 7. the Commiſſioners are to ſell, or otherwiſe to order the Bankrupts eſtate, for true ſatisfaction and payment of the Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, rate and rate like, according to the Quantity of his or their debts, 23 <hi>El. chap.</hi> 7. A debt due to the Bankrupt by Bond, cannot be aſſigned to two of his Creditors joyntly, but part to one and part to another, and by vertue of the Statutes, they may ſue ſeverally. <hi>&amp;c. Godbolts Reports,</hi> 195.</p>
                  <p n="110">(110.) The Commiſſioners ought to make a ſeveral diſtribution to the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditors, and not a joynt-ſale, for the Act
<pb n="157" facs="tcp:101268:79"/> ſaith <note n="†" place="margin">13 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                           <desc>••</desc>
                        </gap> 7.</note> it muſt be to every one, rate, and rate-like, but where a debt is joyntly due, there the Commiſſioners may ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fie the ſame, by a joynt ſale to them, <hi>Cook, lib. 2. 26. b. Caſe of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="111">(111.) All and every Creditor, and Creditors, having ſecurity for his or their ſeveral debts by Judgment, Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute, Recognizance, ſpecialty with pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nalty, or without penalty, or other ſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity, or having no ſecurity, or having made attachment in <hi>London,</hi> or any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther place, by vertue of any cuſtom there uſed of the goods and chattels of any ſuch Bankrupt, whereof there is no ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ecution or extent ſerved and executed, upon any the Lands, Tenements, Here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditaments, Goods, Chattels, and other eſtate of ſuch Bankrupt, before ſuch time, as he, or, ſhe, ſhall or do become Bankrupt, ſhall not be relieved upon any ſuch Judgment, Statute, Recognizance, Specialty, Attachments, or other ſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rity for any more than a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ateable part, of their juſt and due debts, with the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther Creditors of the ſaid Bankrupts, without reſpect to any ſuch penalty or greater ſum contained in any Judgment,
<pb n="158" facs="tcp:101268:80"/> Statute, Recognizance, Specialty, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or other ſecurity, 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19. I ſuppoſe ſecurity by Mortgage of Lands, cannot be within this Statute, for there is particular proviſion for the ſame, in the ſame Statute, 21 <hi>Jac.</hi> 19. nor are lands extended as it ſeems within the ſaid clauſe, by reaſon of the words be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore, [<hi>whereof there is no execution or ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent ſerved or executed.</hi>]</p>
               </div>
               <div type="subpart">
                  <head>The next thing conſiderable is, the effect of the diſtribution, made by the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, as aforeſaid.</head>
                  <p n="112">(112.) Firſt in general, as to Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, goods, chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, and other eſtate of the Bankrupt: by 13 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 7. It is enacted, That every direction, order, bargain, ſale, and things done by the ſaid perſons, ſo autho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rized [<hi>viz the Commiſſioners or greater number of them</hi>] ſhall be good and ef<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fectual in the Law, to all intents, conſtru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions and purpoſes, againſt the ſaid of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fender or offenders, debtor or debtors, his or their wife or wives, heir and heirs, child and children, and ſuch perſon and perſons, as by joynt purchaſe with the ſaid offender or offenders, ſhall have any
<pb n="159" facs="tcp:101268:80"/> eſtate, or intereſt in the premiſes; and againſt all other perſon and perſons, clai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming by, from, or under ſuch offender or offenders, debtor or debtors, by any Act or Acts; had, made, or done, after any ſuch perſon ſhall become Bankrupt, as aforeſaid; and alſo againſt the Lords of the Mannors. <hi>&amp;c. [vide</hi> after for Copy-holds,] 13 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 7. But not to bar any purchaſer upon valuable con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration, unleſs the Commiſſion be ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed forth within five years after the par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty becomes a Bankrupt; by 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <p n="113">(113.) Secondly, As to Lands in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tailed<note place="margin">Lands intay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>led.</note> of the Bankrupts: the Statute gives power to the Commiſſioners to grant, bargain, and ſell by deed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled, Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> intailed of the Bankrupts, [<hi>vide devant, Sect.</hi> 53.] and then adds, that all and every ſuch grants, bargains, ſales, and conveyances ſhall be good and available in the Law, to ſuch perſon or perſons, and their heirs, againſt the ſaid Bankrupts, and againſt all and every the iſſue of the bodies, of ſuch Bankrupts, and againſt all, and every perſon or perſons, claiming any eſtate, right, title, or intereſt, by,
<pb n="160" facs="tcp:101268:81"/> from, or under the ſaid Bankrupts, after ſuch time as ſuch perſon ſhall become Bankrupt, and againſt all and every ſuch perſon or perſons whatſoever, whom the ſaid Bankrupt, by common Recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry, or other way or means might cut off, or debar from any remainder, reverſion; rent, profit, title, or poſſibility, into or out of any of the ſaid Mannors, Lands, Tenements, or hereditaments: 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <p n="114">(114.) Thirdly as to the Copy holds,<note place="margin">Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold.</note> the ſale and diſpoſiton of them<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſhall be good againſt the Bankrupts, to all intents and purpoſes, and againſt his or their wife or wives, heir and heirs, in like manner, as before for his other eſtate, <hi>Sect.</hi> 45. for there is no diſtinct clauſe for the Copy-holds; <hi>viz. And alſo a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the Lords of the Mannors, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the ſaid Cuſtomary, or Copy-hold Lands been holden, their Heirs, Succeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſors, and Aſſigns, and every of them:</hi> and there is a <hi>Proviſo</hi> added, That the Ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dees of ſuch Copy-holds ſhall compound for their Fines with the Lords before entry: <hi>vide Sect.</hi> 93. before.</p>
                  <p n="115">(115.) The ſale of the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners
<pb n="161" facs="tcp:101268:81"/> doth veſt the Copy-hold eſtate, ſo in the Vendee before admittance, that the ſaid Bankrupt cannot be ſaid to be Tenant; and therefore if he dle before admittance, his wiſe ſhall not have any Cuſtomary eſtate, which by the cuſtom ſhe ought to have, when her husband dies Tenant; the Vendee is only ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cluded by the Statute from entry, or ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of the profits, before compoſition made with the Lord, which is only for the Lords benefit, and not the Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>holders; alſo it was held, that after com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſition for the time, and the admittance of the Vendee, it ſhall relate to deveſt all Cuſtomary eſtates happening ſince the ſale, and before the ſaid compoſition and admittance. <hi>Crook, part 3. 568, 569. Parker verſ. Edith Bleek.</hi>
                  </p>
                  <p n="116">(116.) If two Joynt-tenants be of Copy-hold <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ands in Fee, and the one out of Court according to the cuſtom, ſurrender his part to the Lords hands, according to the cuſtom, to the uſe of his laſt will, and by his will deviſeth a part to a ſtranger in fee; and dieth; and at the next Court the ſurrender is preſented<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> by the ſurrender and preſentment the Joynture was ſevered, and the Deviſee
<pb n="162" facs="tcp:101268:82"/> ought to be admitted to the moiety of the Lands, for now by relation, the ſtate of the Land was bound by the ſurren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der. <hi>Cook, ſur Litt.</hi> 596.</p>
                  <p n="117">(117.) As to the debts due to the<note place="margin">Debts due to the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt.</note> Bankrupt, The Commiſſioners have power to grant, aſſign, or otherwiſe to order and diſpoſe all or any debts due, or to be due, to, or for the benefit of the Bankrupt, by any perſon or perſons whatſoever, or in what form ſoever, to the uſe of the Bankrupts Creditors, ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to 13 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 7. And that the ſame grant, aſſignment, or diſpoſition of the ſaid debts, ſhall ſo veſt the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perty, right, and intereſt of the ſaid debt and debts in the perſon or perſons to whom the ſame ſhall be ſo granted, aſſigned, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as fully to all intents and purpoſes, as if the Bonds, Bills, Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes, Judgments, or contracts, where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>upon ſuch debt or debts did ariſe, or grow, had been made to or with the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons to whom the ſame ſhall be ſo aſſigned: And that after ſuch grant, aſſignment, or diſpoſition made of the ſaid debts, neither the Bankrupt, nor any other to whom any ſuch debt ſhall be due, ſhall have power to recover the ſame, nor to make any releaſe or diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charge
<pb n="163" facs="tcp:101268:82"/> thereof, neither ſhall the ſame be attached, as the debt of the Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, or ſuch ſaid other perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to whom the ſame ſhall be due, by any other perſon or perſons, according to the cuſtom of the City of <hi>London,</hi> or otherwiſe, But that the party or par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties to whom the ſaid debt ſhall be aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned, ſhall have like remedy to reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver the ſame, as fully and lawfully in the name, or names of the perſon or perſons to whom the ſame ſhall be ſo granted, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned, or ordered by the ſaid Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, in all reſpects and purpoſes, as the party himſelf might have had: 1 <hi>Jac. chap. 15. Provided always, that no deb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor of the Bankrupt be hereby indangered for the payment of his or their Debt, tru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and</hi> bona fide, <hi>to any ſuch Bankrupt, before ſuch time as he ſhall underſtand, or know that he is become a Bankrupt,</hi> 1 Jac. chap. 15.</p>
                  <p n="118">(118.) To give means of Recove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry; As to the debts of the Bankrupt, aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſigned by the Commiſſioners; the aſſig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nee, ſhall have the like remedy to reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver the ſame, as fully and lawfully, as the party himſelf. 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="119">(119.) The Aſſignees of the ſaid debts may ſue for them in their own
<pb n="164" facs="tcp:101268:83"/> names, becauſe they are debts, transfer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red by Parliament; but yet notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding, in caſe the action of debt ariſe upon a Contract, the Defendant may wage his Law; for although the Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment transferred the debt, yet it is no debt upon Record. <hi>Croke, part 2. 105. Bradſhaws Caſe.</hi> A debt due by bond, aſſigned to two Creditors ſeverally, they may ſue ſeverally for it: <hi>Godbolts Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ports, fol.</hi> 195.</p>
                  <p n="120">(120.) As to Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the<note place="margin">Lands extend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed.</note> Bankrupt extended by any pretended debt or accomptant to the King, after ſuch time as the Bankrupt becomes a Bankrupt; ſuch perſon or perſons to whom the Commiſſioners, or major part, ſhall bargain, ſell, grant or aſſign the ſaid Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall have good remedy, to demand and recover the ſame, againſt ſuch perſons as detain the ſame. 21 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 19.</p>
                  <p n="121">(121.) As to Lands, Tenements, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of the Bankrupts conveyed away upon condition the Commiſſioners have power to appoint one or more to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>form the condition, <hi>vide devant, Sect.</hi> 51.<note place="margin">Credi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ren.</note>
                  </p>
                  <p n="122">(122.) Another effect of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners
<pb n="165" facs="tcp:101268:83"/> diſtribution, is to bar the Cre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditor: if any Creditor of the Bankrupts, ſhall not be fully ſatisfied, or otherwiſe contented, by ſuch means as the Statute appointeth, they may have their remedy againſt the Bankrupt (as before they had) for the remainder, and ſhall be on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly barred for ſo much as they are ſatis<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fied, or contented for, and no more: 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="123">(123.) Laſtly, to reſtore the ca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity<note place="margin">Capaci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts.</note> of the Bankrupt: The Bankrupt to have the overplus of his eſtate if any be, after that the Creditors are ſatisfied. And that the ſaid Bankrupts after the full ſatisfaction of the ſaid Creditors ſhall have power and authority to recover &amp; receive the reſidue and remainder of the Debts to them owing. 1 <hi>Jac. chap.</hi> 15.</p>
                  <p n="124">(124.) Next obſerve, the accompt of<note place="margin">Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compt.</note> the Commiſſioners to the Bankrupt: ſuch of the ſaid Commiſſioners as ſhall put the ſaid Commiſſion in execution ſhall upon lawful requeſt to them made by the Bankrupt, not only make a true declara<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion to the ſaid Bankrupts of imploying and beſtowing of their ſaid Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, offices, Fees, goods, chattels, and debts ſo payed and ſatisfied to their
<pb n="166" facs="tcp:101268:84"/> ſaid Creditors, but alſo make payment of the overplus of the ſame (if any ſuch be) to the ſaid Bankrupts, their exe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cutors, adminiſtrators, or aſſigns. 13 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 7.</p>
                  <p n="125">(125.) Remedy for the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners in any action brought againſt them for acting by force of the ſaid Statutes, they may plead not guilty, and juſtifie by the authority of the ſaid Acts, and the Plaintiff to reply <hi>de ſon tort de meſme:</hi> and if the Verdict paſs for the defen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dant, he ſhall have Coſts: 1 <hi>Jac. cap.</hi> 15.</p>
               </div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="index">
            <pb n="167" facs="tcp:101268:84"/>
            <head>THE TABLE.</head>
            <list>
               <item>ABſenting himſelf makes a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 2, 12, 13, 14.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Accompt made by the Commiſſioners to the Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 124.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Allowance made to Witneſses appearing before the Commiſſioners, <hi>Sect. 87.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Appearance of the Bankrupt before the Commiſſioners, and their power to in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>force it, <hi>Sect. 30, 39.</hi> of other perſons ſuſpected to have any of the Bankrupts goods, <hi>Sect. 78.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Appraiſement of the Bankrupts Eſtate, <hi>Sect. 88.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Arreſt, a Trader ſuffering himſelf wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lingly to be arreſted, makes him a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 21.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Attachment of a Traders goods makes him a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 16. 17.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Authority of Commiſſioners immediately appointed by Act of Parliament, <hi>Sect. 29, 30,</hi> &amp;c. of Commiſſioners mediately appointed by Lord Chancellor, <hi>Sect. 39, 40.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb n="168" facs="tcp:101268:85"/>
               <head>B</head>
               <item>BAil, coming out of priſon upon com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon Bail<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> make a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 22.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Bankrupt, his name, <hi>Sect. 1.</hi> his Deſcrip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion in general, <hi>Sect. 2.</hi> more parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cularly from <hi>Sect. 4.</hi> to 26. his inca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pacity, <hi>Sect. 28.</hi> Proceeding againſt him by perſons immediately authorized by Parliament, <hi>Sect. 29, 31, 32.</hi> By perſons mediately authorized as Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, <hi>Sect. 36.</hi> their authority, as to the Bankrupts perſon, <hi>Sect. 39.</hi> his Eſtate, 43, <hi>uſque ad 49.</hi> his capa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>city reſtored, <hi>Sect. 123.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Barr, The effect of the Commiſſioners diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſing of the Bankrupts Eſtate to bar others, <hi>Sect. 112, 113.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>C</head>
               <item>CApacity of the Bankrupt taken away <hi>Sect. 28.</hi> reſtored, <hi>Sect. 123.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Chattels of the Bankrupt to be diſpoſed by the Commiſſioners, <hi>Sect. 59, 61, 62, 63, &amp;c.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Clothier may be within the Stat. of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, <hi>Sect. 11.</hi>
               </item>
               <pb n="169" facs="tcp:101268:85"/>
               <item>Commiſſion of Bankrupts granted by the Lord Keeper, <hi>Sect. 36.</hi> within what time, and duration of it, <hi>Sect. 36.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Commiſſioners of Bankrupts, how made, <hi>Sect. 36.</hi> their authority. 39. &amp;c. their accompt to the Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 124.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Compoſition, endeavouring to inforce a Compoſition by a Trader makes him a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 24.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Condition, Commiſſioners may fulfil it, <hi>Sect. 51.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Copy-holds, valuable by the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, <hi>Sect. 45.</hi> Diſtribution of them, 114, 115, 116.</item>
               <item>Creditors, orders taken by the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners as to their ſatisfaction, <hi>Sect. 88, 89, &amp;c.</hi> the effect of the diſtribution, <hi>Sect. 112, 113.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>D</head>
               <item>DEbts due to the Bankrupt ſaleable <hi>Sect. 68, 69.</hi> the remedy the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons to whom they are ſaleable have to recover them, <hi>Sect. 117, 118, 119.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Diſcovery of the Bankrupts Eſtate, <hi>Sect. 32.</hi> breaking open Doors, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> 72. ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>amination of Perſons, <hi>Sect. 73.</hi> Pu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſhment, <hi>Sect. 74.</hi> Examination of
<pb n="170" facs="tcp:101268:86"/> Bankrupts wife, <hi>Sect. 77.</hi> other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, <hi>Sect. 78.</hi> Puniſhment of them, Sect. <hi>79, 80, 82, 83, 84, 85.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Diſpoſition of the Bankrupts Eſtate by the Commiſſioners, <hi>Sect. 88, 89.</hi> of what, 90. in what manner, 91. as to Lands in tail, 92. Copy-hold, <hi>Sect. 93, 94.</hi> Lands made over upon Condition, <hi>Sect. 96.</hi> Debts, 98. to what Creditors, 99. <hi>&amp;c.</hi> not within four months, <hi>Sect. 107.</hi> manner of Diſtribution, <hi>Sect. 109.</hi> effect thereof, <hi>Sect. 112.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>E</head>
               <item>EScape out of Priſon makes a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 22.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Effect of the Commiſſioners diſtribution, as to Lands, <hi>Sect. 112, 113.</hi> Copy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold, 114, 115, 116. as to Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts Debts, 117, 118, 119. to bar the Creditor, <hi>Sect. 122.</hi> to reſtore the Bankrupts capacity. <hi>Sect. 123.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Eſtate of the Bankrupt ſubject to ſale: as ſuch as was by him joyntly purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, <hi>Sect. 46.</hi> not what was conveyed by him away before he became Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 57.</hi> Alſo the Bankrupts Chattels are ſaleable by the Commiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſioners, <hi>Sect. 59, 61, 62, 63.</hi> Goods
<pb n="171" facs="tcp:101268:86"/> extended, 65. Goods of which the Bankrupt diſpoſed as his own. <hi>Sect. 66.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Examination of the Bankrupt himſelf touching his Eſtate, <hi>Sect. 73.</hi> Of his Wife, <hi>Sect. 77.</hi> Of perſons ſuſpected to have the Bankrupts Eſtate, <hi>Sect. 78.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Expoſition of Statutes made againſt Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts; They are to be largely and beneficially expounded, for the relief of Creditors, <hi>Sect. 27.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>F</head>
               <item>FEme Covert, ſole Merchant, within the Statute of Bankrupts, <hi>Sect. 8.</hi> power of the Commiſſioners to examine the Bankrupts Feme, 77.</item>
               <item>Forfeiture, for refuſing to be examined by the Commiſſioners, or delivering the truth to them, <hi>Sect. 32. 81.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Fraud, fraudulent Gifts make the Giver a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 25.</hi> the Bankrupts fraud puniſhed, <hi>Sect. 76.</hi> fraudulent Recoveries againſt him, <hi>Sect. 34.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>G</head>
               <item>GRaſier, within the Statute of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupts, <hi>Sect. 10.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb n="172" facs="tcp:101268:87"/>
               <head>H</head>
               <item>HIding himſelf, makes a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 12. 14.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>I</head>
               <item>IMpriſonment; Power of Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners to impriſon the Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 39.</hi> other perſons, <hi>Sect. 73.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Joynt-tenants, whether ſale made by Commiſſioners, prevents ſurvivor-ſhip, <hi>Sect. 44.</hi> Lands ſaleable, which were joyntly purchaſed by the Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 46.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Inn-keeper, not within the Statute of Bankrupts, <hi>Sect. 5.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Intail'd Lands of the Bankrupt, ſubject to the Statutes, <hi>Sect. 53.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>K</head>
               <item>KEeping in his houſe, makes a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 12. 14.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>L</head>
               <item>LImitation of Ac<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ions, whether that Statute extends to Bankrupts debts, <hi>Sect. 70.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <pb n="173" facs="tcp:101268:87"/>
               <head>M</head>
               <item>MErchant, what Merchant is with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the Statute of Bankrupts, <hi>Sect. 4, 5, 6, 7,</hi> &amp;c.</item>
               <item>Mortgagee, may chuſe whether he will come in as a Creditor, <hi>Sect. 103.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>O</head>
               <item>OFfices ſaleable by Commiſſioners, <hi>Sect. 60.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>P</head>
               <item>PErjury, of the Bankrupt himſelf, how puniſhable, <hi>Sect. 75.</hi> of other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, <hi>Sect. 82.</hi> procurement of Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury, 82.</item>
               <item>Petition, to inforce Creditors to com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pound, makes the Petitioner a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 24.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Priſon, yielding himſelf to Priſon, and lying there 6 months, makes a Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 19, 20, 21. vide</hi> Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt.</item>
               <item>Proclamation made for the Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 39,</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Property, how the ſale and diſtribution
<pb n="174" facs="tcp:101268:88"/> made by the Commiſſioners veſteth the property, <hi>Sect. 112, 113, 114,</hi> &amp;c.</item>
               <item>Protection obtained makes a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 23.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Puniſhment of a Bankrupt, he ſhall be out of the Kings protection, <hi>Sect. 31. 39.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Pillory, 75, 76. of the Bankrupts Wife, <hi>Sect. 77.</hi> other perſons, <hi>Sect. 79,</hi> &amp;c.</item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>Q</head>
               <item>Q<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ality of any perſon, exempts not him out of the Commiſſion of Bankrupts, if he be a Trader, <hi>Sect. 7.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>R</head>
               <item>REcovery, means of Recovery of the Debts of the Bankrupt aſſigned over, <hi>Sect. 118.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Relation, in what caſe the party ſhall be judged a Bankrupt from the time of his Arreſt, <hi>Sect. 22.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>S</head>
               <item>SAle, the Commiſſioners authority to ſell the Bankrupts Eſtate, <hi>Sect. 35.</hi> of what Eſtate, <hi>Sect, 43, 44, 45,</hi> &amp;c. to whom 89. in what manner, <hi>Sect. 91.</hi>
                  <pb n="175" facs="tcp:101268:88"/> &amp;c. the effect of their ſale, <hi>Sect. 112.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Sanctuary, keeping of Sanctuary, makes a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 15.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Satisfaction, <hi>vide</hi> diſpoſition.</item>
               <item>Shoomaker, may be within the Statute of Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 5.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Scrivener may be a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 11.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>T</head>
               <item>TAil, Lands intailed ſaleable, <hi>Sect. 53. 92.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Taylor, not within the Statutes of Bank<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rupt, <hi>Sect. 6.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Truſt, Lands made over in Truſt for the Bankrupt, ſaleable by the Commiſſio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners, <hi>Sect. 48.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>U</head>
               <item>UTlagary, a Traders ſuffering him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf to be outlawed, makes him a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 18.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <list>
               <head>W</head>
               <item>WArning, left for a Bankrupt to ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pear before the Commiſſioners, being not obſerved, he may be pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>claimed a Bankrupt, <hi>Sect. 40.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>Witneſſes, their allowance, <hi>Sect. 87.</hi>
               </item>
            </list>
            <trailer>The End.</trailer>
         </div>
         <div type="half_title">
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:89"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:89"/>
            <p>THE RESOLUTIONS OF THE Judges, Upon 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> and 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tutes touching Fraudulent Conveyances. By Way of APPENDIX; By The Same Author.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="appendix">
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:90"/>
            <pb n="179" facs="tcp:101268:90"/>
            <head>The Reſolutions of the Judges, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p n="1">(1.) THe Statute of 13 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 5. is<note place="margin">Fraudu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ances, 13 <hi>El. Chap. 5.</hi>
               </note> made perpetual by 25 <hi>El. cap.</hi> 5. The words are; For the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voiding and aboliſhing of feigned Conveyances, covenous and fraudulent Feoffments, Gifts, Grants, and Alie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nations, Conveyances, Bonds, Suits, Judgments and Executions, as well of Lands and Tenements, as of Goods and Chattels; which have been and are contrived or deviſed of malice, fraud, coven, colluſion or guile; to the end to delay, hinder or defraud Creditors and others of their juſt and lawful Actions, Suits, Debts, Accompts, Demages, Penalties, Forfeitures, Her<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riots, Mortuaries, and Reliefs; not on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly to the let or hindrance of the due courſe and execution of Law and Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtice: but alſo to the overthrow of all true and plain dealing between man and man, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="180" facs="tcp:101268:91"/>
            <p n="2">(2.) Be it therefore declared, ordain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and enacted, that all and every Feoff<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, Gift, Grant, Alienation, Bargain and Conveyance of Lands, Tenements, Hereditaments, Goods and Chattels, or any of them; or any Leaſe, Rent, Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons, or other profit or charge out of the ſame, or any of them, by writing or otherwiſe; and all and every Bond, Suit, Judgment and Execution, at any time had or made ſince the beginning of the ſaid Queens Reign, or at any time here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after to be had or made to or for any in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent or purpoſe before declared and ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed; ſhall be from henceforth deem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and taken [only againſt the perſons their Heirs, Succeſſors, Executors, Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrators and Aſſigns, whoſe Actions, Suits, Accompts, Damages, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> by ſuch Practiſes, may or ſhall be in any ways diſturbed] to be clearly and utterly void: Any pretence, colour, feigned conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration, expreſſion or uſe, other matter or thing to the contrary notwithſtand<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing</p>
            <p n="3">(3.) And be it further enacted, That all and every the parties, to ſuch feigned, covenous, or fraudulent Feoffment, Gift, Grant, Alienation. Bargain, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyance, Bonds, Suits, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and other
<pb n="181" facs="tcp:101268:91"/> things before expreſſed; and being pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vy, and knowing of the ſame, or any of them, which at any time after the <hi>10th</hi> day of <hi>June</hi> next coming, ſhall witting<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly and willingly put in ure, avow, main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tain, juſtifie or defend the ſame, or any of them, as true, ſimple, and done, or made <hi>bona fide,</hi> and upon good conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration; or ſhall alien or aſſign any of the Lands, Tenements, Goods, Leaſes, or other things before mentioned, to him or them conveyed as aforeſaid, or any part thereof; ſhall incur the penal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty and forfeiture of one years value of the ſaid Lands, Tenements, Heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, Leaſes, Rents, Commons, or other profits out of the ſame; and the whole value of the ſaid Goods and Chat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tels, and ſo much money as ſhall be con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tained in any ſuch covenous and feigned Bond: The one moiety thereof to the Queens Majeſty, the other to the party grieved, by ſuch feigned and frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulent Gift, Grant, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to be recovered in any of the Queens Courts of Record, by Debt, Bill, Plaint, or Information; wherein no eſſoin, protection, or wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger of Law ſhall be admitted for the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant or Defendants: And he alſo, being lawfully convicted, ſhall ſuffer im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priſonment
<pb n="182" facs="tcp:101268:92"/> for half a year, without Bail or main priſe.</p>
            <p n="4">(4.) Proviſoes: Firſt, that the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute<note place="margin">What the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tends not to.</note> ſhall not extend to common Reco<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veries, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> Secondly, nor to any perſon or perſons that ſhall uſe any voucher in <hi>Formedon.</hi> Thirdly, Nor to any Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyances made upon good conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and <hi>bonafide</hi> to any perſon or per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſons, corporation, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> without covin, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="5">(5.) Between <hi>Pauncefoot</hi> and <hi>Blunt</hi>
               <note place="margin">Gift made by a Papiſt.</note> in the <hi>Chequer Chamber,</hi> the caſe was; <hi>Pauncefoot</hi> being a Papiſt, was indicted for his Recuſancie, and he made a gift of all his Leaſes and Goods upon coloura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble conſideration, and fled beyond Sea, and was after outlawed upon the ſaid In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dictment; and ſome thought, that by the Common Law, the ſaid gift was void, in regard it was in prejudice of the Queen; but all agreed that the ſaid Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute of 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> extends to it; for it extends not only to Creditors, but to all ſuch as have any cauſe of action or ſuit, or any penalty or forfeiture: And it was alſo reſolved, that this word, Forfeiture, ſhall be intended, not only of a forfeiture upon an Obligation, Recognizance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
               <pb n="183" facs="tcp:101268:92"/> but to every thing lawfully forfeited to the King, or a Subject: and therefore<note place="margin">Felo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
               </note> if a man to prevent a forfeiture by felo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny, or outlawry, makes a gift of all his Goods, and after is attained or outlaw<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, theſe Goods are forfeited, notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding the Gift, <hi>Cook, lib.</hi> 3. 82.<note place="margin">Per Heir of Deb<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tor.</note>
            </p>
            <p n="6">(6.) It was held, that the Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 5. extends to a fraudulent conveyance made by the Heir of the Debtor, of lands deſcended to him from his deceaſed Anceſtor, as well as by the Debtor himſelf; for in ſuch caſe the Heir is Debtor, and the Writ againſt him is in the <hi>debet</hi> and <hi>detinet,</hi> whereas againſt an Executor it is in the <hi>detinet</hi> only, <hi>Croke,</hi> part 1. 350. <hi>p.</hi> 1.</p>
            <p n="7">(7.) It was found by a ſpecial Ver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dict;<note place="margin">Gift up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition.</note> That a Teſtator was ſeized of di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers Goods, to the value of <hi>250l.</hi> and by covin to defraud his Creditors, he made a gift of the ſaid Goods to his Daughters, with a condition, that upon payment of 20 <hi>s.</hi> it ſhould be void, and dyed; this was held to be a fraudulent gift, by 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 5. and that not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding it, the Goods continued <hi>Aſſets, Croke,</hi> part 1. 810. <hi>p. 16. Bethel</hi> and <hi>dw. Stanbope.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="184" facs="tcp:101268:93"/>
            <p n="8">(8.) An Executrix makes a fraudu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent<note place="margin">Gift by Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>trix, who conti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nues poſſeſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</note> gift of the goods of the Teſtator, and inter-marrieth; and her husband taketh upon him payment of Debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The Goods being ſtill in their poſſeſſion, were held to be ſtill <hi>Aſſets, Croke,</hi> part 1. 406. <hi>p. 16. Wilcotts,</hi> verſ. <hi>Watſon.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="9">(9.) A man maketh a Leaſe for 80<note place="margin">Conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</note> years of Lands, without any conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion; and he after ſetleth a Joynture upon his Wife of the ſame Lands; ſhe could not avoid that Leaſe, becauſe the Conveyance to her was likewiſe volun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tary, and without any valuable conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration, <hi>Croke,</hi> part 1. 445. <hi>p. 8. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pton</hi> and <hi>Baſſett.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="10">(10.) <hi>Pierce</hi> was in debt to <hi>Twine</hi>
               <note place="margin">Gift pending a writ.</note> 400 <hi>l.</hi> and to <hi>C. 200 l. C.</hi> brought Debt againſt <hi>Pie<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ce,</hi> and pending the Writ, <hi>Pierce</hi> being poſſeſs'd of goods to the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of 300 <hi>l.</hi> in ſecret makes a general gift of all his Goods and Chattels, real and perſonal whatſoever, to <hi>Twine,</hi> in ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tisfaction of his debt; and yet notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding <hi>Pierce</hi> continueth in poſſeſſion, and ſome of them he ſold, and he marked the ſheep with his own mark: And af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
<pb n="185" facs="tcp:101268:93"/> 
               <hi>C.</hi> had a Judgment againſt <hi>Pierce,</hi> and a <hi>Fieri Facias</hi> to the Sheriff, who coming to make execution by force of the Writ, divers perſons by <hi>Twines</hi> Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand reſiſted the Sheriff, claiming the goods as <hi>Twines</hi> by force of the ſaid gift: and this was reſolved to be a fraudulent gift; and that in the ſaid caſe there were<note place="margin">Marks of Fraud.</note> theſe ſeveral marks of fraud: Firſt, the gift is general, without any exception, ſo much as of wearing apparel: Second<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly, the Donor continueth in poſſeſſion: Thirdly, it was ſecret: Fourthly, it was made pending the writ: Fifthly, here was a Truſt between the parties, for the donor ſtill uſeth the goods as his own: Sixthly, the words of the Deed are, that it was made honeſtly, truly, and <hi>bona<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>fide, &amp; clauſulae inconſuetae inducunt ſuſpicionem,</hi> Cooke, lib. 3. 81. Twines caſe.</p>
            <p n="11">(11.) Secondly, it was reſolved in<note place="margin">Conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration <hi>bona fide.</hi>
               </note> the ſame caſe, that although here were a Debt due to <hi>Twine,</hi> and a good conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration of a gift, yet it was not aided by the ſame Proviſo in 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> which was, that the ſaid Act ſhould not extend to any Eſtate or Eſtates made upon good conſideration, and <hi>bona fide;</hi> for this is not <hi>bona fide,</hi> becauſe it is upon a Truſt,
<pb n="186" facs="tcp:101268:94"/> and no gift ſhall be conſtrued, to be <hi>bo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na fide,</hi> within the ſaid Statute, that is made upon a Truſt, <hi>Cooke, lib. 3. 81. Twines</hi> caſe.</p>
            <p n="12">(12.) And it is my Lord <hi>Cookes</hi> ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vice<note place="margin">Advice touch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing Gifts.</note> in the ſaid caſe, that when any gift is to be made in ſatisfaction of a debt: Firſt, that it be publickly done before Neighbours: Secondly, that the goods, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> given, be appraiſed by honeſt men: Thirdly, that the Donee preſently after the gift, take poſſeſſion; for the continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance of poſſeſſion in the Donor, is a mark of Truſt, <hi>Cooke, lib. 3. 81. Twines</hi> caſe.</p>
            <p n="13">(13.) One held divers lands of di<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vers Lords by <hi>Herriot</hi> cuſtom; and to defraud one of the Lords of his <hi>Herriot,</hi> he made a fraudulent gift of all his beaſts <hi>Herriottable, viz.</hi> of 20 Horſes: The Lord, who was hereby grieved, bringeth Debt upon 13 <hi>Eliz. tam pro Domina Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gina quam pro ſeipſo,</hi> demanding the va<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lue of the 20 Horſes; and by <hi>Dyer</hi> and <hi>Harper,</hi> it was well ſaid, by intendment of the Statute; for it may be, he ſhall never come to ſeize his <hi>Herriot,</hi> and if he ſhall recover but the value, the Queen ſhall have the one Moiety: But <hi>Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wood</hi>
               <pb n="187" facs="tcp:101268:94"/> held <hi>contra;</hi> for the other Lords are as recompenſable for their <hi>Herriots,</hi> as the Plaintiff: and <hi>Harper</hi> held, that all the Lords might joyn in an action; but <hi>quere,</hi> ſaith <hi>Dier, 35 1. p.</hi> 23.</p>
            <p n="14">(14.) Upon communication of mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage<note place="margin">Proviſo, to deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine, &amp;c.</note> between Sir <hi>R. G.</hi> and the Lady <hi>S.</hi> the ſaid Sir <hi>R. G.</hi> promiſed, before the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fiance, to aſſure unto her 1000 <hi>l. per an.</hi> for her Joynture (his eſtate being then 12000 <hi>l. per an.</hi>) and thereupon ſhe married him, without any aſſurance or covenant in that behalf: After, he con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyed by Deed lands of great value to ſome friends of the Ladies [then his Wife] to the uſe of the ſaid Lady for term of 100 years, if ſhe ſo long lived, to commence after his death, and it was indorſed on the back of the Deed, that the intent was, that when there ſhould be a Joynture of 1000 <hi>l. per an.</hi> ſetled on her, according to the firſt agreement, the Leaſe ſhould be void: and it was held, that this was no fraudulent Leaſe, not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding the Proviſo, to determine it at the Husbands will; for the Court took diverſity between the caſe above, and when a Leaſe is made with a Proviſo, That if the Leſſor pay 10 <hi>s. &amp;c.</hi> the
<pb n="188" facs="tcp:101268:95"/> Leaſe to be void, becauſe in the later caſe, the ſmallneſs of the ſum payable, makes it apparent to be only a power of revocation; and ſuch a Leaſe a purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſer ſhall avoid; And the Court held, that the Leaſe aforeſaid being made in purſuance of the firſt promiſe, although no mention of a Leaſe was therein made, yet it was grounded upon a good con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration, and not fraudulent: And although it was objected, that the Lady had concealed the Leaſe, during her Husbands life, and therefore it ſhould be fraudulent, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> yet, it was anſwered thereunto by the Chief Juſtice; That actions ought to have their reſort to the firſt original, and the Leaſe being good at the firſt, the concealment cannot make it ill, <hi>Croke,</hi> part 2. 455. <hi>p. 13. Dame Griffin,</hi> verſ. <hi>Stanhope.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="15">(15.) <hi>Scire Facias</hi> [upon a Judg<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment<note place="margin">Evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence.</note> in Debt, againſt <hi>T. H.</hi> who died] againſt the <hi>Terre</hi> Tenants, they pleaded a Feoffment made by <hi>T. H.</hi> long before the Judgment, <hi>abſq, hoc,</hi> that he was ſei<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>zed at the time of the Judgment, or af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter: and iſſue being thereupon taken, the Jury found the Feoffment, &amp; that it was made by covin to defraud the Plaintiff
<pb n="189" facs="tcp:101268:95"/> and other Creditors; and judged for the Plaintiff, for <hi>T. H.</hi> remained ſtill ſeized as to the Creditors, notwithſtanding the Feoffment: But if iſſue had been di<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>rectly taken, enfeoffed, or not enfeoffed, it had been found againſt the Plaintiff; for in ſuch caſe, he muſt avoid the Feoff<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, by covin, ſpecially pleaded: but here the Iſſue being ſeized or not ſeized by the Feoffment, the covin may be gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven in evidence, <hi>Hobert,</hi> fol. 72. <hi>Hum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berton</hi> verſ. <hi>Howgill.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="16">(16.) Debt brought by <hi>Hawes verſ.</hi>
               <note place="margin">Fraudu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent gifts of Goods.</note> 
               <hi>Leader</hi> as Adminiſtrator of <hi>Tho. Cook<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon:</hi> the Caſe was, that <hi>Tho. Cookson</hi> for 20 <hi>l.</hi> did grant unto the Plaintiff all his Goods mentioned in a Schedule, annex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed to the Deed, and gave poſſeſſion by a Pewter-diſh, with a covenant ſafely to keep them, and to deliver them unto the Plaintiff upon demand, and bound him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf in 40 <hi>l.</hi> to perform the Covenant; <hi>Tho. Cookson</hi> dies, and the Plaintiff de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands of the Defendant (being the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miniſtrator of <hi>Cookson</hi>) the goods, who refuſed to deliver them, and hereupon the Plaintiff brought his action; the De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendant pleaded the Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 5. and that <hi>Cookson</hi> was indebted to
<pb n="190" facs="tcp:101268:96"/> divers in ſums amounting to 100 <hi>l.</hi> [na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming in particular, the perſons and the ſums] and being ſo indebted, makes the ſaid gift, being then of thoſe and other goods poſſeſs'd, to the value of 80 <hi>l.</hi> and no more; and that the Deed was made by fraud between them, to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceive his Creditors, and the Plaintiff de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>murred: Firſt, becauſe the Defendant avers not that the Debts were unpaid: Secondly, becauſe he doth not ſhew that the debts were due by Specialty, for an Adminiſtrator is not liable to other debts: Thirdly, the Defendant ſuppo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth, that the delivery of the goods would be a <hi>devaſtavit</hi> in him which cannot be; for the goods in the Plaintiffs hands, are lyable to Creditors, as Executor, <hi>de ſon tort demeſne,</hi> if the Deed be fraudulent: Fourthly, It may be the Creditors will never ſue, and then the Defendant might detain the goods for ever, which is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>convenient: Fifthly, the Defendant is not a perſon enabled by 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> to plead that Plea; for the Statute makes the Deed void only againſt Creditors, but not againſt the party himſelf, his Execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors, or Adminiſtrators, judged for the Plaintiff, <hi>Croke,</hi> part 2. 270. <hi>p. 3. Hawes verſ. Leaſder.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="191" facs="tcp:101268:96"/>
            <p n="17">(17.) This fraud need not be plead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed:<note place="margin">Fraud need not be plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded, but given in evi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dence.</note> In debt brought againſt the heir up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on an obligation made by his father, the defendant pleaded nothing by deſcent; and it was found that before the ſuit be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gun, the defendant had made a Feoff<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment in Fee of all his Lands, to defraud the Plaintiff of his action, but this fraud was not pleaded: Reſolved by the Court, it need not be pleaded ſpecially, but only given in evidence: Firſt, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> provides generally, that the eſtate as to the Creditors ſhall be void; and Acts of Parliament made to ſuppreſs fraud, ſhall be favourably inter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preted. Secondly, fraud, and covin are ſo privily hatched, that the party grieved hath no means to find them out, and then to force the Plaintiff, who is a ſtranger to plead it, would be againſt reaſon, <hi>Cook. lib. 5. 60. Gooches Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="18">(18.) The Court ſhall not intend<note place="margin">Fraud not in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tendible by the Court.</note> fraud, where it is not found by the Jury: <hi>A.</hi> ſeized of Lands in Fee, holden of <hi>I. L.</hi> of his Mannor of <hi>H.</hi> by Fealty, Rent, and rendring the beſt beaſt, after the death of every Tenant in Fee-ſimple; <hi>A.</hi> by Deed in conſideration of love to his Son and heir apparent, and a marri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>age
<pb n="192" facs="tcp:101268:97"/> between his Son and <hi>B.</hi> and for the Sons advancement, infeoffs his ſaid Son of the ſaid Land: the Son afterward to the end <hi>B.</hi> ſhould not be endowed du<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring his fathers life, re-demiſeth the Land to his father for 40 years, if he lived ſo long; The marriage took effect, the Son did his ſuit<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and after the Feoffment, the father paid the Lords Rent: the father dies, the Lord taketh his beſt Beaſt for an Herriot; and in Treſpaſs brought, the Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry found all the ſpecial matter, alſo the Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz.</hi> But it was reſolved, That in regard no fraud was found by the Jury, the Court ſhould not intend the ſaid Feoffment to be fraudulently made: and the ſame being found to be made in conſideration of marriage, ſhall not by conſtruction of Law be taken to extend to any other intent, nor to be fraudulent, <hi>Cook, lib.</hi> 10. 56.</p>
            <p>(<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>19.) There are two manner of gifts<note place="margin">Conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on.</note> upon good conſideration: Firſt, upon conſideration of Nature and Blood. Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>condly, a valuable conſideration: and the Statute of 13 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 5. and the <hi>Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viſo</hi> therein extends only to a valuable conſideration: for a gift made to defeat others, muſt be made upon as hihg and
<pb n="193" facs="tcp:101268:97"/> good conſideration, as the things to be defeated are: alſo every gift made upon truſt, is out of the ſaid <hi>Proviſo,</hi> becauſe it is not <hi>bona fide:</hi> and a truſt is either expreſſed, or implied; expreſſed<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> when it is ſet down in, or upon the gift; implied, when the gift is made without any con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration, or upon conſideration of Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture and blood, <hi>Cook, lib. 3. 81. b. Twines Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="statute">
            <pb n="194" facs="tcp:101268:98"/>
            <head>27 Eliz. <hi>Chap.</hi> 4 Concerning Fraudulent Conveyances.</head>
            <p>1. BY the Statute of 27 <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 4.<note place="margin">Stat. of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> Deceit of purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſers.</note> It is ordained and enacted, That all and every Conveyance, Grant, charge, leaſe, eſtate, incumbrance, and limitation of uſe or uſes, of, in or out of any lands, tenements, or other heredita<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments whatſoever, had or made at any time heretofore, ſince the beginning of the Queens Reign, or hereafter to be made, for intent or purpoſe to defraud &amp; deceive ſuch perſon and perſons, Bodies Politick, or Corporate, as have purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, or ſhall hereafter purchaſe, in Fee-ſimple, Fee-tail, for life, lives, or years, the ſame Lands, Tenements, or Heredi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taments, or any part thereof, ſo formerly conveyed, leaſed, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> or to defraud and deceive ſuch as have, or ſhall purchaſe any Rent, Profit, or Commodity, in or out of the ſame, or any part thereof, ſhall be deemed and taken, only as againſt that
<pb n="195" facs="tcp:101268:98"/> perſon and perſons, bodies Politick and Corporate, his and their heirs, ſucceſſors, executors, adminiſtrators, and aſſigns, and againſt all and every other perſon and perſons lawfully having or claim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, by, from, or under them, or any of them, which have purchaſed, or hereafter ſhall ſo purchaſe for money or other good conſideration, the ſame Lands, Te<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nements, or hereditaments, or any part thereof, or any rent, profit, or commodi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty, in, or out of the ſame, to be utterly void, fruſtrate, and of none effect.</p>
            <p n="2">(2.) And be it further Enacted, That all and every the parties, to ſuch feigned, covenous, and fraudulent gifts, grants, leaſes, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> before expreſſed, or be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing privy to, or knowing of the ſame, or any of them, which after the <hi>20th.</hi> of <hi>April</hi> next coming, ſhall wittingly, or willingly put in ure, juſtifie, or defend the ſame, or any of them, as true, ſimple, and done, or made <hi>bona fide,</hi> or upon good conſideration, to the diſturbance, or hin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derance of the ſaid Purchaſers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall incur the penalty, and forfeiture of one<note place="margin">Penalty<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </note> years value, of the ſaid Lands, Tenements, and hereditaments, ſo purchaſed, or char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged; the one moiety to the Queen, the
<pb n="196" facs="tcp:101268:99"/> the party grieved, to be recovered in any of the Queens Courts of Record, by debt, bill, plaint, or information, where no eſſoyn, protection, or wager of Law, ſhall be admitted to the defendant, or de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fendants, and to ſuffer impriſonment for one half year without Bail or Mainpriſe: 27 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 4.</p>
            <p n="3">(3.) Provided, that this Act ſhall not extend to any grant, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> made upon good conſideration, and <hi>bona fide,</hi> nor to any mortgage made <hi>bona fide,</hi> without fraud, and upon good conſideration: 27 <hi>Eliz. chap.</hi> 4.</p>
            <p n="4">(4.) And it is further enacted, that<note place="margin">Convey<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ance with clauſe of Revoca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</note> if any perſon or perſons have ſince the Queens Reign that now is, or ſhall here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after make any conveyance, gift, grant, demiſe, charge or limitation of uſe or uſes, of, in, or out of any lands, tene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, or hereditaments, with any clauſe or condition of Revocation, determina<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, or alteration, at his or their will and pleaſure of ſuch conveyance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> of, in, or out of the ſaid lands, tenements, or he<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reditaments, or any part or parcel thereof; and after ſuch conveyance, gift, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſo had, or made, ſhall bargain, ſell, demiſe,
<pb n="197" facs="tcp:101268:99"/> grant, convey, or charge the ſame Lands, Tenements, or Hereditaments, or any part thereof, to any perſon or perſons, bodies politick or corporate, for money, or other good conſideration payed or given; [the ſaid firſt conveyance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> not being by him revoked, made void, or al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tered, according to the power reſerved;] That then the ſaid former conveyance, aſſurance, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> as touching the ſaid Lands, Tenements, and Hereditaments, ſo after bargained, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> againſt the ſaid Bargainees, Leſſees, and Grantees, and every of them, their heirs, ſucceſſors, executors, admini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtrators and aſſigns ſhall be void, <hi>&amp;c. 27 El. cap.</hi> 4.</p>
            <p n="5">(5.) <hi>J. C.</hi> had a Leaſe for 60 years<note place="margin">Leaſe forged.</note> (if he lived<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſo long) and he forged a Leaſe for ninety years abſolutely; and by Indenture reciting the forged Leaſe, he bargained and ſold the ſame, and all his intereſt in the Land to <hi>R. G. R. G.</hi> is no purchaſer for valuable conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, within the ſaid Statute of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> becauſe he contracted not for the true and lawful intereſt; and although by the words, his true intereſt paſſed: yet he gave no valuable conſideration for it: <hi>Cook upon Littl. fol. 3. b.</hi>
            </p>
            <pb n="198" facs="tcp:101268:100"/>
            <p n="6">(6.) One who intended to ſell his<note place="margin">The Act binds the King.</note> Lands, had by fraud conveyed the ſame by Deed inrolled to the Queen: In this caſe the purchaſer ſhall enjoy the Land againſt the Queen, by the Statute of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> for that Act being general and made in ſuppreſſion of fraud, ſhall bind the Queen: <hi>Cook, lib. 11. 74. a. Mag<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dalen Colledg Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="7">(7.) A man conveyed his Lands to<note place="margin">Future power of Revoca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion.</note> the uſe of himſelf for life, and after to the uſe of divers others of his blood, with a future power of Revocation, <hi>viz.</hi> after ſuch a Feaſt, or after the death of ſuch an one, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> and before the power of Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation commenceth, he, for valuable con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſideration doth bargain and ſell the ſame lands to another, and his heirs: this bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain and ſale is within the remedy of 27. <hi>Eliz. cap.</hi> 4. for although the Statute ſaith, [<hi>the firſt conveyance not by him re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>voked</hi>] which ſeems by the literal ſence to be intended of a preſent power of Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vocation, for no revocation can be made by force of a future power, before it comes in <hi>eſſe;</hi> yet it was held that the in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tent of the Act was, that ſuch voluntary Conveyance that was originally ſubject to a power of Revocation, be it in pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſent
<pb n="199" facs="tcp:101268:100"/> or in future, ſhall not ſtand againſt a purchaſer, who cometh in upon good and valuable conſideration, and <hi>bona fide, Cook, lib. 3. 82. Twines Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="8">(8.) Reſolved, That if a man hath<note place="margin">Power of Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation extin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guiſhed.</note> power of Revocation, and after to the intent to defraud a purchaſer, he levy a Fine, or make a Feoffment, or other conveyance to a ſtranger, whereby he extinguiſheth this power; and after he bargain and ſell the lands to another for valuable conſideration, the Bargainee ſhall enjoy the Land; for as to him, the Fine, Feoffment, or other conveyance, by which the condition was extinct, was void by the ſaid Act of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> And it was ſaid, that the ſaid Act made volun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tary Conveyances, with power of Revo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cation, in an equal degree as to purcha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſers, with conveyances made to defraud purchaſers: <hi>Cook, lib. 3. 82. b. Twines Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="9">(9.) If a man make a Leaſe for<note place="margin">Conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration.</note> years by covin and fraud, and after make another Leaſe <hi>bona fide</hi> without Fine paid, or rent reſerved; the ſecond Leaſe ſhall not a void the firſt: for firſt it was agreed, that by the Common Law, an
<pb n="200" facs="tcp:101268:101"/> Eſtate made by fraud ſhall be only void againſt him that had a former right, and not againſt him that had a puiſne right or intereſt. Secondly, no purchaſer ſhall avoid a precedent conveyance made by fraud or covin, but he that is a purchaſer for money, or other valuable conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion: and the words [<hi>good conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion</hi>] in the Act, ought to be underſtood of valuable conſideration only<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> and not a conſideration of nature or blood, <hi>&amp;c. Cook, lib. 3. 83. Twines Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="10">(10) A man of little capacity, and not able to govern the Lands deſcended to him, and being diſpoſed to riot and diſorder, by mediation of friends, open<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly conveyed his lands to them, upon truſt and confidence, that he ſhould take the profits for his maintenance; and that he ſhould not have power to waſte and conſume them: and after being ſeduced by perſons, he ſold his Lands to them for a ſmall ſum of money: And this bargain and ſale, although it was for money, was held to be out of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> which Act was made againſt fraud and deceit, and ſhall not aid any purchaſer that cometh not to the Land for good conſideration, lawfully and without fraudor deceit;
<pb n="201" facs="tcp:101268:101"/> but ſuch a conveyance made upon truſt, were void as to him that purchaſeth it for valuable conſideration, and <hi>bona fide, Cook, lib. 3. 83. b. Twines Caſe.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="11">(11.) If a man ſeized of Lands in<note place="margin">Notice of the fraud.</note> Fee make a fraudulent Conveyance, to the end to deceive and defraud a pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer, againſt the Statute of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> and continueth in poſſeſſion, and is repu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted as owner, and <hi>B.</hi> enter into commu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nication with <hi>A.</hi> for the purchaſe of it, and by accident <hi>B.</hi> hath notice of this fraudulent conveyance, and yet notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding he concludes with <hi>A.</hi> and ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>keth an aſſurance from him; yet <hi>B.</hi> ſhall avoid this fraudulent conveyance, by the ſaid Act of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> notwithſtanding his notice; for the Act by expreſs words makes the fraudulent conveyance void, as to a Purchaſer, for the notice of a Purchaſer, cannot make that good, which by Act of Parliament is void, as to it: <hi>Cook, lib.</hi> 5. 60.</p>
            <p n="12">(12.) One, after Marriage, volun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tarily<note place="margin">Volunta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veyance</note> aſſigns a Leaſe for years, as it were in joynture for his wife, and took the profits, and after ſold it to one who had no notice of this conveyance: this was held to be within 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> although at
<pb n="202" facs="tcp:101268:102"/> the firſt it was not made upon truſt, to be revoked, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> becauſe it was a voluntary conveyance at the firſt, and ſhall be in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended fraudulent at the beginning: But if at the time of the Marriage, or after, by reaſon of a portion given by his wives friends, in recompence thereof, and for a Proviſion for maintenance of his wife, he had made an aſſignment of ſuch a Leaſe to his wives friends, and had after taken the profits thereof, as in reaſon he ought during his life, and had then ſold that Term, yet it had not been within the ſaid Statute. <hi>Crook, part 2. 158. Colvil verſ. Parker.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="13">(13.) A man Covenants for natural love, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> to ſtand ſeized to the uſe of himſelf for life, the remainder to his Son in Tail, with a power of Revocation, and a <hi>Proviſo</hi> to make Leaſes for 21 years, and after makes a Leaſe for 21 years, for 30 <hi>lib.</hi> Fine paid. Reſolved, That not<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>withſtanding this voluntary and revoke<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>able conveyance, yet the Leaſe for years was abſolutely good, by 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> and as to the Leſſee, the conveyance ſhall be conſtrued, as if it had been revoked, and that the Leſſor was then Tenant in Fee; and it was alſo reſolved, That in caſe of
<pb n="203" facs="tcp:101268:102"/> a Leaſe for years, made as before, there had been a Rent only reſerved, it had been a good conſideration, and within the Statute; and the making of ſuch Leaſe was a revocation of the firſt Eſtate according to the Leaſe, <hi>Crook, part 2. 181. p.</hi> 19. Alſo it was reſolved, that the ſaid Leaſe for years; reſpect being had only to the Proviſo, and power thereby given, was void; for it being only a covenant, and the conſideration not extending to the Leaſe for years, no uſe is raiſed to him thereby, <hi>ibi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dem.</hi>
            </p>
            <p n="14">(14.) Grandfather, Father, and Son; the Grandfather, upon the Fathers mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage, makes the Wife of the Father a Joynture; and at the ſame time, cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nants to demiſe other Tenements to the Father for 1000 years, and after maketh ſuch demiſe accordingly, to commence after his death; in which was a Proviſo to make the ſame void, upon the Fathers dying without iſſue, or making a Leaſe not reſerving the ancient Rent; the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther after aſſigns the ſaid Leaſe to the uſe of his Son (an infant) to the intent, that it ſhould not drown by the deſcent of the reverſion, and with the coloura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble
<pb n="204" facs="tcp:101268:103"/> purpoſe and intent, that the infant ſhould pay debts, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The Grandfather dies, the Father enters into the Lands, and taketh the Profits, and makes Lea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, and doth other Acts as Owner; and neither the Aſſignees nor Infant took any Profits, or paid any Debts; and the Aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignment was made to divers perſons of good reputation, but the aſſignment it ſelf was delivered into the hands of a perſon of mean quality; The Father after bargains and ſells the ſaid Lands for a great ſum of money by Deed in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rolled: By all which marks, the ſaid Leaſe and Aſſignment were taken to be fraudulent, <hi>Cook, lib. 6. 72. a. Burrells</hi> caſe.</p>
            <p n="15">(15.) Reſolved, (in the ſaid Caſe) That whereas the words of the ſaid Act of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> are, That all and every Conveyance, Grant, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> for the intent to defraud or deceive ſuch perſons as have purchaſed, or ſhall purchaſe the ſame Lands, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> ſhall be deemed, on<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly againſt ſuch Purchaſer, void: yet if the Father make a Leaſe by fraud and covin of his Lands, to defraud others, to whom he ſhall demiſe or ſell it, [as all fraudulent demiſes ſhall be intended,]
<pb n="205" facs="tcp:101268:103"/> and before the Father ſells or demiſeth it, he dieth; and the Son, knowing or not knowing the ſaid Leaſe, ſell the Lands upon good conſideration; In this caſe the Vendee ſhall avoid the ſaid Leaſe by the ſaid Act of 27 <hi>Eliz.</hi> for the words of the Act are general, and it is not needful that he who ſold the Land, ſhould make the former Eſtate or incumbrance; But if the Eſtate be frau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dulent, whoſoever is the ſeller, the Pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chaſer ſhall avoid ſuch fraudulent Eſtate: Alſo, it was reſolved, That al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>though the Father had nothing of Inhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ritance in the Land, at the time of the aſſignment of the Leaſe, but the inheri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance was in the Grandfather, yet when the Grandfather dieth, and the Father ſells the Land, his Vendee ſhall avoid the ſaid Term: for if he had bargained, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>old the Term only, the bargain ſhould have avoided the fraudulent aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignment, and by conſequence, the Ven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dee of the whole Fee-ſimple ſhall avoid it, <hi>Co<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>k, lib. 6. 72. a. b. Burrells</hi> caſe.</p>
            <p n="16">(16.) In Treſpaſs: The Plaintiff and D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ſendant claim by ſeveral Leaſes from the ſame man: The Plaintiff in his Declara<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>io<gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#KEYERS" extent="1 span">
                  <desc>〈…〉</desc>
               </gap> the defendants Leaſe
<pb n="206" facs="tcp:101268:104"/> to be made by fraud, but ſheweth not any conſideration payed by himſelf: whereupon the Defendant Demurs: <hi>Yel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verton:</hi> at Common Law there was not any fraud remedied, to defeat an after purchaſe, but that only which was com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted to defeat a former intereſt, which was granted; and 27 <hi>El.</hi> doth not aid it, for here is no conſideration payed for the ſecond Leaſe, no more than for the firſt: <hi>Lukener contra.</hi> A thing obtained by a mans own act, makes a man a purchaſer within the ſaid Statute, and the fraud is confeſſed by the Demurrer; <hi>Anderſon:</hi> the confeſſion of the fraud is not mate<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rial, in regard the Plaintiff is not ſuch a perſon, as ought to have benefit thereby, and within the remedy and proviſion of the Act; and by that Act a fraudulent conveyance is not made void againſt all, but only againſt ſuch as come in upon valuable conſideration: <hi>Wamſey,</hi> accord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing; and he ſaid, that a fraudulent gift of goods, remains good againſt the do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nor, but not againſt his Creditor, by 13 <hi>Eliz. Crook, part 1. 445. p. 8. <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pton verſ. Baſſet.</hi>
            </p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:101268:104"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
